<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Nonsenses on Santa Barbara Bullshit — sbshit.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Alex Dunn</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2014 Alex Dunn; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-01-25 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blame Canada! (Because They’re Socialists, So They Might As Well Be Communists, Which Is Apparently What Tenured Professors Are)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/tenure</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/tenure</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an admirer of fine dissimulation, it was with great pride that I
read Brett Debbold&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2014/01/teacher-tenure-only-good-in-theory&#34; title=&#34;Teacher Tenure: Only Good in Theory&#34;&gt;recent piece on tenure&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/em&gt;.  With
such young prodigies (or should we say
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theawl.com/2014/01/better-than-ezra&#34; title=&#34;Better
then Ezra&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;wunderkinder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;), we need not worry about the advancing age of some of
our current &lt;a href=&#34;http://sbshit.com/wage.html&#34; title=&#34;What Is The
Point Of A Living Wage If We Are Not Truly Alive&#34;&gt;sleeper agents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Debbold&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2014/01/teacher-tenure-only-good-in-theory&#34; title=&#34;Teacher Tenure: Only Good in Theory&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, titled &amp;ldquo;Teacher Tenure: Only
Good in Theory&amp;rdquo;, is, of course, actually a cleverly-disguised attack
on the underlying logic of capitalism.  That&amp;rsquo;s something Harris
Sherline already did very well, but the angle of tenured employment is
new, so we will forgive Brett.  And his piece itself is admirably
straightforward, setting up the dialectic in the very first sentence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenure, much like communism, is a good idea in theory, but its
modern application does more harm than good for teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re using the standard John Birch Model, then communism is on the
opposite end of the economic freedom spectrum from capitalism.  By
comparing tenure to capitalism, we are to understand it as
antithetical to the principles of capitalism.  The existence of tenure
will necessarily be precarious in a capitalistic system, as Mr. Debbold
points out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of tenure is to protect proven teachers from dismissal when
new administrations or young teachers come into their schools
[or they express controversial opinions in their classrooms; or they criticize the existing administration; or they speak out against racism, sexism, or other sorts of discrimination; or they come out as gay, lesbian, transgender, etc.; or they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/1996/11/13/us/anita-hill-plans-to-leave-teaching-post-in-oklahoma.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;src=pm&#34;&gt;find themselves in a political firestorm&lt;/a&gt;].
The fear is that without tenure, older teachers will be unjustly
pushed out in order to save the school money or because of
conflicting teaching theory
[or because they express controversial opinions in their classrooms; or because they criticize the existing administration; or because they speak out against racism, sexism, or other sorts of discrimination; or because they come out as gay, lesbian, transgender, etc.; or because they find themselves in a political firestorm].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having established so clearly the great value of tenure, Mr. Debbold&amp;rsquo;s
rhetorical strategy is to lay forth the common arguments against
tenure and simply allow the reader to see how ludicrous they are in
the light of what has already been said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the teachers who would deserve to keep their jobs
would do so easily even without tenure. Just like in any other
profession, there is no reason for an administration to fire good
employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly, no reason at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenure does, however, give license to those who have earned it to
become complacent in their work. Of course not every tenured teacher
lets his or her work decline, but it is an easy course to
take. Knowing that you can’t be fired for anything less than a
serious offense is a dangerous thing. The fear of getting fired and
the desire to get promoted are the most common incentives for good
work, and with tenure, many teachers are left without either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an anecdotal aside, 100% of my fellow graduate students have
actually informed me that they&amp;rsquo;re dedicating the majority of their
twenties to become experts in a field they are truly passionate about
just so they can play Candy Crush a lot when they get tenure.  But
like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/hume/#Emp&#34; title=&#34;SEP: Hume: Empiricism&#34;&gt;Hume&amp;rsquo;s missing shade of blue&lt;/a&gt;, I don&amp;rsquo;t think this data point should be
given much weight.  In any case, here is the heart of Brett&amp;rsquo;s essay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse than that, tenure forces schools to fire superior teachers for
the sole reason that they haven’t been around as long as their
peers. When merit is no longer the basis for which firings are
decided, something is wrong with the system. When schools inevitably
undergo cutbacks and inferior teachers remain employed while young
teachers excited to go to work are let go, tenure is to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They key word here is &amp;ldquo;inevitable&amp;rdquo;.  In a capitalist society, the
expansion of higher education following World War Two was in fact an
anomaly, and the current funding cuts, privatization, and rise of the
adjunct labor class should be seen as the more natural phenomena.
Anyone feeling mystified as to why our government is not even
considering straightforward and relatively inexpensive reforms that
would make education
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/01/heres-exactly-how-much-the-government-would-have-to-spend-to-make-public-college-tuition-free/282803/&#34; title=&#34;Here&#39;s Exactly How Much the Government Would Have to Spend to Make
Public College Tuition-Free&#34;&gt;truly free for all&lt;/a&gt; does not fully appreciate the economic
and political pressures, created by capitalism, that rule out this
obvious solution.  Likewise, the sensible job protections offered by
tenure are anathema to capitalism, and so have been strategically
associated with lazy, overpaid, unqualified professors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if to drive home the absurdity of this last charge, Brett Debbold
ends with a comparison of tenured teachers with Supreme Court
Justices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching is a far cry from the Supreme Court, where job security is
necessary to ensure job performance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was, of course, a certain member of that judicial body whose sexual
harassment created the aforementioned political firestorm around
&lt;em&gt;tenured professor&lt;/em&gt; Anita Hill, who was saved from retaliatory
termination of her employment due to her tenure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A far cry, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strawman That Broke The Camel’s Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/obama</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/obama</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I love apps. I have downloaded so, so many of them.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/229576&#34; title=&#34;Forget Constant Communication, This App Offers Instant Communication&#34;&gt;Kyle Richey, Millennial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials love apps.  We make Tweets, we Tumbl, and Snap Chat with
each other all day long.  We also love President Obama.  Like,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wonkette.com/498120/why-spend-17-95-on-erotic-obama-fan-fic-when-you-can-get-your-cow-for-free&#34; title=&#34;Why Spend $17.95 On &#39;Erotic&#39; Obama Fan-Fic, When You Can Get Your Cow
At Wonket For Free?&#34;&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt;.  So we were very excited when we learned that
Obama was making an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.healthcare.gov/&#34;&gt;app&lt;/a&gt;.  An app made
by Obama would be the combination of the two things we love &amp;mdash; Obama
and apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Obama did not make a good app.  His app is not the next Snap Chat.
It is not snappy.  It is bad.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s bad app has left us Millennials
feeling betrayed and very sad.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-11-19/breaking-the-second-term-curse/&#34; title=&#34;Breaking the Second Term Curse&#34;&gt;And angry&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to avoid this topic, I did.  But I can only sit around for
so long while Jon Stewart, NPR and the New York Times &amp;mdash; basically
all of my closest friends &amp;mdash; tear one of my biggest heroes apart.
This has been heartbreaking for me.  And for all of the times that I
have blindly supported Obama, though I will never admit to actually
ever being false, today I cannot ignore our president&amp;rsquo;s decisions
simply because I am really inspired by Michelle Obama&amp;rsquo;s gnarly
biceps and triceps.  Today is the day I never expected to see.
Today I will critique the actions of President Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These words are coming from a Millennial, so they should concern
President Obama.  Especially because even though this Millennial is
writing under the name &amp;ldquo;Mckinley Krongaus&amp;rdquo; she is probably
actually &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/o6G3nwhPuR4&#34;&gt;Lena Dunham&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am debatably President Obama&amp;rsquo;s biggest fan.  I am constantly
tweeting inappropriate fantasies of wishing to bear his children and
quite frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why the National Security Agency hasn&amp;rsquo;t
checked up on me yet.  The newspaper cover from that heavenly day in
November 2008 remains tacked on my closet door at home and I will
forever remember the incredible feeling I had as I gave up my voting
virginity for him aside a stripper pole at the lovely AEPi house.
But holy shit, is he dicking around right now, or what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason why Millennials are not happy about Obama&amp;rsquo;s app is that a
cool feature was removed that we really wanted.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wonkette.com/532898/obamas-you-can-keep-your-plan-failed-to-anticipate-how-much-americans-love-cheap-crappy-plans-that-cover-nothing&#34; title=&#34;Obama’s &#39;You Can Keep Your Plan&#39; Failed To Anticipate How Much
Americans Love Cheap Crappy Plans That Cover Nothing&#34;&gt;We wanted to be able to be fucked over by insurance companies&lt;/a&gt;, and Obama&amp;rsquo;s
app doesn&amp;rsquo;t let us do that (no wait it was just
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/online/daily/2013/11/obamacare-keep-your-insurance-plan&#34;&gt;updated&lt;/a&gt;,
we&amp;rsquo;re all good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not the only reason we Millennials are mad.  We&amp;rsquo;re also mad
because the Obama app is not a good app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my bike ride to class yesterday morning I was listening to NPR&amp;rsquo;s
&amp;ldquo;Morning Edition&amp;rdquo; (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m that person) and heard a ridiculous
story about these three guys in the Silicon Valley who were fed up
with the terrible setup of the healthcare website and sat down and
literally made their own.  It&amp;rsquo;s called healthsherpa.com and so far
it&amp;rsquo;s helped to provide thousands of users with insurance quotes that
they couldn&amp;rsquo;t get access to on the actual Affordable Care Act
website.  One of the programmers said that about 85 percent of their
website&amp;rsquo;s users have been able to complete the process of finding a
plan that works for them compared to the humorously praised number
of 100,000 Americans that have chosen plans on the real website.
Reality check: There are 40 million uninsured Americans and we&amp;rsquo;re
pretending to be stoked on 100,000 being able to even make their way
through the website all the way? The moral of the story was that
three dudes under the age of 30 created a website that is more
functional than the website brain-child of the entire federal
government. That&amp;rsquo;s a little silly, don&amp;rsquo;t you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lena Dunham is a Millennial, so she
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/funny-stuff/d7e5d14065f1&#34; title=&#34;Dear
Miss Disruption&#34;&gt;learned to code&lt;/a&gt; and knows some things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Move fast and break things&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always be shipping&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disrupt the industry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Innovation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pivot&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Entrepreneur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Horse_ebooks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s app did not break things.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s app is broken.  It&amp;rsquo;s not
the same thing, and Obama&amp;rsquo;s app is the bad one.  Also it did not move
fast.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s app is slow.  The Health Sherpa is a good app because
it was made by Millennial.  It also has vision.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://e-pluribusunum.com/2013/11/11/why-healthsherpa-com-is-not-a-replacement-for-healthcare-gov/&#34;&gt;It does one thing&lt;/a&gt;
and does it well.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s app tries to do too many things, like sell
people health insurance.  That&amp;rsquo;s bad.  The Health Sherpa worked for 85
percent of its users.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s app only worked for 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100,000 is less than 85 percent.  That&amp;rsquo;s bad for Obama and his app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s app
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/elements/2013/10/why-the-healthcaregov-train-wreck-happened-in-slow-motion.html&#34; title=&#34;Healthcare.gov: It Could Be Worse&#34;&gt;could not have been worse&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s as bad as the hurricane that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esquire.com/blogs/politics/Things_That_Are_Not_Like_Each_Other&#34; title=&#34;Nobody Drowned From Obamacare&#34;&gt;killed a lot of people&lt;/a&gt;.  Obama&amp;rsquo;s app might be killing people
too, maybe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;obamacare is a fuckin trainwreck. kids with cancer don&amp;#39;t even want insurance now. &amp;quot;the website is bad,&amp;quot; they said, dying. &amp;quot;its too slow&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; beefy tee (@BronzeHammer) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BronzeHammer/statuses/391548402997407744&#34;&gt;October 19, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONSTANT VIGILANCE!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/muni</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/muni</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/em&gt;, the flagship publication of
&lt;a href=&#34;drama.html&#34; title=&#34;An Unlikely Friendship&#34;&gt;our media empire&lt;/a&gt;, has a fine
record of &lt;a href=&#34;who.html&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s No Woman Good
Enough To Play Dr. Who But There Are Strong Female Characters So Shut
It&#34;&gt;standing athwart history&lt;/a&gt;.  This week that tradition was honored by Madison Donahue-Wolfe,
who steals the Complain-About-Technology crown from
&lt;a href=&#34;sexy.html &amp;quot;Stop Making Sense (feat. Ben Moss&#34;&gt;Ben Moss&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;) with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/10/smartphones-how-being-constantly-connected-can-have-deathly-consequences&#34; title=&#34;Smartphones: How Being Constantly Connected Can Have Deathly
Consequences&#34;&gt;this deep insight&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As technology surges forward, and companies develop more involved
and even wearable products, such as Google Glass, slated for release
sometime in 2014, you must ask yourself whether being so connected
to the web, to your friends, and to your device makes you in turn
more disconnected from the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must, you must, &lt;strong&gt;You Must,&lt;/strong&gt; because our sudden immersion in
&amp;ldquo;tech&amp;rdquo;, something that has
&lt;a href=&#34;http://punch.photoshelter.com/image/I00006GHuH4c0Ojo&#34;&gt;only just now occurred&lt;/a&gt;,
leaves us alienated and miserable, as a recent poll discovered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report [by Kleiner Perkins Caulfield &amp;amp; Byers] went on to state
that when asked how social and communication activities on
smartphones made them feel, the two most common feelings users
responded with were &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;excited.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now so &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;excited&amp;rdquo; that we have ceased to sit and
stare at fellow passengers while riding trains, keeping an eye out for
guns and wondering when somebody will get around to inventing the
printing press so we can fucking read a book or something because this
commute feels like forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s No Woman Good Enough To Play Dr. Who But There Are Strong Female Characters So Shut It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/who</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/who</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blogosphere let out a collective &lt;em&gt;jolly good&lt;/em&gt; earlier this month
upon learning that a white gentleman had been selected to represent
Doctor Who in &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; eponymous television show.  God continues to save
the Queen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True devotees of the television event had understandably been rather
worked up in advance of the announcement, for there had been a number
of outrageous rumors and suggestions regarding the nature of the
future Doctor.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/08/peter-capaldi-is-great-but-its-time-for-a-change/comment-page-1#comment-970526&#34;&gt;Insufficiently British&lt;/a&gt;
commentators had the gall to imagine the venerable man as something
quite unsuitable&amp;mdash;namely, a man of color or, worse, a woman!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://giphy.com/embed/YTRMdFNmWVYhq&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, cooler (and paler) heads prevailed, and one &amp;ldquo;Peter
Capaldi&amp;rdquo; was selected to carry on the white man&amp;rsquo;s burden of pretending
to be an alien on television.  But even with the question of
&amp;ldquo;diversity&amp;rdquo; settled forever, there are still some who insist on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/08/peter-capaldi-is-great-but-its-time-for-a-change&#34; title=&#34;Beth Askins: Peter Capaldi Is Great, But It&#39;s Time For A Change&#34;&gt;picking up pitchforks&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying Peter Capaldi isn&amp;rsquo;t talented.  I&amp;rsquo;m not saying we
should all riot with pitchforks and torches against the casting
director.  And I&amp;rsquo;m certainly not saying I haven&amp;rsquo;t loved the previous
doctors.  All I&amp;rsquo;m saying is, it&amp;rsquo;s about time for a little change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/08/should-the-doctor-be-doctored&#34; title=&#34;Should the Doctor be Doctored?&#34;&gt;Coleman Gray comes out swinging&lt;/a&gt; in today&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/em&gt; against
this outrageous attempt to undermine one of the last opportunities for
white male employment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent Doctors of Eccleston, Tennant, and Smith have all been
excellent actors, and I would like to think that all future
regenerations will feature similarly talented actors chosen based on
performance alone.  Even though the casting of a female or racially
diverse Doctor might be appreciated by some, I would be just as
excited and apprehensive as I am over the casting of any other new
replacement actor.  But, if they were to cast an individual because
of the grumblings of an upset minority and not because of acting
talent, it would be a mistake.  After all, as a creature nearly a
millennium old and bouncing about the utter limits of both time and
space, the Doctor should be above current political and social
trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Gray admits that &amp;ldquo;there are many strong female and racially
diverse characters&amp;rdquo; in the series, but points out that while female
and racially diverse actors do a good enough job in supporting roles,
they just aren&amp;rsquo;t as good as white men.  The choice of a woman and/or
person of color to play Doctor Who would be a politicized choice,
biased by current social trends, in a way that the selection of a
white man is not.  Decades from now, we will look back and laugh at
the idea that a creature nearly a millennium old and bouncing about
the utter limits of both time and space could ever be accurately
portrayed by anyone but a white man from a small island in the
Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because trends come and go, but white men are forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boys Will Be Boys And Girls Must Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/lulu</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/lulu</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last time our worthless &lt;a href=&#34;drama.html&#34; title=&#34;An Unlikely
Friendship&#34;&gt;subsidiary&lt;/a&gt; bothered to publish something this summer, we were
alarmed to find that it was an unapologetically
&lt;a href=&#34;hurdle.html&#34; title=&#34;The War On Men Continues&#34;&gt;misandrist screed&lt;/a&gt; against
the right of men to do whatever they want without jeopardizing the sex
that is also a thing that they have a right to.  We at &lt;em&gt;The Daily
Nonsense&lt;/em&gt; apologize for allowing &amp;ldquo;Haley K.&amp;rdquo; a soapbox for her
outrageous opinions, and are happy to announce that we have replaced
her with &amp;ldquo;Hayley E.&amp;rdquo;, who this week has rescued the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; tradition
of blaming everything on women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-08-07/some-things-are-better-left-in-the-bedroom/&#34; title=&#34;Some Things are Better Left in the Bedroom&#34;&gt;Hayley is concerned in her column&lt;/a&gt; about Lulu, a relatively
new app that allows women to anonymously review men in a way that&amp;rsquo;s
been described as
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buzzfeed.com/katieheaney/the-girls-only-yelp-for-boys&#34; title=&#34;Katie Heaney: The Girls-Only Yelp For Boys&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yelp for boys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  Hayley sees the app
as part of the ongoing coarsening of our values, driven&amp;mdash;of
course&amp;mdash;by fragile womanly natures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I fully understand why an app like this was created: Some girl
probably got cheated on and said something along the lines of, &amp;ldquo;My
fragile womanly heart has burst asunder!  If only other women knew
the scheming cruel ways of Bobby Whatshisface!&amp;rdquo;  Were these the good
old days, she would&amp;rsquo;ve drenched his possessions in gasoline, lined
them up in the yard to spell &amp;ldquo;ballface&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;douchenozzle,&amp;rdquo; and then
lit them up like the Fourth of July.  But nowadays, such a simple
act of rebellion does not seem to go far enough in sending a message
to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first this may seem like an unintuitive conclusion, for one
imagines that most men would prefer to retain their possessions than
have the #FartMachine hashtag applied to them at OnLulu Dot Com.  But
as Hayley argues, things can be replaced, but a ruined reputation is
forever:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in an age where everything we do is permanently stored on
the internet.  That dorky MySpace profile picture where you had
braces and wore your pants too high?  It&amp;rsquo;s up there.  That video
where you tried to do a sexy dance and instead ended up totally
eating it?  It&amp;rsquo;s somewhere in the bowels of the web &amp;hellip; or, if
you&amp;rsquo;re really unlucky, on the front page of YouTube.  And your
romantic endeavors, gross habits and/or traits you&amp;rsquo;d hoped would
never leave the bedroom?  Yep. If you&amp;rsquo;re a man, these, too, are
readily available to the public eye thanks to Lulu.  Guys, be afraid
&amp;hellip; be very afraid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you think that this is overly dramatic, that surely guys
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t worry about anonymous review of dubious authenticity posted
on a single website&amp;mdash;Hayley E. would like to remind you that women
are uniformly shallow and mindless, and will often ignore their own
judgment because of something a stranger said on the internet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my little brother falls for a girl in the future and she decides
to look him up on Lulu before their date, she&amp;rsquo;s going to spend the
whole time thinking about his hashtags, judgments fully formed
before so much as talking to him.  She&amp;rsquo;ll look specifically for
those attributes and faults, and when he does something that matches
his description, she&amp;rsquo;ll feel like everything on the page has been
validated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The danger is clear: this perverse and unaccountable system has the
power to render legions of men
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/puahate_txt/status/354601082309185536&#34; title=&#34;Tweet from @PUAHate_txt on 9 July 2013&#34;&gt;incel&lt;/a&gt;, and angry.  But there may
be a risk to women as well, apart from the possibility of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Men_Going_Their_Own_Way&#34; title=&#34;Entry for \&amp;quot;Men Going Their Own Way\&amp;quot; on RationalWiki&#34;&gt;men going their own way&lt;/a&gt;.  Men may
&lt;em&gt;strike back&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If action isn&amp;rsquo;t taken against Lulu, it&amp;rsquo;s only a matter of time
before there is a male equivalent.  Right now it exists by word of
mouth in places like locker rooms, bars and dorms, where towels are
rat-tailed and there&amp;rsquo;s talk of &amp;ldquo;tapping that.&amp;rdquo;  But soon they could
be detailing your nastiest girl habits and that weird thing you did
in bed (even if it was just that once) for the whole guy-world to
see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true: if we&amp;rsquo;re not careful, men might get ideas and start shaming
women on the internet.  Until now they have been kept in check,
following the virtuous example set by women.  But now, Hayley worries,
women may not be women anymore: they have abdicated their
responsibility of reining in male libidos that are too great for men
to control by themselves.  Now that men see themselves betrayed by
women, who knows what they might do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a version of Lulu that allows men to rate women they know.
But men&amp;rsquo;s righteous anger may carry them further.  Although not
wanting to generalize, Hayley generalizes about men&amp;rsquo;s likely behavior,
saying: &amp;ldquo;Not to generalize, but I imagine men would be inclined to be
a tad more explicit with their posts on your page.&amp;rdquo;  She may be right,
however.  It&amp;rsquo;s within the realm of &lt;em&gt;possibility&lt;/em&gt; that they might not
only leave &amp;ldquo;reviews&amp;rdquo; of women, but upload
&lt;a href=&#34;http://betabeat.com/2012/10/creepshots-reemerges-under-the-guise-of-a-fashion-police-subreddit/&#34; title=&#34;Jessica Roy: Creepshots Reemerges Under the Guise of a \&#39;Fashion
Police\&#39; Subreddit&#34;&gt;candid photographs&lt;/a&gt; of them, publish their
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gawker.com/5961208/revenge+porn-troll-hunter-moore-wants-to-publish-your-nudes-alongside-directions-to-your-house&#34; title=&#34;Camille Dodero: Revenge-Porn Troll Hunter Moore Wants To Publish Your
Nudes With Directions to Your House&#34;&gt;personal information&lt;/a&gt;, and even encourage
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_of_Amanda_Todd&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia: Suicide of Amanda Todd&#34;&gt;ruthless bullying&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that all this could happen.  So women, &lt;em&gt;shape up&lt;/em&gt;.
Because &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; it does happen, it will be your fault for using a novelty
app in order to say that a guy is #Boring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The War On Men Continues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/hurdle</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/hurdle</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During Emile Nelson&amp;rsquo;s tenure at the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;, great gains have been
made for Men&amp;rsquo;s Rights.  He established himself as a leader of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.involuntarycelibacy.com/&#34; title=&#34;The Incel
Project&#34;&gt;incel movement&lt;/a&gt; by eloquently explaining how sex is, for the male, often
&lt;a href=&#34;batman.html&#34; title=&#34;Batman is Best at Everything,
Including Fighting the Matriarchy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;an act of self-defense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  The truth of this is clearly
shown by the following lament from a man who has found himself
involuntarily celibate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being incel really fucks you up. Not only do you not get to have sex, but you also develop bizarre fetishes and usually become racist.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Puahate.txt (@puahate_txt) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/puahate_txt/statuses/336300385478275072&#34;&gt;May 20, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Mister Nelson also did a great service to mankind by developing a
cogent argument to the effect that
&lt;a href=&#34;hump.html&#34; title=&#34;How To Have Sex While Hating Yourself And Others&#34;&gt;women who are not virgins have profound mental handicaps&lt;/a&gt;.  By setting forth
these truths, he dealt a serious blow to the misandrist goal of
subjugating men under the promiscuous heel of a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Nelson appears to have taken a well-deserved break over the
summer, though, and in his absence trouble is brewing.  Known
misandrist &amp;ldquo;Haley K.&amp;rdquo; has used her bully pulpit at the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-06-26/the-hurdles-to-jump-before-you-hump/&#34; title=&#34;The Hurdles to Jump Before You Hump&#34;&gt;shame
men into once more obeying female whims&lt;/a&gt;.  But we stand in solidarity
with Emile Nelson and say, &amp;ldquo;Never Again!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haley betrays her agenda early on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the basic standards for guys are much less demanding, many
still struggle with taking the deceptively simple steps necessary to
get laid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Deceptively simple&amp;rdquo;?  Has Haley K. never heard the heart-wrenching
testimony of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://governmentsgetgirlfriends.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/my-parents-criminals-who-deserve-to-be-put-in-jail-or-killed/&#34; title=&#34;My parents --- criminals who deserve to be put in jail or killed&#34;&gt;those men who have been reduced to asking the government to find them a partner&lt;/a&gt;?
The suffering of these poor souls will not be alleviated by buying
into matriarchal beauty standards.  &amp;ldquo;Proper pants&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;great hair&amp;rdquo;
are merely further tools of oppression.  And don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on
chivalry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so it&amp;rsquo;s old-fashioned, but everyone loves a knight in shining
armor.  Hold the door open, offer up your jacket on those cold
nights, give a compliment here and there and remember that the
occasional bouquet of flowers never hurt anybody.  Go the extra mile
so that they will too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men are being asked to follow arcane rules steeped in misandry in
exchange for the sex that they are owed!  Haley is treating women as
if they were slot machines that release sex when the right combination
of compliments and flowers are supplied.  But as any
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/mensrights&#34; title=&#34;/r/mensrights&#34;&gt;MRA&lt;/a&gt; will tell
you, that is not the right way of looking at things.  Rather, women
should be seen as the candy in those little bowls at banks that you
can take even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t depositing any money.  You deserve it,
just for showing up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us pray that Emile Nelson returns to us and preaches these truths
again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Hardly Knew You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/goodbye</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/goodbye</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a sad day.  Mr. Jeffrey Robin, whose intriguing piece of analytic
philosophy was the subject of
&lt;a href=&#34;robin.html&#34; title=&#34;Critical discussion of a metaphysical thesis recently proposed by
Mr. Robin&#34;&gt;the very first essay published by the &lt;em&gt;Nonsense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is stepping down from his position as Reactionary Bigot
at the &lt;em&gt;Daily Nexus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He begins with some
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-28/right-side-columnist-bids-ucsb-farewell/&#34; title=&#34;Right-Side Columnist Bids UCSB Farewell&#34;&gt;misty-eyed remembrances&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be perfectly honest&amp;mdash;UCSB wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first choice, by far.  I
came out of high school the preppy, sarcastic valedictorian of a
sleepy suburb no one&amp;rsquo;s heard of.  Despite receiving the Regents
Scholarship here, I was sure that I was off to Pomona College in
Claremont.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being valedictorian of an entire suburb is a remarkable
accomplishment, and while I share Mr. Robin&amp;rsquo;s astonishment that he was
not accepted at a more prestigious institution, I am incredibly
grateful that we at UCSB have been blessed with his presence.  It
seems that he, too, has gained from his association with public-school
leeches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting waitlisted at every private school I wanted to go to gave me
the greatest lesson in humility I think I have ever experienced. But
as I sit here writing an article I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for
months, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could be more glad for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time at UCSB has profoundly changed me in ways I could never have
anticipated. It flipped me upside down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such is the power of education.  When you leave your sleepy suburb and
enter a state university, not only are you exposed to new ideas in
your classes, but you come into contact with &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; that you haven&amp;rsquo;t
met before, people whose backgrounds and worldviews differ sharply
from your own.  Being able to learn from the experiences of others,
especially from those less privileged than yourself, is a huge
opportunity to become a better and more tolerant person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could not even imagine myself listening to country music.  Now,
country line and swing dancing is the single most time-consuming
hobby I have.  Once the prudish, smart-guy type who confused
everyone with his diction, I&amp;rsquo;ve caught myself using the word &amp;ldquo;brah&amp;rdquo;
perhaps a little more than I&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps my personal beliefs have undergone the greatest and most
counterintuitive changes.  I came here convinced of Ayn Randian
philosophy and pure libertarian ideology, totally having bought in
to the populism of Ron Paul (Tea Party before it was cool).  Now,
perhaps to your chagrin, I am the strictest of elitist
constitutional conservatives, an advocate of the Empire of Liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly a wrenching change!  I can hardly imagine a situation better
described as being &amp;ldquo;flipped upside down&amp;rdquo;, except perhaps the
transformation involved in moving from the Socialist Equality Party to
the International Socialist Organization (a process that invariably
destroys friendships).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, in a time when many in our country are
increasingly antagonistic to the idea of God, I moved from a tepid
agnosticist and occasional deist to a strong believer in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A daring admission to make in these hateful, secular times.  But I
doubt he will come under too much fire, as long as he doesn&amp;rsquo;t use his
new-found faith to justify
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2012-02-15/contest-government-almighty-judge-soul/&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;A Contest Over Whether Your Government or the Almighty is the Judge
of Your Soul\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;vicious attacks on the rights of others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I close, I exhort you all to not intertwine or falsely associate
our faith with politics, as easy as it might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jeffrey Robin ends his tenure at the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; fittingly, with a
quote that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to really understand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have sworn upon the altar of God eternal hostility against every
form of tyranny over the mind of man&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tyranny that Jefferson speaks of here is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://etext.virginia.edu/etcbin/toccer-new2?id=JefLett.sgm&amp;amp;images=images/modeng&amp;amp;data=/texts/english/modeng/parsed&amp;amp;tag=public&amp;amp;part=133&amp;amp;division=div1&#34; title=&#34;Letter to To Dr. Benjamin Rush, Sep. 23, 1800&#34;&gt;that of organized Christianity&lt;/a&gt;, were it allowed to
be established as a state religion.  But if Jeffrey realized
this&amp;mdash;that the hero he quotes is arguing &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; the sort of thing
that would allow Christian institutions to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2012-02-15/contest-government-almighty-judge-soul/&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;A Contest Over Whether Your Government or the Almighty is the Judge
of Your Soul\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;deny women basic reproductive rights&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;then he would not be our beloved Mr. Robin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will miss him &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Strong Didn’t Give a Shit Before It Was Cool To Not Give a Shit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/personal</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/personal</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Strong is just about the luckiest person in the world.  Not only
is he white, male and (probably) straight and cis, he also has a
column in the finest student newspaper at UCSB that isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;The Bottom
Line&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Daily Nonsense&lt;/em&gt;.  And if that weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-23/when-becoming-the-issue-becomes-the-issue/&#34; title=&#34;When Becoming the Issue Becomes the Issue&#34;&gt;ideas for
his columns simply fall into his lap wherever he goes!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was digging into a new novel on the patio outside Nicoletti&amp;rsquo;s a
few weeks back when a single word in a nearby conversation caught my
attention: divestment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pair&amp;mdash;a guy and girl, both college-aged and bespectacled,
sipping coffee and picking at muffins&amp;mdash;was sitting directly behind
me.  Not one to eavesdrop, I tried to find my place on the page in
front of me, but before I could, I heard the word again. Divestment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muffins, coffee, and spectacles?  Hipsters, surely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe they took it off the table again,&amp;rdquo; the girl was
saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know,&amp;rdquo; the guy said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m personally offended. It just goes to
show how the ignorance in the &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words kept coming out of his mouth after that, but I found myself
suddenly engrossed and mulling over that two-word phrase. Personally
offended? Offended &amp;hellip; personally? What the fuck does that even mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest you thought that Mark Strong&amp;rsquo;s success in life is only the result
of the incredible privilege he was born with, here he demonstrates
that hard work has also played a part.  Ben Moss needs at least
&lt;a href=&#34;sexy.html&#34; title=&#34;Stop Making Sense \(feat. Ben
Moss\)&#34;&gt;450 words of clickbait&lt;/a&gt; to inspire his articles, but Mark Strong can get by with just
two
&lt;a href=&#34;http://infotrope.net/2009/08/05/action-and-reaction-on-avoiding-offense/&#34; title=&#34;Action and reaction: on avoiding \&amp;quot;offense\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;poorly-chosen&lt;/a&gt; words from a hipster.
&amp;ldquo;Personally offended?  Offended &amp;hellip; personally?&amp;rdquo;  He plays around with
them, rolling them over his tongue, and through some alchemical
process, a column emerges.  Compare his thought process to Tom
Friedman&amp;rsquo;s, and it becomes clear that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://buffalobeast.com/73/feature4.htm&#34; title=&#34;The Word is Hack: The Impossible Physics of Thomas Friedman\&#39;s
Brain&#34;&gt;they are related by something more than blood&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I left the Infosys campus that evening along the road back to
Bangalore, I kept chewing on that phrase: &amp;ldquo;The playing field is
being leveled.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Nandan is saying, I thought, is that the playing field is being
flattened &amp;hellip; Flattened? Flattened? My God, he&amp;rsquo;s telling me the
world is flat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(What the &lt;em&gt;fuck&lt;/em&gt; does that even mean?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After wondering for some time what it could possibly mean to be
personally offended (he having been lucky enough to avoid that
feeling), Mark Strong asks the question that has largely defined his
life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When did we start taking things so goddamn personally?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Strong yearns for the days when lucky men like him could
&lt;em&gt;rationally&lt;/em&gt; debate the issues of the day without having to suffer the
emotional outbursts of those personally affected.  These hysterical
children should be ignored, for &amp;ldquo;in personalizing the issue, [they]
eradicate [their] ability to think of it objectively.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily for Mark Strong, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t really care very much about
Palestine, abortion, and other vitally important issues (in this way,
he&amp;rsquo;s something of a hipster himself).  They&amp;rsquo;re interesting things to
play Devil&amp;rsquo;s advocate with, but ultimately (luckily!) they don&amp;rsquo;t
affect Mark Strong&amp;rsquo;s life, so why would anyone get worked up about
them?  Just &lt;em&gt;let it go&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished chapter seven and stowed Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Misery&lt;/em&gt; in the
front pocket of my backpack, leaving the pair to bicker in peace on
the patio in the bright May sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Comes Early at the *Nexus*</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/dead</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/dead</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Edwin Feliciano, a self-proclaimed &amp;ldquo;psychiatrist&amp;rdquo; at UCSB, today
appears to be attempting
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-22/anatomy-of-an-overdose/&#34; title=&#34;Anatomy of an Overdose&#34;&gt;a séance in the pages of the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and reports to us a story told by the dead.
Let us refer to the ghostly narrator as &amp;ldquo;Edwin&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of one commenter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-22/anatomy-of-an-overdose/comment-page-1/#comment-172755&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool story, bro.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how did Edwin die?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s one pill, man?&amp;rdquo; said my friend.  &amp;ldquo;People take six of those a
day for pain.&amp;rdquo;  I looked at it.  It was white, oval-shaped and
promised a good time.  Two hours later I was in bed, unable to
breathe.  My friends thought I was just passed out&amp;mdash;something that
happens a lot at college parties. Hell, I had seen it so many times
too!  Why would something go wrong then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise that Edwin isn&amp;rsquo;t the brightest bulb,
but it&amp;rsquo;s rather alarming that Dr Feliciano doesn&amp;rsquo;t pause in his
spirit-channeling to point out that there are rather a lot of reasons
why &lt;em&gt;something would go wrong&lt;/em&gt; when a person passes out at a party.
I can only assume that the good doctor knows something we don&amp;rsquo;t (and I
guess that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected, given that &lt;em&gt;he&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; the one who can commune
with the dead).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the doctors discussed my &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo; after I died, one doc said,
&amp;ldquo;This is outrageous.  Too many kids die from this. How stupid can a
person be?&amp;rdquo;  I was angry, but I hung around and listened to their
&amp;ldquo;expert analysis.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Expert&amp;rdquo; is rightly enclosed in quotation marks, because these doctors
probably don&amp;rsquo;t even believe in ghosts.  But more interesting are the
quotes around &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo;.  What is Dead Edwin trying to tell us?  Was
there no real case?  Let us proceed with caution, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dead man&amp;rsquo;s story continues with some bizarrely pedagogic
ruminations on his so-called case, and the claim that &amp;ldquo;what I learned
may help you stay alive.&amp;rdquo;  That&amp;rsquo;s a rather strange thing to tell a
doctor, but Edwin Feliciano apparently doesn&amp;rsquo;t realize that a
passed-out person might be in trouble, so I suppose he could use the
advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reach the conclusion, though, a careful reader gets the
impression that this is not the monologue of a normal (if deceased)
19-year-old:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the explanation got too technical for me.  By then, I
didn&amp;rsquo;t care to understand the &amp;ldquo;physiological&amp;rdquo; causes of my death.
It boiled down to this: there is a difference between what you feel
psychologically&amp;mdash;relaxed, buzzed, happy&amp;mdash;and what your body is
experiencing internally.  While it may be easy to gauge your mood,
alcohol and drugs are accumulating in your system at a rate faster
than your body can metabolize them.  The fact is that the effects
are delayed, so when you have one more shot, or an Adderall, or a
Norco, you&amp;rsquo;re creating a unique, often deadly cocktail in your
body. That&amp;rsquo;s what happened to me.  I got the message too late, which
is, very simply, that mixing drugs will kill you, period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have stayed home watching the Sixers play the Knicks and
having a few beers with my friends. I didn&amp;rsquo;t, as you now know, but
you have a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds less like the lament of a soul who is mourning the loss of
its body than a school psychiatrist who is insulting the intelligence
of his patients by making obviously false claims that lead students to
dismiss his advice&amp;mdash;and therefore be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; likely to make risky
decisions&amp;mdash;instead of explaining accurately how common drugs interact
and urging young people to educate themselves about the effects of
what they put in their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So maybe ghosts don&amp;rsquo;t exist after all.  They&amp;rsquo;re just another thing Dr
Feliciano made up to scare us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Have Sex While Hating Yourself And Others</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/hump</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/hump</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marissa Perez of &lt;em&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;the only arm of our media empire
that actually does any work&amp;mdash;today broke
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/05/violent-altercation-breaks-out-in-iv-provoked-by-homophobic-remarks&#34; title=&#34;Violent Altercation Breaks Out in IV, Provoked By Homophobic
Remarks&#34;&gt;the story of a hate crime that occurred last month&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violence broke out in Isla Vista on Trigo Road Friday, April 26,
following one student directing homophobic comments toward another,
reminding the campus community of the importance of creating a safe
climate in and around campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[T]he student who had made the homophobic comments began &amp;ldquo;kicking
[the victim&amp;rsquo;s] head repeatedly and started stomping on him,&amp;rdquo; said
Aljawad. &amp;ldquo;I just wanted him to not kill the guy, so we called the
cops.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident raises not only issues of campus climate but also the
dismissive attitude the police often take toward crimes against
minority groups.  Law enforcement is perceived by many to take the
side of those &lt;em&gt;perpetrating&lt;/em&gt; hate crimes, instead of those victimized
by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of this story, the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; was not silent.  In today&amp;rsquo;s
op-ed, Emile Nelson and R. Pengsta have a message for the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://queerumich.com/post/25021141159/lgbt-lgbtq-queer-quiltbag-gsm-gsrm-whats&#34; title=&#34;Queer \@ UMich: LGBT? LGBTQ? Queer? QUILTBAG? GSM? GSRM?&#34;&gt;GSRM&lt;/a&gt; community
at UCSB:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-15/to-hump-or-not-to-hump-he-said-she-said-edition/&#34; title=&#34;To Hump or Not to Hump? He Said, She Said Edition&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go away.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoothly articulating the principles behind
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/index.php?pid=101961#renewing&#34; title=&#34;Daily Nexus Mission Statement&#34;&gt;the mission statement of the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Nelson and Pengsta bravely defend
commonsense heterosexual values against the &amp;ldquo;compulsory homosexuality&amp;rdquo;
taught in liberal universities such as UCSB.  They also
unapologetically reaffirm the Biblical truth that men and women are
irredeemably different creatures, each incomprehensible to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nelson and Pengsta therefore present their polemic as a dialogue, with
Pengsta as the straight woman speaking to other straight women who
chase after men, and Nelson &lt;a href=&#34;batman.html&#34; title=&#34;Batman
is Best at Everything, Including Fighting the Matriarchy&#34;&gt;reprising his role&lt;/a&gt; as the
misogynistic fuckwit who slut-shames his female peers.  Discussing the
Serious Problem of having sex on a first date, Nelson
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-15/to-hump-or-not-to-hump-he-said-she-said-edition/&#34; title=&#34;To Hump or Not to Hump? He Said, She Said Edition&#34;&gt;pontificates finely&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]t&amp;rsquo;s risky to light the candles and whip out the Marvin Gaye on day
one for a couple of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleaze factor: You can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder that if she&amp;rsquo;s ready for
me on day one, who else is getting this kind of treatment?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Natural Order: It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to become friends before the
first hump than it is to try to go back and get to know each other
afterwards. You might feel satisfied, but you&amp;rsquo;ll probably never know
if she shares your love for Batman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nelson is of course perfectly correct that if a woman has had sex with
multiple (male!) partners she&amp;rsquo;s thereby worthless, but that point has
been made more eloquently elsewhere.  His second itemized bit of
19th-century wisdom is rather more original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a truth long-forgotten that men and women can only engage in
normal relations (&amp;ldquo;be friends&amp;rdquo;, to use the jargon) when they are not
and have never been engaged in abnormal relations (have not &amp;ldquo;fucked
each others&amp;rsquo; brains out&amp;rdquo;)&amp;mdash;and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jezebel.com/5954769/for-the-love-of-god-will-we-ever-stop-asking-if-men-and-women-can-be-ever-be-just-friends&#34; title=&#34;For the Love of God, Will We Ever Stop Asking if Men and Women Can
Really Be \&#39;Just Friends\&#39;?&#34;&gt;perhaps not even then!&lt;/a&gt;  Once the man has taken the woman as
his, she is no longer his equal and it is inappropriate and
emasculating for him to &amp;ldquo;talk to her&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;care about her opinion&amp;rdquo;
concerning Batman and similarly intellectual subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, by-definition-heterosexual &lt;strong&gt;Ladies:&lt;/strong&gt; do you want to talk about
Batman with Emile Nelson?  Then for the love of God, don&amp;rsquo;t have sex
with him.  But don&amp;rsquo;t have sex with anyone else either, since that
would make you a ruined trollop, unworthy of his attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe just don&amp;rsquo;t talk to Emile Nelson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Thomas Friedman and Matthew Yglesias Had a Child, That Child Would Be Mark Strong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/moral</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/moral</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like some bold, contrarian thinking to shake up the
stale Washington consensus.  Noted
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eschatonblog.com/2012/04/one-true-wanker-of-decade.html&#34; title=&#34;Thomas Friedman: The One True Wanker of the Decade&#34;&gt;wanker&lt;/a&gt; Thomas Friedman
is perhaps the finest practitioner of this art, the apogee of his
career being his bold and contrarian suggestion that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2009/01/14/friedman_7/&#34; title=&#34;Tom Friedman offers a perfect definition of \&amp;quot;terrorism\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;Israel terrorize the Palestinian population&lt;/a&gt;.  This
quite &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; idea took many by surprise, but has since been adopted by
the IDF to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Cast_Lead&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia: Operation Cast Lead&#34;&gt;great effect&lt;/a&gt;.  Matthew Yglesias is part of a
younger generation of wankers, but has risen rapidly in stature since
his inspired defense of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrdestructo.com/2013/04/destructo-salon-does-matthew-yglesias.html&#34; title=&#34;Destructo Salon: Does Matthew Yglesias Enjoy Murder?&#34;&gt;collapsing buildings on poor people in exchange for cheap denim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though these wankers will eventually retire and die, there is no
shortage of young wankers willing and ready to replace them, as Mark
Strong proves today.  Faced with the classic tension between
&amp;ldquo;optimists&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;pessimists&amp;rdquo; and their disagreements over whether
things are getting better or worse, Strong makes the brilliant
proposal that we simply
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-09/eternal-optimism-and-pessimism-both-impediments-to-human-progress/&#34; title=&#34;Eternal Optimism and Pessimism, Both Impediments to Human
Progress?&#34;&gt;stop caring about right and wrong&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas a pessimist sees the glass half-empty and an optimist sees
the glass half-full, a pragmatist simply observes the glass and its
contents and determines its maximum utility.  Moral judgments are
cut neatly out of the evaluation.  The situation is neither good nor
bad; the situation just is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a truly divine bit of wanking.  Strong pushes aside the
sentimental fools who cling to &amp;ldquo;principles&amp;rdquo; and presents his
pseudo-utilitarian neoliberalism as &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; detached, rational
worldview, unsullied by any sort of emotional attachment to the
millions oppressed by his beloved &amp;ldquo;bipartisan consensus&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of his pitch for &lt;em&gt;The World is Really Fucking Flat, Or:
I Want a Big House Like Tom Friedman&lt;/em&gt;, Strong shows that his writing
is just as horrific as that of his spiritual father:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re all entitled to our respective opinions, there is no
productive value in the belief that humanity is headed for a cliff
on a runaway train.  The same goes for plugging our ears with wax
and tying ourselves to the mast.  Ship, train, plane or
blimp&amp;mdash;whatever comparative vessel you prefer, if we don&amp;rsquo;t do
something, it&amp;rsquo;s going to crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Strong&amp;rsquo;s future looks bright.  The rest of us are fucked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Making Sense (feat. Ben Moss)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/sexy</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/sexy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daily Nexus&lt;/em&gt; writer Ben Moss, having failed to think of anything
interesting to write about in his Tuesday column, resigned himself to
authoring
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-07/51217/&#34; title=&#34;&amp;lt;3-to-&amp;lt;3 in Ones and Zeroes&#34;&gt;a thinkpiece on clickbait&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was mindlessly browsing the internet the other day, as one does,
and I came across an article promising to reveal the 21st century&amp;rsquo;s
sexiest career. I must say, I never expected Yahoo! Finance to be so
infatuated with &amp;ldquo;data scientists.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! is refreshingly upfront about the disingenuous nature of their
article, admitting that to take it seriously
&lt;a href=&#34;http://finance.yahoo.com/blogs/daily-ticker/sexiest-job-21st-century-122238562.html&#34; title=&#34;Yahoo! Finance: The Sexiest Job of the 21st Century&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;you have to buy the logic that what makes a career &amp;lsquo;sexy&amp;rsquo; is when demand for your skills outstrips supply, allowing you to command a sizable paycheck and options.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; This is
bullshit, of course, and Ben Moss could have used this quote to segue
into a discussion of the sort of soulless careerism that leads people
into believing that the best job is the one that pays the most.  But
this being the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;, we instead get something bizarre and
completely inane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I think about data science, the more I see its sexiness is
obvious to our place in time. Data is no longer boring, as I thought
it once was. Just look at UCSB. Here, our friends fight bitterly to
study accounting, we&amp;rsquo;re asked to fill out surveys every time we
check our emails and our perm numbers are (as ugly as it sounds to
say) crucial to our identity as students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing turns Ben on more than turning &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; his roommate&amp;rsquo;s alarm in
order to get a spot in ECON 3B; it&amp;rsquo;s positively orgasmic.  And the
second-best part of his day is when he hears that SurveyMonkey cares
so much about his opinion that it reaches out to him &lt;em&gt;in person!&lt;/em&gt;
(This is because nobody else does.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, Ben addresses the question of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; he gets so horned up
thinking about MySQL tables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My take on the paradigm shift is a little different. I think it&amp;rsquo;s
about the role data has played in our growing up and the way we use
it so extensively now. After all, we&amp;rsquo;ve all sent off a meaningful
email or an emotional text. We&amp;rsquo;ve all proudly fashioned our Facebook
profiles to mean something about who we are. In one way or another,
we&amp;rsquo;ve all had a heart-to-heart in the ones and zeroes of computer
programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben is a living testament to the truth of Marshall McLuhan&amp;rsquo;s famous
dictum that &amp;ldquo;the medium is the message.&amp;rdquo;  He is unable to separate the
content of what he writes from the medium in which he composes it.
While researching this column, an anonymous source provided me with
one of Ben Moss&amp;rsquo; sexts, and you can see for yourself what living in
this digital environment has done to Ben&amp;rsquo;s ideas of romance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;js&#34;&gt;for ( var i=0; i &amp;lt; 5; i++ ) {
  if ( i % 2 === 0 ) {
    alert(&amp;quot;I love you&amp;quot;);
  }
  else {
    alert(&amp;quot;I love you not&amp;quot;);
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(His deep immersion into digital media has also apparently erased the
distinction in his mind between &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the ones and zeroes of
computer programming.&amp;ldquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the conclusion of his essay, Ben finally recognizes his digital
addiction and vows to make a change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do think we need to make a practice of diplomacy, as it may
not come as naturally in the digital age.  There&amp;rsquo;s still something
intangible and more effective about spoken interaction, especially
when something is being negotiated.  When emailing, you have to
concern yourself with precision in language, exactness in tone and
concision in length. Moreover, emails are easy to delete.
Negotiating in person can actually save time and grief because
arguably the human face is so innately appealing that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to
reject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m actually trying to include less and less meaning in
my emails.  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make them vague and unclear.  The less I
send electronically, the less I find myself attracted to data, the
less I leave myself open to digital criticism, the less&amp;mdash;in
fact&amp;mdash;I foresee a future in cold, robotic shades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if anticipating this very piece, Ben Moss here declares his
intention to &lt;em&gt;stop making sense&lt;/em&gt; in order to avoid the relentless
&amp;ldquo;digital criticism&amp;rdquo; that
&lt;a href=&#34;drama.html&#34; title=&#34;An Unlikely Friendship&#34;&gt;last week led the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; to surrender to the &lt;em&gt;Nonsense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and become a subsidiary of our media empire,
a misbehaving pet that we continue to scold.  We look forward to
publishing Moss&amp;rsquo; next column, which will consist of epic poetry
written only with consonants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of press time, Ben replied to his mother&amp;rsquo;s text about his phone
bill with &amp;ldquo;Forever six times have I killed the wurm.  Life is death
and worse.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman is Best at Everything, Including Fighting the Matriarchy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/batman</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/batman</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been more than four decades since the last Men&amp;rsquo;s Rights
Activists were routed by Misandrists during the Tit Offensive.  Since
then the feminist dystopia has ruthlessly victimized men, forcing them
into poverty and making the wearing of the fedora a daring and
subversive act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/kMCp0Rs.gif&#34; alt=&#34;I have no idea where this GIF came from.&#34; title=&#34;Man puts on fedora, nods slowly.  TEXT: \&amp;quot;EUPHORIC\&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is hope!  There are still male heroes fighting the
matriarchy and demanding their Man-given rights to be Men.  One such
hero is Emile Nelson, who today authored
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-01/boobies-booze-and-batman-3-little-words-that-make-men-melt/&#34; title=&#34;Boobies, Booze and Batman: 3 Little Words That Make Men Melt&#34;&gt;a treatise on what men deserve from the women they are forced to copulate with&lt;/a&gt;, since
it&amp;rsquo;s still illegal for men to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Men_Going_Their_Own_Way&#34; title=&#34;Entry for \&amp;quot;Men Going Their Own Way\&amp;quot; on RationalWiki&#34;&gt;Go Their Own Way&lt;/a&gt;.  Nelson
boldly proclaims, in a section titled &amp;ldquo;Show Up Naked&amp;rdquo;, that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are few things [worse] than a girl who is brave enough to take
some control in a relationship.  This means saying what you like,
how you like it, when you like it, where you like it and not being
afraid to be the initiator and get nasty-specific with your boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern woman, drunk on the theories of Lindy West and other
radical feminists, has come to believe that it is her own desires that
matter, rather than those of male columnists in shitty college
newspapers.  They are tragically mistaken, of course, and not only are
ruining the happiness of their male slaves but are in fact acting
contrary to their own interests.  Emile insists that in order for a
woman to have any chance of &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; dying alone and unloved, &amp;ldquo;you need
to be completely naked in each sense of the word every time you show
up to play with your man.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;boobies&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; is the first of the &amp;ldquo;words that make men melt.&amp;rdquo;
When Jason Collins, the NBA player who
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sportsillustrated.cnn.com/magazine/news/20130429/jason-collins-gay-nba-player/&#34; title=&#34;Why NBA center Jason Collins is coming out now&#34;&gt;came out on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, was asked what
makes &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; melt, he answered&amp;mdash;without hesitation&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;boobies&amp;rdquo;.  Upon
being
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lenadunham/status/329048636094836738&#34; title=&#34;Tweet by @lenadunham on 30 April 2013&#34;&gt;threatened with sexual assault by Lena Dunham&lt;/a&gt;, Collins dissolved into his
constituent elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second key word identified by Emile Nelson is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;beer&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;
Discussing &lt;strong&gt;beer&lt;/strong&gt;, Nelson writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as guys like to see a lady squeal, it&amp;rsquo;s not always enough to
go home thinking &amp;ldquo;yeaaa I bet she feels good&amp;rdquo; while armies of ninjas
(infamously known as blue balls) slash up your downstairs business.
I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to say that you should never ever let your man go home
unfinished, but please, if you&amp;rsquo;re in a sexual relationship, don&amp;rsquo;t
let his little friend&amp;rsquo;s satisfaction fall to the wayside on a
regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a novel argument that, for men, &lt;em&gt;sex with a women is an act of
self-defense&lt;/em&gt;.  When asked what his greatest fear is, Jason Collins
answered, &amp;ldquo;the little ninjas in my balls, definitely.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third word that, when uttered, imbues men with the power to fight
misandry is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Batman&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single boy has [the same] dreams of [the same] freaky ways he
wishes he could get it on and most of them are harmless and
exciting.  The problem is that far too often, these fantasies are
disregarded because the act itself is &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;  I&amp;rsquo;m here to
tell you that if you let him wear his Batman mask and talk in the
Dark Knight&amp;rsquo;s voice as he explores your Batcave with his Batmobile,
you will have given that man a memory to be cherished until the end
of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Collins confirmed in his &lt;em&gt;Sports Illustrated&lt;/em&gt; interview that his
favorite sexual roleplaying scenario is &amp;ldquo;anything involving Batman.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emile Nelson ends
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-05-01/boobies-booze-and-batman-3-little-words-that-make-men-melt/&#34; title=&#34;Boobies, Booze and Batman: 3 Little Words That Make Men Melt&#34;&gt;his manifesto&lt;/a&gt; with a
final warning to any women whose misandry has not been fully
eviscerated by his wise words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men are fairly simple creatures; take care of them and they&amp;rsquo;ll take
care of you.  Just remember, ladies, trashy has the word &amp;ldquo;trash&amp;rdquo; in
it for a reason.  Keep it classy until the door closes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, show up naked, but don&amp;rsquo;t, because that would mean
you&amp;rsquo;re a slut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*fist pump&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Unlikely Friendship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/drama</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/drama</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We at &lt;em&gt;The Daily Nonsense&lt;/em&gt; have not been particularly kind to the
time-traveling bandits behind the pseudo-publication known as &amp;ldquo;The
Daily Nexus&amp;rdquo;.  Our writers have referred to them as a
&lt;a href=&#34;../nonsense.html&#34; title=&#34;Announcement of the launch of The
Daily Nonsense on Baruffio.com&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;cabal of hacks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; who publish
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn/status/327667602971320320&#34; title=&#34;Tweet by @dunndunndunn on 25 April 2013&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;racist garbage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  So it was not particularly
surprising that they eventually made an official response.  What was
surprising was when and how this response was made, and the
heartwarming ending to the ensuing affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Nonsense&lt;/em&gt; was launched yesterday to much acclaim.  The most
evident testimony of its immediate impact was the reaction from a
group of campus Republicans, who went back in time &lt;em&gt;over 40 years&lt;/em&gt; to
start a competing publication.  These scoundrels founded &amp;ldquo;The Daily
Nexus&amp;rdquo; in order to undermine our credibility and dilute our brand.
For decades they prepared for the day when they would use their clout
to strike the &lt;em&gt;Nonsense&lt;/em&gt; down on the very day it launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re finally on @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/twitter&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search/%23socialmedia&#34;&gt;#socialmedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search/%23brands&#34;&gt;#brands&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search/%23tcot&#34;&gt;#tcot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/Nf3n7Ms18b&#34; title=&#34;http://baruffio.com/ds/&#34;&gt;baruffio.com/ds/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The Daily Nonsense (@thedailynexus) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thedailynexus/status/328254426647248896&#34;&gt;April 27, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By launching on a weekend, we attempted to catch the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; off-guard
and establish ourselves as the only legitimate news source:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;NB: Campus Republicans are trying
to dilute our brand by squatting on the @&lt;a
href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus&#34;&gt;dailynexus&lt;/a&gt; account.  They are NOT the Daily Nonsense!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The Daily Nonsense (@thedailynexus) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thedailynexus/status/328256959952347138&#34;&gt;April 27, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late that night, they struck.  We at the &lt;em&gt;Nonsense&lt;/em&gt; knew what was
coming as soon as the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328373627819028480&#34; title=&#34;Tweet from @dailynexus on 27 April 2013&#34;&gt;tweeted a link to an article&lt;/a&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;Seth Rogen enjoys
being in control&amp;rdquo;.  We were threatening the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt; over
the UCSB news cycle, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328374159220539392&#34; title=&#34;Deleted tweet by @dailynexus from 27 April 2013&#34;&gt;they were not pleased&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_wtf.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot taken by our Managing Editor and feline mascot [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;The Daily Nexus replies to our tweet with
\&amp;quot;what the fuck\&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 40 years of hegemony the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; was suddenly experiencing real
competition.  Having become so accustomed to being on top, they
panicked and lashed out.  It became clear that
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328376801854369792&#34; title=&#34;Deleted tweet by @dailynexus from 27 April 2013&#34;&gt;they were confused&lt;/a&gt;, no
longer sure how to respond:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_what.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot by [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;Tweets: @dunndunndunn asks \&amp;quot;gosh what&#39;s
up with the daily nexus\&amp;quot; and @dailynexus replies \&amp;quot;good question\&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally comprehending the magnitude of our superiority, they
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328376961317613568&#34; title=&#34;Deleted tweet by @dailynexus from 27 April 2013&#34;&gt;acknowledged defeat&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_good.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot by [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;@dailynexus to @thedailynexus: \&amp;quot;good
one\&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some hasty negotiations, it was decided that the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; would
become a subsidiary of the &lt;em&gt;Nonsense&lt;/em&gt;.  As part of the agreement, they
began retweeting our content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_tcot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot by [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;@dailynexus retweets @thedailynexus&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_cat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot by [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;@dailynexus retweets @dunndunndunn&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the merger was not entirely painless.  Certain comments by one of
our writers
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328382045577433089&#34; title=&#34;Deleted tweet by @dailynexus on 27 April 2013&#34;&gt;rankled the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; staff&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/dn_really.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot by [\@dunndunndunn](https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn
&amp;quot;Twitter&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;Tweets: @dunndunndunn says \&amp;quot;The
@dailynexus is publishing more racist garbage\&amp;quot; and @dailynexus
replies \&amp;quot;really now\&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is rather inflammatory!  In addition, the article in question was
found, &lt;a href=&#34;pc.html&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;What Do Words Mean?\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;on closer examination&lt;/a&gt;, to
be a work of biting &lt;em&gt;anti-racist&lt;/em&gt; satire.  &lt;strong&gt;We therefore apologized
to Mark Strong and the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; for the remarks of our feline mascot,
and do so publicly again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That misunderstanding aside, all is well between us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daily Nexus (@dailynexus) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dailynexus/status/328385484080443392&#34;&gt;April 28, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future looks bright for the joint &lt;em&gt;Nonsense/Nexus&lt;/em&gt;.  Going forward
we will be officially merging into a single publication known as the
&lt;strong&gt;Noxious&lt;/strong&gt;.  Thank you again for your support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do These Words Mean?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/pc</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/pc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Strong, Managing Editor of the &lt;em&gt;Daily Nexus&lt;/em&gt; and author of a
column with the whimsical title &amp;ldquo;Politically Incorrect&amp;rdquo;, is troubled
and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-04-25/so-wrong-its-right/&#34; title=&#34;So Wrong, It&#39;s Right&#34;&gt;has turned to his readers with a pressing question&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;politically incorrect&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Goodness!&amp;rdquo; you might be saying.  &amp;ldquo;How could dear Mark write a column
called &amp;lsquo;Politically Incorrect&amp;rsquo; without knowing what that means?
Surely the &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt;, of all student newspapers, is rigorously dedicated
to accuracy and would never print idiotic bullshit that flies in the
face of basic decency under the guise of bravely opposing conventional
wisdom?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong reassures us somewhat in the next paragraph by exhibiting his
subtle analytical skills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a question I&amp;rsquo;ve been asking myself for a while.  With 18
articles claiming the title, you&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d have figured it out by
now.  But the question is actually twofold.  &amp;ldquo;Politically
Incorrect,&amp;rdquo; the column, is not the same thing as politically
incorrect, the concept, any more than a house is the same as its
foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really is a crucial distinction.  Mark Strong&amp;rsquo;s eighteen episodes
of concern trolling are in fact &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; identical with a term that is
widely used to make various forms of bigotry socially acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nor is his column identical with the television show once hosted by
fellow freethinker
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juancole.com/2012/09/muslims-are-no-different-or-why-bill-mahers-blood-libel-is-bigotry.html&#34; title=&#34;Muslims are no Different, or why Bill Maher&#39;s blood libel is
Bigotry&#34;&gt;Bill Mahar&lt;/a&gt;, the title of which Strong honors by using as the title of
his own column.  (&amp;ldquo;Honors&amp;rdquo; here is the politically correct term for
&amp;ldquo;steals&amp;rdquo;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It soon becomes clear that our faith in Mr. Strong was not misguided,
as he demonstrates a keen understanding of how &amp;ldquo;politically incorrect&amp;rdquo;
is used to perpetuate racism, sexism, and other systems of
institutional discrimination in a society where outright hate speech
is no longer acceptable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of this column, [political incorrectness is] about
delivering a take on an issue free of the usual constraints and
pretensions of social etiquette.  We all have a stern and
Sharpie-wielding soldier stationed somewhere between our mouths and
our brains, ready to scribble out any statements that could leave us
vulnerable to the criticism of others.  For people like Mel Gibson
and Michael Richards, that guy is doing us all a service. But he&amp;rsquo;s a
conservative censor, strictly by the books, and his indiscriminate
scribbling often leaves those of us with actual points silenced just
the same as those who blame their personal shortcomings on &amp;ldquo;the
Jews.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the problem with political correctness.  For all its promise
of tolerance and progress, it fails to make the crucial distinction
between the reasonable and the reasonless.  A white supremacist and
a white philosopher might share nothing in common beside their use
of the word &amp;ldquo;nigger,&amp;rdquo; but from a politically correct perspective,
this is enough to set them equal.  When it comes to being
politically correct, context is thrown carelessly out the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Strong here excellently brings out how racism can be given a pass
when in the correct context.  It is difficult indeed to defend the
writers at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://takimag.com/article/im_not_a_racist_sexist_or_a_homophobe_you_nigger_slut_faggot/print&#34; title=&#34;Big Ol&#39; Trigger Warning for Racism/Sexism/Homophobia&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taki&amp;rsquo;s Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but if you&amp;rsquo;re
a &lt;strong&gt;college professor&lt;/strong&gt; of Philosophy (a discipline that &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt;
doesn&amp;rsquo;t have issues with diversity) you can claim that you&amp;rsquo;re speaking
in an &amp;ldquo;academic context&amp;rdquo; and that you are really just being coolly
analytical and why are these students walking out of your class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example that Strong might have mentioned is the &amp;ldquo;hipster
racism&amp;rdquo; of Lisa Lampanelli, though her delivery was so artless that
even
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/04/lena-dunham-girls-race.html&#34; title=&#34;White \&amp;quot;Girls\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;accidental racist Lena Dunham&lt;/a&gt; distanced herself from the &amp;ldquo;joke&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me with my nigga @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lenadunham&#34;&gt;lenadunham&lt;/a&gt; of @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hbogirls&#34;&gt;hbogirls&lt;/a&gt; - I love this beyotch!! &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/VOaV30eB&#34; title=&#34;http://say.ly/oKP5chO&#34;&gt;say.ly/oKP5chO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lisa Lampanelli (@LisaLampanelli) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LisaLampanelli/status/303308274038616064&#34;&gt;February 18, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;em&gt;Nexus&lt;/em&gt; writer concludes, tongue firmly in cheek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is politically incorrect?  We could come up with
Webster-worthy definitions for the next 50 years, but none of them
would ever quite hit the nail on the head.  It&amp;rsquo;s the line between
racism and reality, the comment you&amp;rsquo;d think but never say, the punch
line that makes the audience groan.  It&amp;rsquo;s the aborted child of every
argument, the thing you&amp;rsquo;d rather drown in the tub than raise to call
your own, and more often than not, it&amp;rsquo;s the pure, unadulterated
truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that nod to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2012/07/11/why-daniel-tosh-s-rape-joke-at-the-laugh-factory-wasn-t-funny.html&#34; title=&#34;Why Daniel Tosh&#39;s &#39;Rape Joke&#39; at the Laugh Factory Wasn&#39;t Funny&#34;&gt;Daniel Tosh&lt;/a&gt;,
Mark Strong makes it quite clear what the pure truth is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tanehisi&#34;&gt;tanehisi&lt;/a&gt; &#34;politically incorrect&#34; itself is a politically correct way to describe oppressive ignorance at best and sheer bigotry at worst.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andrea S. (@andreaTshang) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andreaTshang/status/320715247193321472&#34;&gt;April 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical discussion of a metaphysical thesis recently proposed by Mr. Robin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/robin</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nonsense/robin</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Daily Nexus&lt;/em&gt; is not known for publishing cutting-edge research in
analytical philosophy, but on the 2nd of this month
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dailynexus.com/2013-04-02/right-said-gay-or-not-marriage-is-already-in-the-dog-house/&#34; title=&#34;Gay or Not, Marriage Is Already in the Dog House&#34;&gt;Mr. Jeffrey Robin authored a startling piece&lt;/a&gt; in which he
advanced a very novel claim of just this sort.  Here is the claim in
context; just prior to the paragraph I quote below, Mr. Robin suggests
that it is no use pondering whether &lt;em&gt;the homosexual&lt;/em&gt; poses an
existential threat to the marriage institution, given that marriage
has been irredeemably fucked for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift in attitude and treatment of marriage has come both from
society and governmental action. For too much of our history, we
have been concerned about where and when people are allowed to sit
at the lunch counter or on a bus. This, in turn, has lead to an
attitude that everyone has a right to sit anywhere they
please. Indeed, if nothing is true than everything must necessarily
be permitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not wish to downplay the importance of what Mr. Robin has to say
in the first three sentences of this passage&amp;mdash;I entirely share his
belief that allowing the Negro to sit anywhere he likes was one of the
great stumbles in our nation&amp;rsquo;s history&amp;mdash;but I am here concerned with
the last sentence.  More precisely I am concerned with the following
conditional: &amp;ldquo;if nothing is true than everything must necessarily be
permitted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How remarkable!  &lt;em&gt;If nothing is true than everything must necessarily
be permitted.&lt;/em&gt;  The profundity of this statement cannot be
overstated.  In order that we may attempt to grasp it, a formalization
is in order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math display=&#34;block&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&#34;&gt;&lt;mrow&gt;&lt;mo&gt;¬&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mo&gt;∃&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;→&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mo&gt;▫&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mo&gt;∀&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo stretchy=&#34;false&#34;&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;→&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mtext mathvariant=&#34;bold&#34;&gt;PE&lt;/mtext&gt;&lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo stretchy=&#34;false&#34;&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here &lt;em&gt;Tx&lt;/em&gt; means &lt;em&gt;x is true&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ay&lt;/em&gt; means &lt;em&gt;y is an action&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;PE&lt;/strong&gt; is
the permissibility operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something of a conundrum confronts us if we attempt to move from left to
right along this conditional. The antecedent is only satisfied if
nothing (presumably no proposition) is true, but if the very conditional
proposition &lt;em&gt;if nothing is true than everything must necessarily be
permitted&lt;/em&gt; is true, then the antecedent is not satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we learn anything by moving right-to-left?  It seems plausible
(even for a Communist such as myself!) that there are some things
which are not permissible: perhaps obstructing the overthrow of the
bourgeoisie, or being openly racist in a college newspaper in 2013.  In
any case, Mr. Robin certainly seems to believe that there are some
things that are impermissible: his invocation of this very conditional
is part of an attempt to discredit his political opponents by painting
them as moral relativists or, worse, as nihilists.  So if it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
true that everything is permissible, then by &lt;em&gt;modus tollens&lt;/em&gt; it is not
true that nothing is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Robin has established that at least &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; is true.  But
unfortunately for him, the undeniable truth that he has established in
his article seems to be this one: that Mr. Jeffrey Robin is an
imbecile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>