<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Map on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/map/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2013-11-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Unplottable&#34; is Unpossible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so &amp;mdash; apparently &amp;mdash; incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem impossible, and when we think through it carefully we&amp;rsquo;ll
see that it basically is.  A coherent notion of &lt;em&gt;unplottability&lt;/em&gt;
cannot not say anything about what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of
paper.  Witches and wizards might, however, try to stop people from
&lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts from that piece of paper &amp;mdash; the
information can be &lt;em&gt;encoded&lt;/em&gt;, but it may be possible with magic to
prevent it from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ultimately this won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to
find Hogwarts.  Unplottability is a scam that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on &amp;mdash; how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable &amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 121; page references are
from the UK versions of the &lt;em&gt;Pottermore&lt;/em&gt; ebooks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists or whatever, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point here.
Just what on earth does it &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; for something to be Unplottable?  If
I know where Hogwarts is, what stops me from drawing a map and marking
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on the relevant section? (I think it&amp;rsquo;s safe to assume that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaiaonline.com/forum/harry-potter/if-hogwarts-castle-is-unplottable/t.13491169_15/#15&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;If Hogwarts castle is unplottable...\&amp;quot; at Gaia Online&#34;&gt;Hogwarts is unplottable if Durmstrang is&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;We can figure out where Hogwarts is&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, drawing a map and marking &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on the relevant section
requires knowing where Hogwarts is.  One way that it would be
impossible to plot Hogwarts on a map is if &lt;em&gt;nobody actually knows&lt;/em&gt;
where Hogwarts is.  Maybe after the Founders build Hogwarts, they
&lt;em&gt;Obliviated&lt;/em&gt; each other to forget where they were and then brought in
job candidates by Floo powder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how, in this case, could the rails for the Hogarts Express have
been laid down centuries after Hogwarts was built?  Even if some
ingenious witch or wizard successfully cast the exceedingly difficult
&lt;em&gt;Build-a-Train-Track-From-Here-to-King&amp;rsquo;s-Cross-Station&lt;/em&gt; spell, you
could then just follow the Hogwarts Express in the air, like Ron and
Harry do in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, and record the castle&amp;rsquo;s location
relative to King&amp;rsquo;s Cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t consist simply in Hogwart&amp;rsquo;s location being
unknown by everyone.  If &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; know
&lt;a href=&#34;http://members.madasafish.com/~cj_whitehound/Fanfic/map_of_Hogwarts/location.htm&#34; title=&#34;White Hound&#39;s discussion of the location of Hogwarts&#34;&gt;this much about the castle&amp;rsquo;s location&lt;/a&gt;, then a clever
witch or wizard can certainly discover its whereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;I can even draw a map and write &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if that&amp;rsquo;s true, and it&amp;rsquo;s possible to discover where Hogwarts
is, why can&amp;rsquo;t we be prevented from recording that information?  Why
did I say above that unplottability &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; mean that information
about the location of Hogwarts is impossible to encode?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how someone might try to prevent us from encoding that
sort of information.  Whatever they do, I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;ll manage
it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose a witch or wizard managed to cast an enchantment that had
the following effect: whenever someone writes &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; (or
something sufficiently similar) at roughly the point where Hogwarts
is located on a map, the enchantment erases what you&amp;rsquo;ve written.
This obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, because you could refer to
Hogwarts using a different name.  This is a ban on &lt;em&gt;using
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; to refer to Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;.  It is not a ban on plotting
Hogwarts on a map.  If I am trying to make you a map with Hogwarts
on it, I could tell you &amp;ldquo;I will write &amp;lsquo;Pigfarts&amp;rsquo; instead of
&amp;lsquo;Hogwarts&amp;rsquo;&amp;ldquo;, and then when I write &amp;ldquo;Pigfarts&amp;rdquo;, I am plotting
Hogwarts on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second problem with this approach is that if the enchantment
only detects when I&amp;rsquo;ve written &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;, my writing will be
visible until I finish that string of letters.  If you are
watching over my shoulder as I work, you will see me get at least
as far as &amp;ldquo;Hogwart&amp;rdquo; and will probably infer my intention (to plot
Hogwarts on this map), and the enchantment will be foiled.  In
order to work, the enchantment would have to determine our
&lt;em&gt;intentions&lt;/em&gt; and act before we can even start writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of &lt;em&gt;intention&lt;/em&gt; brings us to a second possible method
to make it impossible to encode information about a place&amp;rsquo;s
location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose it&amp;rsquo;s possible, somehow, to determine when I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;intending&lt;/em&gt;
to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Maybe an enchantment could figure out
when I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about Hogwarts in a certain way while mapmaking,
or whatever.  When this happens, the enchantment makes me forget
what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, or triggers something like the Tongue-Tying Curse
except for writing, or in some other way prevents me from
fulfilling my intention to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
this work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work because it&amp;rsquo;s possible for someone to make
something that &lt;em&gt;functions&lt;/em&gt; as a map showing the location of
Hogwarts without intending to.  Suppose a Muggle child is drawing
fake maps for fun and &lt;em&gt;accidentally&lt;/em&gt; draws one with a castle in
just the right place on an accurate representation of the Scottish
highlands.  It&amp;rsquo;s even possible that &amp;mdash; by a massive coincidence
&amp;mdash; the child could decide to label this castle &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a sense in which this Muggle child
has not plotted Hogwarts on a map, the following scenario could
still occur: the child drops their map while leaving King&amp;rsquo;s Cross,
and it is picked up by a witch or wizard, who has been seeking the
location of Hogwarts.  They assume that someone plotted Hogwarts
on a map and then dropped it.  They guide themselves using this
map, and as a result arrive at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first solution was obviously insufficient, in part because it
failed to account for a mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s intention.  But in our examination
of the second solution, we can see that accounting for the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
intention won&amp;rsquo;t work either.  Our scenario, involving the child
serendipitously writing &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; in exactly the right place on a map
of the Scottish highlands, might be a scenario in which it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;strictly
false&lt;/em&gt; that Hogwarts was plotted on a map, but the spirit of the idea
has clearly been violated.  The &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of unplottability is to keep
people from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; maps to locate Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we should look next at how a witch or wizard would &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; a map to
find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;But I can&amp;rsquo;t use that map to find Hogwarts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crucial detail of our scenario above was that the witch or wizard
who finds the child&amp;rsquo;s map &lt;em&gt;assumes&lt;/em&gt; that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot
Hogwarts on their map.  They believe &amp;mdash; incorrectly, in this case &amp;mdash;
that the map was written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  The witch
or wizard believes &amp;mdash; again incorrectly &amp;mdash; that they &lt;em&gt;recognize the
communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to communicate to the
reader the location of Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose our witch or wizard had not made this mistake.  Suppose they
overheard the Muggle child taking about the map before dropping it,
and realized that it was pure coincidence that led the child to label
a map with &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.  If the witch or wizard nonetheless picked up
the map, they would not mistake it for a map showing the location of
Hogwarts because they would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; take themselves to recognize the
author&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.  They would not think that the map
was written with a communicative intent.  They would not learn
anything from the map because they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is
anything to learn.  Information transmission of this sort requires the
belief in a communicative intention, and when this is missing it will
not occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if unplottability does anything at all, it prevents readers of maps
from recognizing a communicative intention.  Even if a witch or wizard
finds a map on which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of
unplottability will be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
communicative intention.  The reader will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are
reading a map showing the location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in
a situation similar to the witch or wizard who knows that they are
looking at the scrawlings of a Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but whatever, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter because you can find Hogwarts anyway using maps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed to be coming together nicely until I got
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHZNpFiIQbA#t=0h06m14s&#34;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;
from an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenrobynne&#34;&gt;anonymous reviewer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all due respect my lord, there&amp;rsquo;s just one tiny flaw with this
flawless plan &amp;hellip; the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augh, you&amp;rsquo;re right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and therefore
&amp;mdash; because we used the Map to find the relative location of Hogwarts
&amp;mdash; locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking, &amp;ldquo;Whatever, Snape.  This loophole probably
only affects Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  Who cares?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only guess at this point is that unplottability is a scam.  There
aren&amp;rsquo;t enough jobs in the wizarding world so the Ministry made up
things like unplottability and &lt;a href=&#34;trace.html&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s No Such
Thing as the Trace&#34;&gt;the Trace&lt;/a&gt; in order to create positions for otherwise
useless people who couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass their O.W.L.s.  They go around making
things like the World Cup stadium unplottable and get to feel good
about themselves, because given the level of intelligence in the
wizarding world they probably don&amp;rsquo;t realize that what they&amp;rsquo;re doing is
useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe unplottability still does prevent information transmission, and
maybe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.  Either way it&amp;rsquo;s basically useless, but that
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a big surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>