<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Time on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/time/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-05-06 20:00:00 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;It is too late, you understand me?&#8221;: Time travel in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 20:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/time</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here at &lt;em&gt;Baruffio&lt;/em&gt; we sometimes cast a critical eye on &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter,&lt;/em&gt;
and amuse ourselves by pointing out inconsistencies in the books (then
&lt;a href=&#34;/p/trace&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s no Such
Thing as the Trace&#34;&gt;weaving them into conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;).  But time travel in &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; is a
model of consistency, illustrating wonderfully how time travel
works&amp;mdash;if it&amp;rsquo;s possible at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Going back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 21 of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban,&lt;/em&gt; Harry and Hermione wake up in
the hospital wing to learn that Sirius Black is about to receive the
Dementor&amp;rsquo;s Kiss.  It is, as Dumbledore tells them, too late to save
him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sirius has not acted like an innocent man. The attack on the Fat
Lady&amp;mdash;entering Gryffindor Tower with a knife&amp;mdash;without Pettigrew,
alive or dead, we have no chance of overturning Sirius&amp;rsquo; sentence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you believe us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I do,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore quietly. &amp;ldquo;But I have no power to make
other men see the truth, or to overrule the Minister for Magic &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry stared up into the grave face and felt as though the ground
beneath him was falling sharply away.  He had grown used to the idea
that Dumbledore could solve anything.  He had expected Dumbledore to
pull some amazing solution out of the air.  But no &amp;hellip; their last
hope was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What we need,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore slowly, and his light-blue eyes
moved from Harry to Hermione, &amp;ldquo;is more &lt;em&gt;time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo; Hermione began. And then her eyes became very round. &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, pay attention,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore, speaking very low, and very
clearly.  &amp;ldquo;Sirius is locked in Professor Flitwick&amp;rsquo;s office on the
seventh floor.  Thirteenth window from the right of the West Tower.
If all goes well, you will be able to save more than one innocent
life tonight.  But remember this, both of you. &lt;em&gt;You must not be
seen.&lt;/em&gt; Miss Granger, you know the law&amp;mdash;you know what is at stake
&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;you&amp;mdash;must&amp;mdash;not&amp;mdash;be&amp;mdash;seen”&lt;/em&gt; (Chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so they go back in time, to rescue Buckbeak the Hippogriff and
Sirius Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;You must not be seen, and you &lt;em&gt;will not&lt;/em&gt; be seen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry and Hermione go back in time with the intention of preventing
Buckbeak from being killed.  But it&amp;rsquo;s very important to realize that
&lt;em&gt;Buckbeak never was killed.&lt;/em&gt;  When Hermione spins the Time-Turner to
send her and Harry back three hours, Buckbeak isn&amp;rsquo;t dead.  They&amp;rsquo;d
already saved him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to make this clear because Rowling leaves Buckbeak&amp;rsquo;s
fate deliberately ambiguous the first time around, in Chapter 16
and 17.  When Hermione, Harry, Ron, and Scabbers leave Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s hut at
sundown, they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they hear Buckbeak being killed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rat was squealing wildly, but not loudly enough to cover up the
sounds drifting from Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s garden. There was a jumble of
indistinct male voices, a silence and then, without warning, the
unmistakeable swish and thud of an axe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione swayed on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They did it!&amp;rdquo; she whispered to Harry. &amp;ldquo;I d-don&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;mdash;they
did it!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s mind had gone blank with shock. The three of them stood
transfixed with horror under the Invisibility Cloak. The very last
rays of the setting sun were casting a bloody light over the
long-shadowed grounds. Then, behind them, they heard a wild howling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hagrid,&amp;rdquo; Harry muttered. Without thinking about what he was doing,
he made to turn back, but both Ron and Hermione seized his arms
(Chapters 16&amp;ndash;17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they&amp;rsquo;re leaving the cabin, they don&amp;rsquo;t see Buckbeak getting killed.
They hear Hagrid howling, but they can&amp;rsquo;t hear it clearly.  This is
because Buckbeak &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; get killed, and Hagrid is howling from joy,
not from grief.  When Harry and Hermione go back in time, the first
thing they do is rescue Buckbeak.  While Hagrid, Dumbledore, a
Ministry committee member, and the executioner Macnair are in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s
hut, Harry unties Buckbeak and leads him away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s back door had opened with a bang. Harry, Hermione and
Buckbeak stood quite still; even the Hippogriff seemed to be
listening intently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silence &amp;hellip; then&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where is it?&amp;rdquo; said the reedy voice of the Committee member. &amp;ldquo;Where
is the beast?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was tied here!&amp;rdquo; said the executioner furiously. &amp;ldquo;I saw it! Just
here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How extraordinary,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore. There was a note of amusement
in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beaky!&amp;rdquo; said Hagrid huskily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a swishing noise, and the thud of an axe. The executioner
seemed to have swung it into the fence in anger. And then came the
howling, and &lt;strong&gt;this time they could hear Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s words through his
sobs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gone! Gone! Bless his little beak, he&amp;rsquo;s gone! Musta pulled himself
free! Beaky, yeh clever boy!&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 21, my emphasis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve emphasized the important clause above.  It was never true that
Buckbeak got executed.  Hagrid is sobbing with joy &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; times we see
this scene.  When Harry and Hermione are under the Invisibility Cloak
with Ron and Scabbers, they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they are listening to Macnair
killing the Hippogriff, but they are &lt;em&gt;wrong:&lt;/em&gt; Buckbeak had already
been rescued&amp;mdash;by them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the past when he casts his Patronus, either.
After he, Hermione, Ron, Sirius, Lupin, Snape, and Pettigrew leave the
Shrieking Shack, the full moon comes out and Lupin transforms into a
werewolf.  Pettigrew escapes in the confusion, and Sirius chases after
him.  Harry and Hermione find Sirius at the edge of the Hogwarts lake,
surrounded by Dementors.  Sirius and Hermione faint, and just before
Harry&amp;rsquo;s soul is sucked from his body by the Dementor&amp;rsquo;s Kiss, something
miraculous happens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something was driving the Dementors back &amp;hellip; it was circling around
him and Sirius and Hermione &amp;hellip; the rattling, sucking sounds of the
Dementors were fading. They were leaving &amp;hellip; the air was warm again
&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With every ounce of strength he could muster, Harry raised his head
a few inches and saw an animal amidst the light, galloping away
across the lake. Eyes blurred with sweat, Harry tried to make out
what it was &amp;hellip; it was bright as a unicorn.  Fighting to stay
conscious, Harry watched it canter to a halt as it reached the
opposite shore.  For a moment, Harry saw, by its brightness,
somebody welcoming it back &amp;hellip; raising his hand to pat it
&amp;hellip; someone who looked strangely familiar &amp;hellip; but it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be
&amp;hellip; (Chapter 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry thinks he was saved by his father, but he&amp;rsquo;s wrong.  He saved
himself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry raised his head to look at the circle of Dementors across the
lake.  One of them was lowering its hood.  It was time for the
rescuer to appear&amp;mdash;but no one was coming to help this time&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it hit him&amp;mdash;he understood. He hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen his father&amp;mdash;he
had seen &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry flung himself out from behind the bush and pulled out his
wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;EXPECTO PATRONUM!&amp;rdquo; he yelled (Chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Harry does this, he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changing the past.  The person who
cast the Patronus was him, all along:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;mdash;you conjured up a Patronus that drove
away all those Dementors! That&amp;rsquo;s very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; advanced magic &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew I could do it this time,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, &amp;ldquo;because I&amp;rsquo;d already
done it &amp;hellip; Does that make sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything Harry and Hermione do in Chapter 21 has already occurred
when Hermione spun the Time-Turner three times.  They don&amp;rsquo;t change
the past; everything they have to do, they have already done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why don&amp;rsquo;t they change the past &lt;em&gt;anyway?&lt;/em&gt; Harry wants to; he tries
to convince Hermione to capture Pettigrew while Pettigrew&amp;mdash;in the
form of Scabbers&amp;mdash;is still in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with Harry and
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s past selves.  But Hermione won&amp;rsquo;t let him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hermione,&amp;rdquo; said Harry suddenly, &amp;ldquo;what if we&amp;mdash;we just run in there,
and grab Pettigrew&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo; said Hermione in a terrified whisper. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you understand?
We&amp;rsquo;re breaking one of the most important wizarding laws!  Nobody&amp;rsquo;s
supposed to change time, nobody! You heard Dumbledore, if we&amp;rsquo;re
seen&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;d only be seen by ourselves and Hagrid!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, what do you think you&amp;rsquo;d do if you saw yourself bursting into
Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s house?&amp;rdquo; said Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d gone mad,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, &amp;ldquo;or I&amp;rsquo;d think there was
some Dark Magic going on&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Exactly!&lt;/em&gt; You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand, you might even attack yourself!
Don&amp;rsquo;t you see? Professor McGonagall told me what awful things have
happened when wizards have meddled with time &amp;hellip; loads of them ended
up killing their past or future selves by mistake!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Hermione gives as to why they don&amp;rsquo;t change the past is that
it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;dangerous.&lt;/em&gt;  She seems to believe this herself, because she
thinks she and Harry &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; changing the past, and breaking the law in
doing so.  As far as she and Harry know, Buckbeak &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; executed, and
they&amp;rsquo;re trying to change that.  Because Hermione thinks they are
changing the past, and because she thinks it&amp;rsquo;s very dangerous, she
panics whenever Harry tries to change things without thinking about
the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione tells Harry not to change this part of the past because it&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;em&gt;dangerous.&lt;/em&gt; She thinks the past shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be changed except in very
rare circumstances, but she thinks it is possible to change the past.
Indeed, she and Harry think they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; going to change the past when
they rescue Buckbeak.  They don&amp;rsquo;t know that he was never killed; they
thinks he &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; killed, and they&amp;rsquo;re trying to change that.  Hermione
believes that while they&amp;rsquo;re taking a big risk in rescuing Buckbeak, it
would be an even bigger risk to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she needn&amp;rsquo;t have worried.  Not only is changing the past not
dangerous, it&amp;rsquo;s simply &lt;em&gt;impossible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The past is fixed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it impossible to change the past?  Why is it impossible for
Harry to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers?  Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough
way of explaining why it&amp;rsquo;s impossible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry, standing outside and wondering if he should burst into
Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, can remember sitting inside with Scabbers.  He can
also remember &lt;em&gt;leaving&lt;/em&gt; Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with Scabbers, and he
remembers nobody bursting in and trying to grab Scabbers.  His
memory is correct&amp;mdash;what he remembers happening is what happens, so
it&amp;rsquo;s too late to try to change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explanation should strike you as odd; who cares if he remembers
nobody bursting into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin?  Of course nobody has &lt;em&gt;yet,&lt;/em&gt; but
the question is whether he, Harry, &lt;em&gt;will.&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s nothing in the past
that rules out Harry bursting into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, so why can&amp;rsquo;t he?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rough explanation &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; odd, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s actually more or
less right.  To see why, we need to take a detour and introduce some
new terms for talking about time: &amp;ldquo;external time&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;personal time.&amp;rdquo;
These terms were coined by David Lewis in his 1976 paper
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kieranhealy.org/files/misc/lewis-paradoxes.pdf&#34; title=&#34;PDF&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Paradoxes of Time Travel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;  Lewis proposes that we think about time travel as involving &amp;ldquo;a
discrepancy between time and time&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any traveler departs and then arrives at his destination; the time
elapsed from departure to arrival (positive, or perhaps zero) is the
duration of the journey.  But if he is a time traveler, the
separation in time between departure and arrival does not equal the
duration of his journey.  He departs; he travels for an hour, let us
say; then he arrives.  The time he reaches is not the time one hour
after his departure.  It is later, if he has traveled toward the
future; earlier, if he has traveled toward the past.  If he has
traveled far toward the past, it is earlier even than his
departure.  How can it be that the same two events, his departure
and his arrival, are separated by two unequal amounts of time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this puzzle requires distinguishing &amp;ldquo;external time&amp;rdquo; from
&amp;ldquo;personal time.&amp;rdquo;  External time is what is recorded by clock-towers
and atomic clocks; when Harry and Hermione go back in time, they are
going three hours backward in &lt;em&gt;external time.&lt;/em&gt; But they are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
going back in &lt;em&gt;personal time.&lt;/em&gt; Personal time is what is recorded by
Harry&amp;rsquo;s wristwatch.  If Harry checked his watch before and after
Hermione spins the Time-Turner, the hands would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have moved three
hours back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When David Lewis says that time travel involves a discrepancy between
&amp;ldquo;time and time,&amp;rdquo; he means that there is a discrepancy between external
time and personal time; the two come apart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The time traveler&amp;rsquo;s] journey takes an hour of his personal time,
let us say; his wristwatch reads an hour later at arrival than at
departure.  But the arrival is more than an hour after the departure
in external time, if he travels toward the future; or the arrival is
before the departure in external time (or less than an hour after),
if he travels toward the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of Harry and Hermione&amp;rsquo;s journey&amp;mdash;when they appear in the
Entrance Hall&amp;mdash;is a few seconds &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;, in &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; time, the
beginning of their journey&amp;mdash;when Hermione spins the Time-Turner in
the hospital wing.  But, remember, the end of their journey is three
hours &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; its beginning in &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another way of thinking about the difference between external
and personal time, if you&amp;rsquo;re still confused: External time is time in
the third person; personal time is time in the first person.  External
time is the same for everyone; if you could step back and observe the
universe like God, you would watch it progress in external time.
Personal time is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the same for everyone; your personal time
corresponds to your &lt;em&gt;development&lt;/em&gt; through time.  From Harry&amp;rsquo;s
perspective, he appears in the Entrance Hall a few seconds &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;
Hermione spins the Time-Turner.  He remembers being in the hospital
wing immediately prior, his watch has moved a few seconds forward, and
the physical age of his body is only a few seconds older.  (That last
bit is important: I can be confused about the progress of my own
personal time, like when I wake up and can&amp;rsquo;t remember how long I&amp;rsquo;ve
slept.  But my body has aged a certain number of hours, and I&amp;rsquo;ve moved
&lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; many hours ahead in personal time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the life of a person, and their progress
through history, we use personal time.  Harry fainted at the edge of
the lake, surrounded by Dementors, then woke up in the hospital wing,
&lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; went back in time, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; cast the Patronus to save himself.
Those events all occurred, and they occurred &lt;em&gt;in that order&lt;/em&gt; for
Harry.  And most importantly, this is a &lt;em&gt;perfectly accurate&lt;/em&gt; way of
describing the events at the end of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban.&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s no
less accurate than a description of those events in external time.
(An external-time description would be: Harry cast the Patronus to
save himself, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; fainted at the edge of the lake, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; woke up
in the hospital wing, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; went back in time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think of external time as &lt;em&gt;objective&lt;/em&gt; and personal time
as &lt;em&gt;subjective,&lt;/em&gt; external time as &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt; and personal time as
&lt;em&gt;secondary;&lt;/em&gt; but both are equally legitimate.  Personal time isn&amp;rsquo;t
just our &lt;em&gt;opinion&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;feeling&lt;/em&gt; about the passage of time.  Like I
said earlier, we can be unsure about how far we&amp;rsquo;ve proceeded in
personal time: if we are unconscious, we lose the ability to detect
the passage of time.  But there are other, largely objective, ways to
measure how far we move forward in personal time.  When you wake up,
even if &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think you&amp;rsquo;ve only been asleep for a few minutes, your
watch might say otherwise, and your body will have aged as many hours
as you&amp;rsquo;ve been asleep.  You&amp;rsquo;ve progressed a certain determinate number
of hours in personal time.  And &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; fact&amp;mdash;that you&amp;rsquo;ve moved
forward a number of hours in personal time&amp;mdash;is just as &lt;em&gt;objectively
true&lt;/em&gt; as the fact that you&amp;rsquo;ve moved forward (or backward, if you&amp;rsquo;re
time traveling) a number of hours in external time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Harry and Hermione go back in time, the &lt;em&gt;fact&lt;/em&gt; that only a few
seconds of personal time has elapsed for each of them is just as
objectively true as is the fact that they&amp;rsquo;ve moved backward three
hours in external time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our original, rough explanation of why it&amp;rsquo;s
impossible to change the past: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, standing outside and wondering
if he should burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, can remember sitting inside
with Scabbers.  He can also remember&lt;/em&gt; leaving &lt;em&gt;Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with
Scabbers, and he remembers nobody bursting in and trying to grab
Scabbers.  His memory is correct&amp;mdash;what he remembers happening is what
happens, so it&amp;rsquo;s too late to try to change it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My appeal to what Harry remembers was a rough way of trying to
describe his journey in terms of &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; time.  Let&amp;rsquo;s write out
this series of events explicitly in terms of personal time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Hermione find Scabbers in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin; then left the
cabin with Ron, Hermione and Scabbers; then saw Scabbers escape and
get dragged (with Ron) into the Whomping Willow; then went into the
Shrieking Shack and out again; then fainted at the lake&amp;rsquo;s edge; then
woke up in the hospital wing; then went back in time; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt;
suggested to Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab
the rat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, these events all occur, and they occur &lt;em&gt;in this order&lt;/em&gt; for
Harry and Hermione.  It&amp;rsquo;s because they occur in this order that when
Harry suggests to Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, it&amp;rsquo;s
too late.  They &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; left the cabin with Scabbers, and nobody
burst in.  Harry &lt;em&gt;remembers&lt;/em&gt; this&amp;mdash;he remembers being in in the
cabin, and leaving the cabin, with nobody bursting in.  And he
remembers correctly!  That really happened, and it happened long
before Harry suggests he and Hermione burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, so
there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Is the future fixed as well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordering events in terms of personal time is no less accurate than
ordering them in terms of external time.  But when we think through
what this means, we&amp;rsquo;ll notice a surprising consequence: if time travel
is possible, then parts of the future are just as fixed as the past
is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think about Harry&amp;rsquo;s fight with the Dementors at the lake&amp;rsquo;s edge.
Harry, about to collapse, sees his Patronus running across the lake,
back to his future self.  Just because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize himself
doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s any less true that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; on the other side of
the lake.  By the time he faints, he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; cast the
Patronus&amp;mdash;in external time.  But since this has already happened in
external time, at some point in Harry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt;-time future he will
&lt;em&gt;have to&lt;/em&gt; be at that spot, and he will have to cast the Patronus
Charm.  His future actions must and &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; eventually lead him there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry, on the verge of collapse at the edge of the lake, has certain
things he is &lt;em&gt;determined&lt;/em&gt; to do in his personal future, because Harry,
standing on the the other side of the lake, is &lt;em&gt;doing those things&lt;/em&gt; at
the very same external time.  But all this shows is that there are
things that Harry has to do at &lt;em&gt;some point&lt;/em&gt; in his personal future.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t there some flexibility about when he gets around to doing them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no.  We&amp;rsquo;ve agreed that when Harry finally faints at the
edge of the lake, he&amp;rsquo;s already (in terms of external time) cast the
Patronus.  That means that he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; already done all the individual
actions that brought him to the spot where he cast the Patronus.  He&amp;rsquo;s
already hid in the forest, watching Snape pick up his Invisibility
Cloak; he&amp;rsquo;s already rescued Buckbeak; he&amp;rsquo;s already suggested to
Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin; and he&amp;rsquo;s already
appeared in the Entrance Hall after traveling back in time with
Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can illustrate Harry&amp;rsquo;s journey through the last chapters of
&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;no-border&#34; src=&#34;/img/time-split.png&#34; title=&#34;External time is a horizontal teal line; personal time is a red line curving back to represent backward time travel; the period of time between the beginning of the backward journey in time and its end is fixed.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; represent moments in external
 time.  &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; represent moments in
 personal time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is walking with Ron and Hermione to
visit Hagrid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is sitting in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with
Ron and Hermione and Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry faints after being saved by the stag
Patronus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry watches Hermione spin the Time-Turner
three times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is traveling back in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry appears in the Entrance Hall with
Hermione.  (Only a few seconds separate &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is suggesting to Hermione that
they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry casts his Patronus for the first time,
driving away the Dementors from across the lake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry runs with Hermione to the door of the
hospital wing after helping Sirius escape on Buckbeak:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to lock you in,&amp;rdquo; they heard [Dumbledore] saying. &amp;ldquo;It
is five minutes to midnight. Miss Granger, three turns should do
it. Good luck.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumbledore backed out of the room, closed the door and took out
his wand to magically lock it. Panicking, Harry and Hermione ran
forwards. Dumbledore looked up, and a wide smile appeared under
the long silver moustache. &amp;ldquo;Well?&amp;rdquo; he said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We did it!&amp;rdquo; said Harry breathlessly. &amp;ldquo;Sirius has gone, on
Buckbeak &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumbledore beamed at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well done. I think&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo; he listened intently for any sound within
the hospital wing. &amp;ldquo;Yes, I think you&amp;rsquo;ve gone, too&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 22).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at things exclusively from the perspective of external time,
you&amp;rsquo;ll see that &lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is simultaneous with &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a hard time seeing why it&amp;rsquo;s too late
for Harry to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers.  But what
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to show is that the perspective of external time is &lt;em&gt;just a
perspective,&lt;/em&gt; and that it&amp;rsquo;s not the only way to look at time.  When
you look at things from the perspective of Harry&amp;rsquo;s personal time,
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; simultaneous.  When Harry
is standing outside Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin at &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
is long past, and so is his opportunity to seize Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By appreciating both the external and personal perspectives on time,
we can see more clearly how parts of Harry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt; are fixed, as
well as his past. At &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; Harry is collapsing at the edge
of the lake, but he sees his future self, standing on the other side
of the lake &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; He&amp;rsquo;s able to see into his personal future
because &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;em&gt;externally&lt;/em&gt;
simultaneous. But the fact that he can see his future means that it&amp;rsquo;s
predetermined. If his future self had walked around the lake and
revived him using &lt;em&gt;Rennervate,&lt;/em&gt; Harry could have told himself, in
perfect detail, everything that he would do in his next three
hours. And there would be nothing Harry &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; do but walk that path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all a bit mind-bending, but the upshot is that when Harry goes
back in time three hours, everything that happens during those three
hours is fixed.  Harry already (in personal time) &lt;em&gt;lived&lt;/em&gt; those three
hours, and he can&amp;rsquo;t change that.  He can go back and &lt;em&gt;relive&lt;/em&gt; those
three hours&amp;mdash;which he does&amp;mdash;but he can&amp;rsquo;t undo what he did the first
time around.  Once you&amp;rsquo;ve lived through a period of time, it&amp;rsquo;s fixed;
going back in time doesn&amp;rsquo;t change that.  And it&amp;rsquo;s fixed for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of
us, not just the time-travelers: since Harry&amp;rsquo;s future includes his
casting the Patronus Charm from across the lake, nobody else can
&lt;em&gt;possibly&lt;/em&gt; do anything that would prevent him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem alarming and implausible, but think about it: how
could Professor Trelawney make &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; correct predictions otherwise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Postscript: Pottermore? How about Potter&lt;em&gt;less!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.com&#34;&gt;Pottermore&lt;/a&gt; entry for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.wikia.com/wiki/Time-Turner&#34; title=&#34;Pottermore Wikia&#34;&gt;Time-Turners&lt;/a&gt; includes this alarming statement from Department
of Mysteries employee Saul Croaker:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All attempts to travel back further than a few hours have resulted
in catastrophic harm to the witch or wizard involved. It was not
realised for many years why time travellers over great distances
never survived their journeys. All such experiments have been
abandoned since 1899, when Eloise Mintumble became trapped, for a
period of five days, in the year 1402. Now we understand that her
body had aged five centuries in its return to the present and,
irreparably damaged, she died in St Mungo&amp;rsquo;s Hospital for Magical
Maladies and Injuries shortly after we managed to retrieve her. What
is more, her five days in the distant past caused great disturbance
to the life paths of all those she met, changing the course of their
lives so dramatically that no fewer than twenty-five of their
descendants vanished in the present, having been &amp;ldquo;un-born.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen, this is impossible.  The notion of time-travel that
exists in the popular imagination and in films like &lt;em&gt;Back to the
Future,&lt;/em&gt; where Marty McFly sees his childhood photos begin to fade
when he threatens to prevent his parents from meeting, are
nonsensical.  We must therefore conclude that the above statement from
Professor Croaker is in error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>