<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Maps on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/maps/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-04-07 23:00:00 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philosopher&#8217;s Stoned: an Opinionated Introduction to Proper Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/names</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 23:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/names</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Snape was wrong when he suggested that the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is &amp;ldquo;plainly
full of Dark Magic,&amp;rdquo; but it is a remarkably powerful artifact and it&amp;rsquo;s
not at all obvious how it works.  How does it know your name, in order
to label your dot as it tracks you throughout the castle?  In order to
answer that question, we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to start from the beginning,
and figure out what a &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt; even is, and how &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; works.  &lt;em&gt;Sonorous!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map and how does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a map showing every detail of the Hogwarts castle and
 grounds. But the truly remarkable thing was the tiny ink dots
 moving around it, each labelled with a name in minuscule
 writing. Astounded, Harry bent over it. A labelled dot in the top
 left corner showed that Professor Dumbledore was pacing his study;
 the caretaker&amp;rsquo;s cat, Mrs Norris, was prowling the second floor, and
 Peeves the poltergeist was currently bouncing around the trophy
 room (&lt;em&gt;PoA,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea here is pretty straightforward: the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a map
of Hogwarts that also reveals the location of everyone inside the
castle&amp;mdash;or at least, the locations of people and certain cats.  It
reveals your location by placing a dot on the section of the map that
corresponds to where you are in the castle, and by labeling that dot
with your name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the books, the Map has no problem figuring out everyone&amp;rsquo;s name and
labeling them correctly.  But how does it do that?  How does it know
our names?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to answer that question, we first need to settle a more basic
question about the relationship between words and the world.  This
question might seem silly, but there is actually a great deal of
controversy over the correct answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the relationship between someone&amp;mdash;like Harry Potter&amp;mdash;and
their name&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;?  (Or their &lt;em&gt;names,&lt;/em&gt; if, like Alastor
Moody, they sometimes go by a different name.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we should start by making an assumption that&amp;rsquo;s common among
philosophers of language, which is that names &lt;em&gt;designate.&lt;/em&gt; In other
words, names (at least most of them) stand in a particular relation to
things in the world.  It&amp;rsquo;s because of this designation relation that
names &lt;em&gt;hook onto the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like an obvious assumption, but not everyone agrees.
Before moving on, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss an objection to this assumption, and
why we&amp;rsquo;re going to stick with it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Some people don&amp;rsquo;t think names designate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some philosophers, influenced by Ludwig Wittgenstein, have argued that
the answer we gave above, and the evocative metaphor of words hooking
onto the world, is altogether misguided.  The objection is that
instead of thinking of words as &lt;em&gt;labels&lt;/em&gt; that stick to various
objects, we should think of words, including names, as &lt;em&gt;tools&lt;/em&gt; that we
&lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; to do things.  On page 78 of his &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language: A
Contemporary Introduction&lt;/em&gt; (Second Edition), William Lycan suggests
that this is what Wittgenstein himself was getting at in his later
work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein [offered] a further analogy
[in &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;]: A builder and his assistant
have just four kinds of building stones that they use. They speak a
little primitive language that has just four corresponding words in
it: &amp;ldquo;block,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;pillar,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;slab,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;beam.&amp;rdquo; They build things,
engaging in their nonlinguistic activities aided by a certain
primitive sort of linguistic activity: the builder says &amp;ldquo;slab,&amp;rdquo; and
the assistant brings a stone of the appropriate shape. Now, someone
might say, &amp;ldquo;Of course, that word &amp;lsquo;slab&amp;rsquo; bears the [designation]
relation to a block of this shape, and its meaning is the
proposition that the assistant is to bring such a block to the
builder.&amp;rdquo; But according to Wittgenstein this would be missing the
point. In this little primitive language-game, the word &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo; does
have a function that is obviously connected with blocks of that
shape, but the point is the function and not the [designation]
relation. The point of the builder&amp;rsquo;s making the noise &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo; is just
to get the assistant to do something, to trigger conventionally (the
assistant having learned his trade) a pattern of useful
activity. The activity does involve things of this shape, but the
primary point is to initiate action, not to [designate].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea here, roughly, is that names, and words in general, are less
like &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; and more like &lt;em&gt;hammers.&lt;/em&gt; Instead of asking what a name is
&lt;em&gt;attached to,&lt;/em&gt; we should ask what a name is &lt;em&gt;used for.&lt;/em&gt; In
Wittgenstein&amp;rsquo;s example, the words &amp;ldquo;block,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;pillar,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;slab,&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;beam&amp;rdquo; are used to make the assistant retrieve certain building
materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to this sort of theory, words in general work a lot like
spell-words do.  Here&amp;rsquo;s an example from &lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets,&lt;/em&gt; right
after Gilderoy Lockhart admits that he didn&amp;rsquo;t do any of the brave
things he claimed to do in his books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pulled out his wand and turned to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awfully sorry, boys, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put a Memory Charm on you
now. Can&amp;rsquo;t have you blabbing my secrets all over the place.  I&amp;rsquo;d
never sell another book &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry reached his wand just in time. Lockhart had barely raised his,
when Harry bellowed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;CoS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make much sense to ask what &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo;
designated there.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t designate &lt;em&gt;anything.&lt;/em&gt;  It was &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; by
Harry to disarm Lockhart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Problems with the words-as-tools theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As appealing as this words-as-tools theory is, it&amp;rsquo;s got some real
problems. Here&amp;rsquo;s one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look again at how we talked about the &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; case: we said
that &amp;ldquo;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make much sense to ask what &amp;lsquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rsquo;
designated &lt;em&gt;there.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  It &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; seem to make much sense to ask what
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designated &lt;em&gt;in that context,&lt;/em&gt; but it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make sense
to ask what &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;in general.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo;
is the name of a spell.  When we use the word &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus,&amp;rdquo; we&amp;rsquo;re
not always using it to cast a spell.  Sometimes we just want to talk
about the spell, like Harry and Zacharias Smith do during the first
meeting of Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s Army:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Right,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, [&amp;hellip;] &amp;ldquo;shall we get practising then? I was
thinking, the first thing we should do is Expelliarmus, you know,
the Disarming Charm. I know it&amp;rsquo;s pretty basic but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it
really useful&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, please,&amp;rdquo; said Zacharias Smith, rolling his eyes and folding his
arms. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think Expelliarmus is exactly going to help us
against You-Know-Who, do you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve used it against him,&amp;rdquo; said Harry quietly. &amp;ldquo;It saved my life in
June&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the right conclusion to draw here is that, while
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus,&lt;/em&gt; we don&amp;rsquo;t always &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; to talk about &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus.&lt;/em&gt;  Sometimes, as we&amp;rsquo;ve
seen, we use it to cast the spell.  Just because a word designates a
certain thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we can&amp;rsquo;t use it to do things other
than talk about what it designates.  Malfoy does just this in
&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, look who it is,&amp;rdquo; said Malfoy in his usual lazy drawl, pulling
open the compartment door. &amp;ldquo;Potty and the Weasel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; designates, but it&amp;rsquo;s not Harry.  And &amp;ldquo;the
Weasel&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t designate Ron&amp;mdash;many philosophers of language think
that the determiner &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; means that &amp;ldquo;the Weasel&amp;rdquo; can only designate
the &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt; Weasel, and so doesn&amp;rsquo;t designate anything in a world with
many weasels, such the world of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter.&lt;/em&gt; But Malfoy is
nonetheless using &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; to talk about Harry and using &amp;ldquo;the Weasel&amp;rdquo;
to talk about Ron.  Let&amp;rsquo;s introduce another bit of technical language
and say that while &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; does not &lt;em&gt;designate&lt;/em&gt; Harry, Malfoy is using
it, in this context, to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context is important for &lt;em&gt;referring,&lt;/em&gt; but not for &lt;em&gt;designating.&lt;/em&gt;  If
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter, it does so all the time, and
whether or not anyone is using the name.  But Malfoy has to be in the
right sort of situation in order to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry using &amp;ldquo;Potty.&amp;rdquo;
Basically, he has to be in a situation where the people he&amp;rsquo;s talking
to realize he&amp;rsquo;s using &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; as if it was a name for Harry.  This is
how Kent Bach describes it on page 518 of &amp;ldquo;What Does it Take to
Refer?&amp;rdquo; in the &lt;em&gt;Oxford Handbook of Philosophy of Language:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker reference is a four-place relation between a speaker, an
expression, an audience, and a referent: you use an expression to
refer someone to something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between designation and reference will be important
later on, but the point of bringing it up now is to show that while
the words-as-tools theory is &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; to say that we use words for
different purposes in different contexts, that &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; mean we
should think that words never designate anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other objections to the words-as-tools theory.  One is that
while it might be true for some words and maybe even some phrases,
it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;generally&lt;/em&gt; true; some words and phrases might be tools, but
some aren&amp;rsquo;t.  We&amp;rsquo;re interested in names right now, and names seem the
&lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; like tools; they really do seem more like labels or tags.
Another objection to word-as-tools is that even if I understand the
conventional ways to use English words, that&amp;rsquo;s not all there is to
&lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; English.  This is one of William Lycan&amp;rsquo;s objections,
from page 81 of &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I not know the use of an expression, and fall in with it,
mechanically, without understanding it? I have known undergraduates
who are geniuses at picking up academic jargon of one sort or
another and slinging it around with great facility, but without
understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A similar example is in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire,&lt;/em&gt; when Harry and Ron simply
make up predictions about what will happen to them in the coming
month, but aren&amp;rsquo;t caught by Professor Trelawny because what they write
sounds like what she expects to hear.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could program a computer (or enchant a hat) to reply to English
sentences with other English sentences; it might be well-designed
enough to give replies that a fluent English speaker would give.  But
if the computer&amp;rsquo;s replies were chosen by making statistical
generalizations from a database of recorded conversations, we would
probably say that the computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; English.
It can use English words, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what they &lt;em&gt;mean.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more that could be said on both sides, but let&amp;rsquo;s put away the
words-as-tools theory, and accept for the time being that names really
do designate things.  Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;em&gt;meaning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;The meaning of names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve just talked about whether or not names designate things.
But at least for most words, you&amp;rsquo;re probably more familiar with the
question, &amp;ldquo;what does this word &lt;em&gt;mean?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  We&amp;rsquo;re going to stay focused
just on names, so our question is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;what do names mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have no problem explaining what most words mean, so it may seem odd
that the meaning of names is such a big problem.  For example, the
meaning of &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;person without magical power but with at least
one parent who is a witch or wizard.&amp;rdquo;  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;thestral&amp;rdquo; is
something like &amp;ldquo;winged horse visible only to those who have seen and
understood death.&amp;rdquo;  But it&amp;rsquo;s not nearly as obvious what the meaning of
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to look at three different theories of names, which each
provide a different answer to the question, &amp;ldquo;what is the meaning of
&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;  The first theory is &lt;strong&gt;Descriptivism,&lt;/strong&gt; the second is
&lt;strong&gt;Millianism,&lt;/strong&gt; and the third is &lt;strong&gt;Nominal Descriptivism.&lt;/strong&gt; I think
Nominal Descriptivism is the correct theory, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why, but
there are many philosophers who disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Descriptivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As its name suggests, Descriptivism claims that the meaning of a name
&lt;em&gt;describes&lt;/em&gt; the person or object designated by that name.  According
to this theory, names such as &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; are a lot like general
terms like &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;thestral.&amp;rdquo;  The meanings of those words also
describe the things they designate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t be just any description that
describes Harry Potter.  For example, the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
can&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived.&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s true that &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo; is
commonly used to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry Potter, and has become associated in
the popular imagination with Harry Potter, but &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo;
doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;uniquely&lt;/em&gt; describe Harry.  Strictly speaking, any living boy
is a boy who lived; Harry is not actually unique in that respect.  And
as I mentioned above, &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; implies uniqueness.  There are many maps,
but only one Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map, so it is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.  If there
were multiple Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Maps, then it would not be correct to use
&amp;ldquo;the.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ldquo;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map&amp;rdquo; only designates the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map while
it is the unique&amp;mdash;the only&amp;mdash;Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo; does not designate Harry, even
though it is very often used to refer to him.  So if Descriptivism is
true, then the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is something other than &amp;ldquo;the
boy who lived.&amp;rdquo;  It will be something that does uniquely describe
Harry, something like &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31
July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; describes nobody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Descriptivism, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is really nothing more than
an &lt;em&gt;abbreviation&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31
July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.&amp;rdquo;  The only difference between the following two
sentences is their length:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981,
lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet
Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Descriptivism is correct, then we use &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; instead of
&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived
a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo; essentially
because it&amp;rsquo;s more convenient; but the meaning is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;How would the Map work in a Descriptivist world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose that Descriptivism is correct.  What would that tell us
about how the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map works?  We&amp;rsquo;re not worried about how it
determines that &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; person is in, for example, the Gryffindor
common room; presumably that&amp;rsquo;s taken care of by the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.wikia.com/wiki/Marauder%27s_Map&#34; title=&#34;entry for the Marauder&#39;s Map on the Pottermore wiki&#34;&gt;Homonculous Charm&lt;/a&gt;.  What we want
to know is how the Map goes further, and determines &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; that person
is.  Without asking anyone, how does it figure out your name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make some assumptions about Hogwarts in order to make this
easier.  We&amp;rsquo;ll suppose that the Map already has access to the names of
everyone who is in the castle.  If the Map didn&amp;rsquo;t have the names, then
it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how the Map could match up people with their names.
It would have to be able to deduce a person&amp;rsquo;s name just from &amp;ldquo;looking&amp;rdquo;
at them; and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why should we be allowed to assume that the Map already has access
to the names of everyone in the castle?  I think we&amp;rsquo;re allowed to, for
the following reason: Hogwarts is protected from intruders by a number
of enchantments.  One of these enchantments might well be an
enchantment that prevents unauthorized people from entering the
castle.  At the beginning of the year, the Headmaster or Headmistress
teaches Hogwarts the names of the new students, so that they may
enter.  Individuals who never attended the school but are either
permanent or temporary residents&amp;mdash;Peeves, Filch, Mrs. Norris, the
visitors from Beauxbatons and Durmstrang&amp;mdash;are added on a case-by-case
basis.  Hogwarts determines who is designated by each name, and allows
them entry.  The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map simply piggy-backs off this system of
enchantments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: Hogwarts learns the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; and therefore the
Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map does too.  How does the Map then take that name and
figure out who it designates?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Descriptivism is true, then what the Map learns when it learns the
name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;the
wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.&amp;rdquo;  So in order
to label Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;s dot on the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map, the Map just needs
to discover which of the people within Hogwarts is the wizard born to
James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse
cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.  Whoever in fact fits that
description is Harry Potter, according to this theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the Map actually goes about this investigation is something
J.K. Rowling might have to tell us.  How the Map can reach back into
the past and figure out with complete certainty which of these people
&lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; in the castle was &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; the wizard who survived a Killing Curse
is a complicated question.  It&amp;rsquo;s also a question that we&amp;rsquo;re not going
to try to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know now &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the Map needs to do in order to label its dots, if
Descriptivism is true.  &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; it does that is a question for another
day; and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not even worth trying to answer this second
question, because Descriptivism is probably not the correct theory
anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Problems with Descriptivism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism is intuitive and straightforward, but it has some big
problems.  Here are three:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to understand the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
have to know anything about Voldemort, or even that there is
anyone named &amp;ldquo;Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;  But Descriptivism insists that, since
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is &lt;em&gt;synonymous&lt;/em&gt; with &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and
Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981,&amp;rdquo; understanding the meaning of
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; involves being aware of the (former) existence of
not only Voldemort, but James and Lily as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; just means &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily
Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, than anyone who understands the
name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;just on the basis of
understanding the name!&amp;mdash;that Harry Potter survived a Killing
Curse cast by Voldemort.  But surely this is not true; someone can
understand the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know that he survived
a Killing Curse, or even that his parents were named &amp;ldquo;James&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;Lily.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems perfectly true to say &amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry
Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;
If Lily hadn&amp;rsquo;t died trying to save him, her love wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have
protected him from Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s curse, and he would also have died.
But if Descriptivism is true, then the following are equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that the wizard born to James and Lily Potter
on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981 did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while the first is true, the second seems false.  How could it
be that the wizard, whoever it is, who survived a Killing Curse
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have survived that Killing Curse?  We seem to be
contradicting ourselves.  But we are definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
contradicting ourselves by saying that Harry Potter might not have
survived that Killing Curse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I think that Descriptivism cannot be the correct
theory of names.  So we should move on to examine Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Millianism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three problems for Descriptivism that I listed above were
originally presented by Saul Kripke in a series of lectures at
Princeton in 1972.  Descriptivism was much more widely accepted then
than it is now, and it was Kripke&amp;rsquo;s lectures that caused philosophers
to abandon Descriptivism and look for a better theory of names.  Many
settled on Millianism, which is called that because it was inspired by
the philosophy of John Stuart Mill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Millianism, the meaning of a name &lt;em&gt;just is&lt;/em&gt; the
designation of the name.  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is nothing
more than the person designated by that name&amp;mdash;Harry Potter, the
wizard himself.  Compare this with Descriptivism: according to that
theory, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter because the meaning of
the name&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980,
who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in
1981&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;uniquely describes Harry Potter.  According to Millianism,
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter because the meaning of the name
just &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Harry Potter.  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t something
that describes or &lt;em&gt;picks out&lt;/em&gt; that wizard; the meaning &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that
wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theory does not face the three problems that face Descriptivism:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understand the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; does not require knowing
anything about Voldemort, if Millianism is true.  Understanding
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; just requires knowing who it designates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and
Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, according to Millianism,
understanding the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; not &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; involve knowing
that Harry Potter survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Millianism is true, then the following are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that the wizard born to James and Lily Potter
on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981 did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there is nothing strange about denying the second while
agreeing with the first, if Millianism is correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while Millianism avoids the problems that plagued Descriptivism,
it faces its own set of challenges, as we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  But first let&amp;rsquo;s
look at how the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map would function &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; Millianism were
true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;How would the Map work in a Millian world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Millianism is true, what the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map has to do in order to
label its dots is actually very little.  Since the meaning of a name,
according to Millianism, just is the thing designated by that name,
when the Map learns the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; what it learns is &lt;em&gt;who
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So just learning &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; gives the Map everything it needs to
pinpoint and label Harry Potter.  Descriptivism gave the Map only a
description of Harry Potter; Millianism gives the Map Harry Potter
himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, because we don&amp;rsquo;t have to ask Rowling how the Map can
investigate who fits the descriptions associated with names.  But
unfortunately, Millianism has serious problems that make it a less
attractive theory than you might think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;Problems with Millianism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people have multiple names.  Alastor Moody is more often
known as &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody.&amp;rdquo;  If, like Millianism says, the meaning
of &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; and the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; are both
just the ex-Auror, then they should be completely
&lt;em&gt;interchangeable.&lt;/em&gt; If you understand one, you understand the
other.  The problem is that we often don&amp;rsquo;t realize that two names
designate the same person:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are those who&amp;rsquo;ll turn innocent occasions to their
advantage,&amp;rdquo; Moody retorted in a menacing voice. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my job to
think the way Dark wizards do, Karkaroff&amp;mdash;as you ought to
remember &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alastor!&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore warningly.  Harry wondered for a
moment whom he was speaking to, but then realised &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye&amp;rdquo;
could hardly be Moody&amp;rsquo;s real first name (&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Millianism was true, then &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody is Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo;
is &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt; true, because the two names are synonyms.  If
Millianism was true, then nobody would &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; disagree with
&amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody is the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher at
Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; while agreeing with &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody is the Defense
Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts.&amp;rdquo;  But before Harry&amp;rsquo;s
name came out of the Goblet of Fire, he would have done just that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is just Harry Potter, then if Harry
Potter &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist,&lt;/em&gt; the name is meaningless!  If the only
meaning it has is the person it designates, then if there is no
person there is no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Harry Potter is alive, while he &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; exist, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter
doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo; is a perfectly meaningful sentence&amp;mdash;except that
it&amp;rsquo;s false.  But when Harry ceases to exist, there is no longer
anything for &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; to designate, so &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter doesn&amp;rsquo;t
exist&amp;rdquo; is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; meaningful, because &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; has quite
literally lost its meaning.  Just when we would want to say that
Harry Potter doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, it seems that we no longer can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These objections are convincing enough for me to think that Millianism
cannot be the correct theory of names either.  Fortunately we have one
more candidate that is better than either Descriptivism or Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_10&#34;&gt;Nominal Descriptivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory of Nominal Descriptivism was given that name by Kent Bach.
The name makes perfect sense, because this is what the theory says:
the meaning of any name &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;N&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is &amp;ldquo;the thing designated by &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;N.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;
(Since we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about names of people, from now on we&amp;rsquo;ll say
&amp;ldquo;the &lt;em&gt;person&lt;/em&gt; designated by &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;N.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, Nominal Descriptivism says that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;  According to
this theory, the following differ only in length:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The person designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; lives in the cupboard under
the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet
Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simple theory avoids the problems that plagued &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; (regular)
Descriptivism and Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_11&#34;&gt;How Nominal Descriptivism avoids the Descriptivist problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism required too much.  It said that understanding
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; requires knowing not only specific details about
Harry&amp;rsquo;s history but also that there&amp;rsquo;s someone named &amp;ldquo;Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;
According to Nominal Descriptivism, to understand what &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo; means, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to know any specific details about
Harry Potter or Voldemort or anyone else&amp;mdash;all I have to know is
that it designates whoever it designates!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism had the bizarre consequence that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;true by
definition&lt;/em&gt; that Harry Potter survived a Killing Curse.  This
meant that anyone who understands the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby
knows that Harry survived a Killing Curse, just like anyone who
understands the word &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; knows that squibs don&amp;rsquo;t have magical
power.  All &lt;em&gt;Nominal Descriptivism&lt;/em&gt; says is that anyone who
understands &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby knows that Harry Potter is
designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  That&amp;rsquo;s not a bizarre consequence at
all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism was forced to deny that Harry Potter might not have
survived that Killing Curse cast by Voldemort, because part of the
&lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; was &amp;ldquo;the wizard who survived a Killing
Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;  As it turns out, Nominal Descriptivism
denies this too, but for a very different reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nominal Descriptivism says that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is
&amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;  That is a &lt;em&gt;definite&lt;/em&gt;
description, and we saw above that definite descriptions&amp;mdash;like
&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in
1981&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;are supposed to &lt;em&gt;uniquely&lt;/em&gt; designate someone.  This means
that the sentence &amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; lives
in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey&amp;rdquo; is only true, strictly speaking, if there is
only &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; person designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  If there is more
than one person in the world named &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; then it&amp;rsquo;s
technically false that the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;
lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey.  And if Nominal Descriptivism is true, then it&amp;rsquo;s
likewise &lt;em&gt;false&lt;/em&gt; that Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the
stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, pretty much everything said using the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
will be literally false if there is more than one person named
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  But this is not as bad as it seems.  A lot of
what we say is literally false, even though we don&amp;rsquo;t realize it:
suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a party in Gryffindor Tower and Fred says &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s
no butterbeer&amp;rdquo;.  He&amp;rsquo;s actually saying something false because he&amp;rsquo;s
denying that there is butterbeer, &lt;em&gt;period.&lt;/em&gt; And surely there&amp;rsquo;s
butterbeer &lt;em&gt;somewhere;&lt;/em&gt; in the Hogwarts kitchens, in the Three
Broomsticks, and so on.  But &lt;em&gt;what Fred meant&lt;/em&gt; is that there&amp;rsquo;s no
butterbeer in Gryffindor Tower.  For the same reason, if Harry
says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, he&amp;rsquo;s technically uttering a falsehood,
but as long as the people he&amp;rsquo;s talking to understand that he&amp;rsquo;s
referring them to himself (remember that reference is a four-place
relation between a speaker, audience, name and object), his
meaning is understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter might not have survived that
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort&amp;rdquo; is literally false, because there
are almost certainly multiple people named &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  But
depending on who the speaker intends to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to when they say
that Harry Potter might not have survived that Killing Curse cast
by Voldemort, what they &lt;em&gt;meant&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;rdquo;&lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; might not have survived&amp;rdquo;)
may be true or false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you still think that this is a big problem for Nominal
Descriptivism, keep in mind that we never discussed how
Descriptivism and Millianism deal with multiple people sharing a
name.  If there is another Harry Potter&amp;mdash;a Muggle, say&amp;mdash;then
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t just mean &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; or just
Harry Potter the wizard, because what about the other Harry
Potter(s)?  These theories would have to be tweaked to cope with
this complication, and these tweaks may end up being just as
unintuitive.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_12&#34;&gt;How Nominal Descriptivism avoids the Millian problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A big problem for Millianism was that it gave us the strange result
that there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no difference between names that designate
the same person&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; should be
interchangeable everywhere.  But if Nominal Descriptivism is
correct, then &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;the person designated by
&amp;lsquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;the person designated
by &amp;lsquo;Alastor Moody.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;  Now the names are no longer synonymous, and
there is no mystery as to how Harry could fail to realize that
Mad-Eye Moody is Alastor Moody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millianism also seemed unable to make sense of statements like
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter does not exist.&amp;rdquo;  Nominal Descriptivism has no
problem with these &lt;em&gt;negative existentials:&lt;/em&gt; if Harry Potter means
&amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; then everything becomes
clear: we are just denying that anyone is designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_13&#34;&gt;How does the Map work in a Nominal Descriptivist world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will actually be more complicated.  Remember that in a (regular)
Descriptivist world, when the map learns &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; it learns
that Harry Potter is the wizard, whoever it is, who was born to James
and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, and who survived a Killing Curse cast
by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.  In a Millian world, the Map
simply learns who Harry Potter is.  But in our Nominal Descriptivist
world, all the Map can learn is that the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
designates whoever it in fact designates.  Not very helpful at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Nominal Descriptivist world, unlike the previous worlds we
examined, learning the meaning of a name does not give you enough
information to determine who is designated by that name.  So the Map
will have to look elsewhere for information about who&amp;rsquo;s designated by
what names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where will we look next?  We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to figure out a &lt;em&gt;semantic&lt;/em&gt;
fact: what individual(s) are designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  Previously
we were able to figure this out using another semantic fact&amp;mdash;the
meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  But now that semantic fact has failed us.
So we will have to look at &lt;em&gt;metasemantic&lt;/em&gt; facts: in particular, the
facts about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates the individuals it does.
How did it come to be that Harry Potter (&amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; Harry Potter, the
wizard, the hero of our stories) came to be designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo;?  How did he get his name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_14&#34;&gt;Semantic and metasemantic facts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned above that Saul Kripke argued against Descriptivism in a
series of lectures, later published as &lt;em&gt;Naming and Necessity.&lt;/em&gt; An
important feature of his arguments is that while he insists that the
meaning of a proper name like &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; cannot be some definite
description like &amp;ldquo;the wizard who was born to James and Lily Potter on
31 July 1980 and survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981,&amp;rdquo; he admits (on pages 57&amp;ndash;58) that a description
like that &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be used to &lt;em&gt;fix the designation&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems plausible to suppose that, in some cases, the [designation]
of a name is indeed fixed &lt;em&gt;via&lt;/em&gt; a description in the same way that
the metric system was fixed. When [someone] first saw
Hesperus, he may well have fixed [the designation] by saying, &amp;ldquo;I shall
use &amp;lsquo;Hesperus&amp;rsquo; as a name of the heavenly body appearing in yonder
position in the sky.&amp;rdquo; He then fixed the [designation] of &amp;ldquo;Hesperus&amp;rdquo; by
its apparent celestial position.  Does it then follow that it is a
part of the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of the name that Hesperus has such and such a
position at the time in question?  Surely not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that there are multiple ways to name something or someone.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine Lily Potter naming her baby.  There are at least two
different ways she could do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She could say &amp;ldquo;let &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; designate the wizard, whoever it
is, who was born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, and who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;
(of course, unless she is a Seer, she would not have used that exact
description).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She can point at the baby and say &amp;ldquo;let &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; child be named &amp;lsquo;Harry
Potter.&amp;lsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important point here is that when Lily says these things, she is
fixing the designation of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; but she is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; giving a
&lt;em&gt;definition&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;  We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen why &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
cannot be defined as meaning &amp;ldquo;the wizard who was born to James and
Lily Potter on 31 July 1980 and survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981,&amp;rdquo; or as meaning the person himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Lily fixed the designation of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; by, let&amp;rsquo;s
say, pointing and saying &amp;ldquo;that child shall be &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; is
therefore &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a semantic fact.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a fact that can be
expressed as &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; means such-and-such&amp;rdquo;, nor can it be
expressed as &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; designates the so-and-so.&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s a
&lt;em&gt;metasemantic&lt;/em&gt; fact that tells us &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; the semantic facts.  Knowing
this metasemantic fact, we can then use it to figure out the semantic
fact that &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates the baby that Lily Potter pointed
at when she said &amp;ldquo;that child shall be &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s this
semantic fact that the Map needs to know, in order to label Harry when
he arrives at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We face again the question of how the Map reaches back into the past.
How can it know for certain when and how a person was named, so that
it can learn what name they were given?  This is, again, a question
for another day.  We know what the Map needs to know.  I will not here
attempt to answer how it might know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_15&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bach, Kent. &amp;ldquo;Giorgione was so-called because of his name,&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Noûs&lt;/em&gt;
volume 36, pages 73&amp;ndash;103.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hinchliff, Mark. &amp;ldquo;Has the theory of reference rested on a mistake?&amp;rdquo;
in &lt;em&gt;Reference and Referring,&lt;/em&gt; edited by William Kabasenche, Michael
O&amp;rsquo;Rourke, and Matthew Slater, MIT Press, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kripke, Saul. &lt;em&gt;Naming and Necessity,&lt;/em&gt; Harvard University Press,
1980.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lycan, William. &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language: A Contemporary
Introduction,&lt;/em&gt; Routledge, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are ways to stop even a Hufflepuff from finding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 14:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so&amp;mdash;apparently&amp;mdash;incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not immediately obvious how this is possible.  Some of the
simpler and more obvious proposals as to how Unplottability might work
turn out to be no good.  Unplottability cannot not say anything about
what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of paper.  It&amp;rsquo;s possible with
magic to prevent the information from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted,&lt;/em&gt; but this
won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work is something more drastic: Unplottability has to
prevent us from &lt;em&gt;inferring&lt;/em&gt; the location of a place from other
information.  The benefit of this radical solution is that it
preserves the spirit of Unplottability, which is to prevent people
from figuring out &lt;em&gt;where Hogwarts is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of Unplottability is in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on&amp;mdash;how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists, but that&amp;rsquo;s beside the point.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got one
fact about Unplottability: it can apply to buildings and it makes it
impossible to plot them on a map.  But we learn in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;
that it applies to individual rooms as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter, sir,&amp;rdquo; squeaked Dobby, his great orblike eyes shining
in the firelight, &amp;ldquo;the Malfoy boy is breaking no rules that Dobby
can discover, but he is still keen to avoid detection. He has been
making regular visits to the seventh floor with a variety of other
students, who keep watch for him while he enters&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Room of Requirement!&amp;rdquo; said Harry, smacking himself hard on the
forehead with &lt;em&gt;Advanced Potion-Making&lt;/em&gt;. Hermione and Ron stared at
him. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s where he’s been sneaking off to!  That&amp;rsquo;s where he&amp;rsquo;s
doing … whatever he&amp;rsquo;s doing! And I bet that&amp;rsquo;s why he&amp;rsquo;s been
disappearing off the map&amp;mdash;come to think of it, I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen the
Room of Requirement on there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe the Marauders never knew the Room was there,&amp;rdquo; said Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;ll be part of the magic of the Room,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If
you need it to be Unplottable, it will be&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting aside whether the Room &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Unplottable or not, all the
evidence we&amp;rsquo;ve got so far is compatible with Unplottability being
nothing more than a restriction on what can be written down on a map.
But if the &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of Unplottability is to keep the location of a
place secret, this hardly seems sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s textual support in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; for
Unplottability being more than this sort of limited restriction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Number 12, Grimmauld Place is] ideal for Headquarters, of course,&amp;rdquo;
Sirius said. &amp;ldquo;My father put every security measure known to
wizardkind on it when he lived here. It&amp;rsquo;s unplottable, so Muggles
could never come and call&amp;mdash;as if they&amp;rsquo;d ever have wanted to&amp;mdash;and
now Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s added his protection, you&amp;rsquo;d be hard put to find a
safer house anywhere&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, Sirius can&amp;rsquo;t be right when he says that Muggles
could &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; come and call.  Durmstrang&amp;mdash;and, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume,
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;are Unplottable, but students have to be able to get there
somehow.  Likewise, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the fact that Number 12 is
&lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; protected by the Fidelius Charm, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how any sort of
&lt;em&gt;Unplottability&lt;/em&gt; could have prevented a Muggle from walking up to the
front door, unaided by any map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Unplottability can at least &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; prevent Muggles from
finding Number 12, then it&amp;rsquo;s clearly more than a restriction on what
can be drawn on a map.  But this leaves unexplained exactly what
Unplottability is and how it &lt;em&gt;works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Maybe I can draw you a map, but you can&amp;rsquo;t understand it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen that Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just be about what I can or can&amp;rsquo;t
draw on a piece of paper.  More precisely, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just prevent me
encoding certain information on a map.  It has to also keep people
from &lt;em&gt;getting&lt;/em&gt; to the place that&amp;rsquo;s Unplottable.  So the obvious idea
is that Unplottability somehow prevents us from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; a map to
locate Hogwarts (or any other Unplottable location).  How would that work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read a map, I assume that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot the
locations of certain places on their map.  I read the map with the
belief that it is written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  When I
find the location of a place on the map, I believe that I am
&lt;em&gt;recognizing the communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to
communicate to me the location of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do not believe that there is this sort of communicative
intention, I will probably not assume that I can use the map to find
the locations of places.  If I am a schoolteacher and I have my
students create maps of imaginary places, I will not pore over them
later to learn the locations of the places &amp;ldquo;plotted&amp;rdquo; on the maps.  I
know that they were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; drawn with that sort of communicative
intention, and so I would not&amp;mdash;mistakenly&amp;mdash;take them to be real maps
of real geographic areas.  I would not &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; anything from the maps
because I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is anything to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s a possible explanation for how Unplottability works: it
prevents us from recognizing the &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; behind maps
of Unplottable locations.  Even if a witch or wizard finds a map on
which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of Unplottability would
be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.
The reader would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are reading a map showing the
location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in a situation similar to
the schoolteacher looking over the students&amp;rsquo; maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the students were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but that&amp;rsquo;s no objection to the theory: &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an objection to this theory (which was
brought to my attention by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;I can still find Hogwarts if I can&amp;rsquo;t read your map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and
therefore&amp;mdash;because we used the Map to find the relative location of
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking that this loophole probably only affects
Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  So who cares, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just consist in preventing me from recognizing
a communicative intention.  It has to be something more, if it&amp;rsquo;s going
to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, and if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, therefore &amp;hellip; what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/docs/unplottable.html&#34;&gt;earlier version&lt;/a&gt; of this
essay concluded that Unplottability was impossible.  Jacob T. Levy,
Tomlinson Professor of Political Theory at McGill University, found
that pessimism unwarranted and proposed a solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s easy;just use an SEP field! Interfere with the intention to *either* draw a map or use a map (or 2 maps)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429670387501117441&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; This combines #2 and #3 w rule that if I try to put Marauder&amp;#39;s Map &amp;amp; Hogsmeade maps together I... ooh! shiny!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429671149165752320&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An S.E.P., or Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s Problem, field,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hitchhikers.wikia.com/wiki/Somebody_Else&#34; title=&#34;s_Problem_field
&amp;quot;Hitchhiker Wiki&#34;&gt;utilizes a person&amp;rsquo;s natural tendency to ignore things they don&amp;rsquo;t easily accept&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by causing them to simply &lt;em&gt;ignore&lt;/em&gt; certain
information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any object around which a S.E.P. [field] is applied will cease to be
noticed, because any problems one may have understanding it (and
therefore accepting its existence) become Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s. An object
becomes not so much invisible as unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect example of this would be a ship covered in a S.E.P. field at
a cricket match. A star ship taking the appearance of a large pink
elephant is ideal &amp;hellip; you can see it, but because it is so
inconceivable, your mind can&amp;rsquo;t accept it. Therefore it can&amp;rsquo;t exist,
thus [you ignore it].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proposal raises difficult and delicate questions in the
philosophy of mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to answer.  But it also
suggests an even simpler solution: whenever I try to infer &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; some
pieces of information &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts, the
Unplottability enchantment blocks that inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walk from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, measuring the distance, I may
end up with this bit of knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I walked 1km, northwest, from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be obvious at first, but just knowing that does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean
that one automatically knows this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hogwarts is 1km southeast of Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; (2) from (1), but I have to know some other things as
well.  Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;i&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walk a certain distance from point &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; to point &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is that far from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is a certain distance from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is the same distance from &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is northwest of &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is southeast of &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course all these things are &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;, so we don&amp;rsquo;t usually think
about how we rely on them for drawing equally obvious conclusions like
(2).  But we do rely on them, and we also rely on &lt;em&gt;inference rules&lt;/em&gt;
that allow us to move from our premises to our conclusion.  For
example, just to conclude that Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade, I have
to reason like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore&lt;/em&gt;, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore&amp;rdquo; marks the point at which I make an inference.  If I
somehow fail to see that there is a valid inference to be made, I may
be left with only the first two pieces of information, not knowing
whether Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I suggest, is exactly the situation I will be in, because the
Unplottability enchantment will prevent me from making inferences
that would allow me to learn the location of Hogwarts.  I will be like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://alexdunn.info/docs/carroll1895.pdf&#34; title=&#34;What the Tortoise Said to Achilles&#34;&gt;Lewis Carroll&amp;rsquo;s Tortoise&lt;/a&gt;, except unable&amp;mdash;rather than
simply unwilling&amp;mdash;to see that if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is true, and &lt;em&gt;A then B&lt;/em&gt; is
true, that &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; must be true as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, even if I know where Hogsmeade is, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; know that I have to
walk 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, because Hogwarts is Unplottable I
&lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; use this information to determine where Hogwarts is, because
I simply fail to make the simple but necessary inferences.  Likewise,
after their adventure in the flying Ford Anglia in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets,&lt;/em&gt; Harry and Ron might know both where King&amp;rsquo;s Cross Station is
and how far they traveled to get to Hogwarts, but Unplottability
prevents them from thereby deducing where Hogwarts is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to think that this enchantment could only prevent
inferences from map-based information; it would hardly honor the
spirit of the spell to suppose that if I had learn where Hogsmeade is
without using a map, that I could then determine the location of
Hogwarts.  If the purpose of Unplottability is to keep the location of
a place secret, then a blanket ban on the sorts of inferences that
would betray that secret seems entirely plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>