<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Maps on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/maps/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2013-11-21 14:00:00 -0700 -0700</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are ways to stop even a Hufflepuff from finding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so&amp;mdash;apparently&amp;mdash;incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not immediately obvious how this is possible.  Some of the
simpler and more obvious proposals as to how Unplottability might work
turn out to be no good.  Unplottability cannot not say anything about
what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of paper.  It&amp;rsquo;s possible with
magic to prevent the information from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted,&lt;/em&gt; but this
won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work is something more drastic: Unplottability has to
prevent us from &lt;em&gt;inferring&lt;/em&gt; the location of a place from other
information.  The benefit of this radical solution is that it
preserves the spirit of Unplottability, which is to prevent people
from figuring out &lt;em&gt;where Hogwarts is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of Unplottability is in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on&amp;mdash;how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists, but that&amp;rsquo;s beside the point.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got one
fact about Unplottability: it can apply to buildings and it makes it
impossible to plot them on a map.  But we learn in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;
that it applies to individual rooms as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter, sir,&amp;rdquo; squeaked Dobby, his great orblike eyes shining
in the firelight, &amp;ldquo;the Malfoy boy is breaking no rules that Dobby
can discover, but he is still keen to avoid detection. He has been
making regular visits to the seventh floor with a variety of other
students, who keep watch for him while he enters&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Room of Requirement!&amp;rdquo; said Harry, smacking himself hard on the
forehead with &lt;em&gt;Advanced Potion-Making&lt;/em&gt;. Hermione and Ron stared at
him. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s where he’s been sneaking off to!  That&amp;rsquo;s where he&amp;rsquo;s
doing … whatever he&amp;rsquo;s doing! And I bet that&amp;rsquo;s why he&amp;rsquo;s been
disappearing off the map&amp;mdash;come to think of it, I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen the
Room of Requirement on there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe the Marauders never knew the Room was there,&amp;rdquo; said Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;ll be part of the magic of the Room,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If
you need it to be Unplottable, it will be&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting aside whether the Room &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Unplottable or not, all the
evidence we&amp;rsquo;ve got so far is compatible with Unplottability being
nothing more than a restriction on what can be written down on a map.
But if the &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of Unplottability is to keep the location of a
place secret, this hardly seems sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s textual support in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; for
Unplottability being more than this sort of limited restriction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Number 12, Grimmauld Place is] ideal for Headquarters, of course,&amp;rdquo;
Sirius said. &amp;ldquo;My father put every security measure known to
wizardkind on it when he lived here. It&amp;rsquo;s unplottable, so Muggles
could never come and call&amp;mdash;as if they&amp;rsquo;d ever have wanted to&amp;mdash;and
now Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s added his protection, you&amp;rsquo;d be hard put to find a
safer house anywhere&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, Sirius can&amp;rsquo;t be right when he says that Muggles
could &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; come and call.  Durmstrang&amp;mdash;and, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume,
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;are Unplottable, but students have to be able to get there
somehow.  Likewise, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the fact that Number 12 is
&lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; protected by the Fidelius Charm, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how any sort of
&lt;em&gt;Unplottability&lt;/em&gt; could have prevented a Muggle from walking up to the
front door, unaided by any map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Unplottability can at least &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; prevent Muggles from
finding Number 12, then it&amp;rsquo;s clearly more than a restriction on what
can be drawn on a map.  But this leaves unexplained exactly what
Unplottability is and how it &lt;em&gt;works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Maybe I can draw you a map, but you can&amp;rsquo;t understand it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen that Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just be about what I can or can&amp;rsquo;t
draw on a piece of paper.  More precisely, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just prevent me
encoding certain information on a map.  It has to also keep people
from &lt;em&gt;getting&lt;/em&gt; to the place that&amp;rsquo;s Unplottable.  So the obvious idea
is that Unplottability somehow prevents us from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; a map to
locate Hogwarts (or any other Unplottable location).  How would that work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read a map, I assume that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot the
locations of certain places on their map.  I read the map with the
belief that it is written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  When I
find the location of a place on the map, I believe that I am
&lt;em&gt;recognizing the communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to
communicate to me the location of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do not believe that there is this sort of communicative
intention, I will probably not assume that I can use the map to find
the locations of places.  If I am a schoolteacher and I have my
students create maps of imaginary places, I will not pore over them
later to learn the locations of the places &amp;ldquo;plotted&amp;rdquo; on the maps.  I
know that they were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; drawn with that sort of communicative
intention, and so I would not&amp;mdash;mistakenly&amp;mdash;take them to be real maps
of real geographic areas.  I would not &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; anything from the maps
because I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is anything to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s a possible explanation for how Unplottability works: it
prevents us from recognizing the &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; behind maps
of Unplottable locations.  Even if a witch or wizard finds a map on
which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of Unplottability would
be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.
The reader would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are reading a map showing the
location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in a situation similar to
the schoolteacher looking over the students&amp;rsquo; maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the students were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but that&amp;rsquo;s no objection to the theory: &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an objection to this theory (which was
brought to my attention by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;I can still find Hogwarts if I can&amp;rsquo;t read your map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and
therefore&amp;mdash;because we used the Map to find the relative location of
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking that this loophole probably only affects
Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  So who cares, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just consist in preventing me from recognizing
a communicative intention.  It has to be something more, if it&amp;rsquo;s going
to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, and if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, therefore &amp;hellip; what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/docs/unplottable.html&#34;&gt;earlier version&lt;/a&gt; of this
essay concluded that Unplottability was impossible.  Jacob T. Levy,
Tomlinson Professor of Political Theory at McGill University, found
that pessimism unwarranted and proposed a solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s easy;just use an SEP field! Interfere with the intention to *either* draw a map or use a map (or 2 maps)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429670387501117441&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; This combines #2 and #3 w rule that if I try to put Marauder&amp;#39;s Map &amp;amp; Hogsmeade maps together I... ooh! shiny!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429671149165752320&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An S.E.P., or Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s Problem, field,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hitchhikers.wikia.com/wiki/Somebody_Else&#34; title=&#34;s_Problem_field
&amp;quot;Hitchhiker Wiki&#34;&gt;utilizes a person&amp;rsquo;s natural tendency to ignore things they don&amp;rsquo;t easily accept&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by causing them to simply &lt;em&gt;ignore&lt;/em&gt; certain
information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any object around which a S.E.P. [field] is applied will cease to be
noticed, because any problems one may have understanding it (and
therefore accepting its existence) become Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s. An object
becomes not so much invisible as unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect example of this would be a ship covered in a S.E.P. field at
a cricket match. A star ship taking the appearance of a large pink
elephant is ideal &amp;hellip; you can see it, but because it is so
inconceivable, your mind can&amp;rsquo;t accept it. Therefore it can&amp;rsquo;t exist,
thus [you ignore it].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proposal raises difficult and delicate questions in the
philosophy of mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to answer.  But it also
suggests an even simpler solution: whenever I try to infer &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; some
pieces of information &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts, the
Unplottability enchantment blocks that inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walk from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, measuring the distance, I may
end up with this bit of knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I walked 1km, northwest, from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be obvious at first, but just knowing that does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean
that one automatically knows this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hogwarts is 1km southeast of Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; (2) from (1), but I have to know some other things as
well.  Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;i&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walk a certain distance from point &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; to point &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is that far from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is a certain distance from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is the same distance from &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is northwest of &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is southeast of &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course all these things are &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;, so we don&amp;rsquo;t usually think
about how we rely on them for drawing equally obvious conclusions like
(2).  But we do rely on them, and we also rely on &lt;em&gt;inference rules&lt;/em&gt;
that allow us to move from our premises to our conclusion.  For
example, just to conclude that Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade, I have
to reason like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore&lt;/em&gt;, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore&amp;rdquo; marks the point at which I make an inference.  If I
somehow fail to see that there is a valid inference to be made, I may
be left with only the first two pieces of information, not knowing
whether Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I suggest, is exactly the situation I will be in, because the
Unplottability enchantment will prevent me from making inferences
that would allow me to learn the location of Hogwarts.  I will be like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://alexdunn.info/docs/carroll1895.pdf&#34; title=&#34;What the Tortoise Said to Achilles&#34;&gt;Lewis Carroll&amp;rsquo;s Tortoise&lt;/a&gt;, except unable&amp;mdash;rather than
simply unwilling&amp;mdash;to see that if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is true, and &lt;em&gt;A then B&lt;/em&gt; is
true, that &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; must be true as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, even if I know where Hogsmeade is, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; know that I have to
walk 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, because Hogwarts is Unplottable I
&lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; use this information to determine where Hogwarts is, because
I simply fail to make the simple but necessary inferences.  Likewise,
after their adventure in the flying Ford Anglia in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets,&lt;/em&gt; Harry and Ron might know both where King&amp;rsquo;s Cross Station is
and how far they traveled to get to Hogwarts, but Unplottability
prevents them from thereby deducing where Hogwarts is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to think that this enchantment could only prevent
inferences from map-based information; it would hardly honor the
spirit of the spell to suppose that if I had learn where Hogsmeade is
without using a map, that I could then determine the location of
Hogwarts.  If the purpose of Unplottability is to keep the location of
a place secret, then a blanket ban on the sorts of inferences that
would betray that secret seems entirely plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>