<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-02-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Spell OTP without &#34;OotP&#34;: An Essay in Ronbledore Apologetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/otp</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/otp</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, J.K. Rowling finally admitted that Ron and
Hermione should not have ended up together.  While this led us to
ponder what
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn/status/429878749941596161&#34;&gt;alternate endings&lt;/a&gt;
Rowling might have secretly preferred, it offered powerful support for
the once-maligned
&lt;a href=&#34;http://the-toast.net/2014/02/03/regret-pairing-ron-hermione-together-ron-time-traveling-dumbledore-jk-rowling-admits/&#34;&gt;Ronbledore Theory&lt;/a&gt;,
which maintains that Ron &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Dumbledore, and at some point went back
in time to live the majority of his life as the eldest son of Percival
and Kendra Dumbledore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;*Figure 1: The blue line represents the &amp;quot;Ron&amp;quot; period of Ronbledore&#39;s life, and the green represents the &amp;quot;Dumbledore&amp;quot; period.  The exact point at which Ronbledore went back in time (represented by the cyan line) is unknown, but this essay will help to narrow the possibilites.*&#34; title=&#34;Figure illustrating the Ronbledore theory&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of the Ronbledore Theory has by now been pretty well
established, but I would like to shore up its foundations with some
new evidence, evidence that will help explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; Ronbledore went
back in time, as well as&amp;mdash;roughly&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;She doesn&amp;rsquo;t get your humor like I do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step of this essay may seem to be a &lt;em&gt;non sequitur&lt;/em&gt;, but its
relevance will soon become apparent.  The first step is to show that
&lt;strong&gt;Ron and Luna Lovegood&lt;/strong&gt; are soulmates.  This is easily accomplished.
Allow me to draw your attention to two passages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, from &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron is here declaring his
intention to exert his prefect powers over Gregory Goyle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;For heaven’s sake, Ron –&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I’ll make Goyle do lines, it’ll kill him, he hates writing,’ said
Ron happily. He lowered his voice to Goyle’s low grunt and, screwing
up his face in a look of pained concentration, mimed writing in
midair. &lt;em&gt;‘I … must … not … look … like … a … baboon’s … backside.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone laughed, but nobody laughed harder than Luna Lovegood. She
let out a scream of mirth that caused Hedwig to wake up and flap her
wings indignantly and Crookshanks to leap up into the luggage rack,
hissing. Luna laughed so hard her magazine slipped out of her grasp,
slid down her legs and on to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;That was &lt;em&gt;funny&lt;/em&gt;!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her prominent eyes swam with tears as she gasped for breath, staring
at Ron. Utterly nonplussed, he looked around at the others, who were
now laughing at the expression on Ron’s face and at the ludicrously
prolonged laughter of Luna Lovegood, who was rocking backwards and
forwards, clutching her sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Are you taking the mickey?’ said Ron, frowning at her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Baboon’s … backside!’ she choked, holding her ribs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luna is the only person who truly appreciates Ron&amp;rsquo;s humor.  This point
is repeated in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;He says very funny things
sometimes, doesn’t he?&amp;ldquo;), and we also learn that Ron find&amp;rsquo;s Luna&amp;rsquo;s wit
equally enchanting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I could hear the match commentary from here,’ said Ron, his voice
now shaking with laughter. ‘I hope Luna always commentates from now
on … &lt;em&gt;Loser’s Lurgy&lt;/em&gt; …’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside.  Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy.  Surely, true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True love, however, was not to be.  Ron ended up with Hermione&amp;mdash;for a
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;“It is too late, you understand me?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did Ron end up with Hermione, when our souls cried out in protest
and even Rowling knew it was wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, ultimately, is that &lt;em&gt;it had to be so&lt;/em&gt;.  The course of Time
is fixed, and Ron&amp;rsquo;s choice of Hermione over Luna was a matter of cruel
necessity.  The course of Time is fixed: it is forever true that
Ronbledore went back in time, and so nothing can occur that would
alter that fact.  &lt;strong&gt;And Ron would not have gone back in time,
had he married Luna.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had he married his soulmate, had the baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside been blessed to
suffer from Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy for all of his days, then Ron would have
been happy.  He would have lived his life, content, no longer jealous
of Harry&amp;rsquo;s fame because the one person in the world who understands
him would be always by his side.  There would have been no dissatisfaction,
no reckless urges to break free of a dreary day-to-day and make a
dramatic break with the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But happiness was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron married Hermione, and suffered.  It was for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; reason that he
eventually went back in time, to escape the marriage he knew was wrong
and to &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; something of himself, somewhere where he would not
always be compared to the Boy Who Lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere?  Some&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;How to keep soulmates apart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question remains, however, that torments all gentle hearts: how is
it &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that Ron ended up with Hermione, when true love was
staring him in the face?  What could have prevented such a man from
pursuing Luna Lovegood and winning her hand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, or who?&lt;/strong&gt;  Attend to this passage from &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Oh, it’s a Gurdyroot,&amp;rsquo; she said, stuffing the cat litter and the
toadstool back into her bag. ‘You can keep it if you like, I’ve got
a few of them. They’re really excellent for warding off Gulping
Plimpies.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she walked away, leaving Ron chortling, still clutching the
Gurdyroot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘You know, she’s grown on me, Luna,’ he said, as they set off again
for the Great Hall. ‘I know she’s insane, but it’s in a good –’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped talking very suddenly. Lavender Brown was standing at the
foot of the marble staircase looking thunderous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Hi,’ said Ron nervously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘C’mon,’ Harry muttered to Hermione, and they sped past, though not
before they had heard Lavender say, &amp;lsquo;Why didn’t you tell me you were
getting out today? And why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; with you?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you beginning to understand?  When Lavender says &amp;ldquo;why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;
with you&amp;rdquo;, she is not referring to Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now look!  Look at this passage from &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I like this song,&amp;rsquo; said Luna, swaying in time to the waltz-like
tune, and a few seconds later she stood up and glided on to the
dance floor, where she revolved on the spot, quite alone, eyes
closed and waving her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘She’s great, isn’t she?’ said Ron admiringly. ‘Always good value.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the smile vanished from his face at once: Viktor Krum had
dropped into Luna’s vacant seat. Hermione looked pleasurably
flustered, but this time Krum had not come to compliment her. With a
scowl on his face he said, &amp;lsquo;Who is that man in the yellow?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever Ron admires Luna, whenever his heart is on the verge of
telling him its truth, &lt;strong&gt;a time-traveling witch or wizard arrives to
distract him.&lt;/strong&gt;  The most heartbreaking part of this is that these
magical anti-Cupids are most likely sent by Ronbledore himself, during
his Dumbledore years.  He knows that he &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; marry Hermione in order
to fulfill his destiny, and so deliberately undermines his own
happiness for the sake of the wizarding world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me now in a moment of silence for the &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; great sacrifices
Ronbledore makes: first, his life, and then his love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Unplottable&#34; is Unpossible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so &amp;mdash; apparently &amp;mdash; incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem impossible, and when we think through it carefully we&amp;rsquo;ll
see that it basically is.  A coherent notion of &lt;em&gt;unplottability&lt;/em&gt;
cannot not say anything about what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of
paper.  Witches and wizards might, however, try to stop people from
&lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts from that piece of paper &amp;mdash; the
information can be &lt;em&gt;encoded&lt;/em&gt;, but it may be possible with magic to
prevent it from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ultimately this won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to
find Hogwarts.  Unplottability is a scam that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on &amp;mdash; how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable &amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 121; page references are
from the UK versions of the &lt;em&gt;Pottermore&lt;/em&gt; ebooks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists or whatever, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point here.
Just what on earth does it &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; for something to be Unplottable?  If
I know where Hogwarts is, what stops me from drawing a map and marking
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on the relevant section? (I think it&amp;rsquo;s safe to assume that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaiaonline.com/forum/harry-potter/if-hogwarts-castle-is-unplottable/t.13491169_15/#15&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;If Hogwarts castle is unplottable...\&amp;quot; at Gaia Online&#34;&gt;Hogwarts is unplottable if Durmstrang is&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;We can figure out where Hogwarts is&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, drawing a map and marking &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on the relevant section
requires knowing where Hogwarts is.  One way that it would be
impossible to plot Hogwarts on a map is if &lt;em&gt;nobody actually knows&lt;/em&gt;
where Hogwarts is.  Maybe after the Founders build Hogwarts, they
&lt;em&gt;Obliviated&lt;/em&gt; each other to forget where they were and then brought in
job candidates by Floo powder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how, in this case, could the rails for the Hogarts Express have
been laid down centuries after Hogwarts was built?  Even if some
ingenious witch or wizard successfully cast the exceedingly difficult
&lt;em&gt;Build-a-Train-Track-From-Here-to-King&amp;rsquo;s-Cross-Station&lt;/em&gt; spell, you
could then just follow the Hogwarts Express in the air, like Ron and
Harry do in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, and record the castle&amp;rsquo;s location
relative to King&amp;rsquo;s Cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t consist simply in Hogwart&amp;rsquo;s location being
unknown by everyone.  If &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; know
&lt;a href=&#34;http://members.madasafish.com/~cj_whitehound/Fanfic/map_of_Hogwarts/location.htm&#34; title=&#34;White Hound&#39;s discussion of the location of Hogwarts&#34;&gt;this much about the castle&amp;rsquo;s location&lt;/a&gt;, then a clever
witch or wizard can certainly discover its whereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;I can even draw a map and write &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if that&amp;rsquo;s true, and it&amp;rsquo;s possible to discover where Hogwarts
is, why can&amp;rsquo;t we be prevented from recording that information?  Why
did I say above that unplottability &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; mean that information
about the location of Hogwarts is impossible to encode?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how someone might try to prevent us from encoding that
sort of information.  Whatever they do, I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;ll manage
it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose a witch or wizard managed to cast an enchantment that had
the following effect: whenever someone writes &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; (or
something sufficiently similar) at roughly the point where Hogwarts
is located on a map, the enchantment erases what you&amp;rsquo;ve written.
This obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, because you could refer to
Hogwarts using a different name.  This is a ban on &lt;em&gt;using
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; to refer to Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;.  It is not a ban on plotting
Hogwarts on a map.  If I am trying to make you a map with Hogwarts
on it, I could tell you &amp;ldquo;I will write &amp;lsquo;Pigfarts&amp;rsquo; instead of
&amp;lsquo;Hogwarts&amp;rsquo;&amp;ldquo;, and then when I write &amp;ldquo;Pigfarts&amp;rdquo;, I am plotting
Hogwarts on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second problem with this approach is that if the enchantment
only detects when I&amp;rsquo;ve written &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;, my writing will be
visible until I finish that string of letters.  If you are
watching over my shoulder as I work, you will see me get at least
as far as &amp;ldquo;Hogwart&amp;rdquo; and will probably infer my intention (to plot
Hogwarts on this map), and the enchantment will be foiled.  In
order to work, the enchantment would have to determine our
&lt;em&gt;intentions&lt;/em&gt; and act before we can even start writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of &lt;em&gt;intention&lt;/em&gt; brings us to a second possible method
to make it impossible to encode information about a place&amp;rsquo;s
location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose it&amp;rsquo;s possible, somehow, to determine when I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;intending&lt;/em&gt;
to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Maybe an enchantment could figure out
when I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about Hogwarts in a certain way while mapmaking,
or whatever.  When this happens, the enchantment makes me forget
what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, or triggers something like the Tongue-Tying Curse
except for writing, or in some other way prevents me from
fulfilling my intention to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
this work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work because it&amp;rsquo;s possible for someone to make
something that &lt;em&gt;functions&lt;/em&gt; as a map showing the location of
Hogwarts without intending to.  Suppose a Muggle child is drawing
fake maps for fun and &lt;em&gt;accidentally&lt;/em&gt; draws one with a castle in
just the right place on an accurate representation of the Scottish
highlands.  It&amp;rsquo;s even possible that &amp;mdash; by a massive coincidence
&amp;mdash; the child could decide to label this castle &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a sense in which this Muggle child
has not plotted Hogwarts on a map, the following scenario could
still occur: the child drops their map while leaving King&amp;rsquo;s Cross,
and it is picked up by a witch or wizard, who has been seeking the
location of Hogwarts.  They assume that someone plotted Hogwarts
on a map and then dropped it.  They guide themselves using this
map, and as a result arrive at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first solution was obviously insufficient, in part because it
failed to account for a mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s intention.  But in our examination
of the second solution, we can see that accounting for the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
intention won&amp;rsquo;t work either.  Our scenario, involving the child
serendipitously writing &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; in exactly the right place on a map
of the Scottish highlands, might be a scenario in which it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;strictly
false&lt;/em&gt; that Hogwarts was plotted on a map, but the spirit of the idea
has clearly been violated.  The &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of unplottability is to keep
people from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; maps to locate Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we should look next at how a witch or wizard would &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; a map to
find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;But I can&amp;rsquo;t use that map to find Hogwarts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crucial detail of our scenario above was that the witch or wizard
who finds the child&amp;rsquo;s map &lt;em&gt;assumes&lt;/em&gt; that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot
Hogwarts on their map.  They believe &amp;mdash; incorrectly, in this case &amp;mdash;
that the map was written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  The witch
or wizard believes &amp;mdash; again incorrectly &amp;mdash; that they &lt;em&gt;recognize the
communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to communicate to the
reader the location of Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose our witch or wizard had not made this mistake.  Suppose they
overheard the Muggle child taking about the map before dropping it,
and realized that it was pure coincidence that led the child to label
a map with &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.  If the witch or wizard nonetheless picked up
the map, they would not mistake it for a map showing the location of
Hogwarts because they would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; take themselves to recognize the
author&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.  They would not think that the map
was written with a communicative intent.  They would not learn
anything from the map because they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is
anything to learn.  Information transmission of this sort requires the
belief in a communicative intention, and when this is missing it will
not occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if unplottability does anything at all, it prevents readers of maps
from recognizing a communicative intention.  Even if a witch or wizard
finds a map on which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of
unplottability will be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
communicative intention.  The reader will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are
reading a map showing the location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in
a situation similar to the witch or wizard who knows that they are
looking at the scrawlings of a Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but whatever, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter because you can find Hogwarts anyway using maps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed to be coming together nicely until I got
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHZNpFiIQbA#t=0h06m14s&#34;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;
from an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenrobynne&#34;&gt;anonymous reviewer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all due respect my lord, there&amp;rsquo;s just one tiny flaw with this
flawless plan &amp;hellip; the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augh, you&amp;rsquo;re right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and therefore
&amp;mdash; because we used the Map to find the relative location of Hogwarts
&amp;mdash; locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking, &amp;ldquo;Whatever, Snape.  This loophole probably
only affects Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  Who cares?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only guess at this point is that unplottability is a scam.  There
aren&amp;rsquo;t enough jobs in the wizarding world so the Ministry made up
things like unplottability and &lt;a href=&#34;trace.html&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s No Such
Thing as the Trace&#34;&gt;the Trace&lt;/a&gt; in order to create positions for otherwise
useless people who couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass their O.W.L.s.  They go around making
things like the World Cup stadium unplottable and get to feel good
about themselves, because given the level of intelligence in the
wizarding world they probably don&amp;rsquo;t realize that what they&amp;rsquo;re doing is
useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe unplottability still does prevent information transmission, and
maybe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.  Either way it&amp;rsquo;s basically useless, but that
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a big surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s No Such Thing as the Trace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/trace</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/trace</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Much is made in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; about &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;, the charm on
underage witches and wizards that is used by the Ministry to detect
illegal spellwork.  The problem is that there is no such thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo; supposed to be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second problem: you&amp;rsquo;re under-age, which means you&amp;rsquo;ve still got the
Trace on you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Trace, the Trace!&amp;rdquo; said Mad-Eye impatiently.  &amp;ldquo;The charm that
detects magical activity around under-seventeens, the way the
Ministry finds out about under-age magic!  If you, or anyone around
you, casts a spell to get you out of here, Thicknesse is going to
know about it, and so will the Death Eaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the Trace to break, because the moment you turn
seventeen you&amp;rsquo;ll lose all the protection your mother gave you.  In
short: Pius Thicknesse thinks he&amp;rsquo;s got you cornered good and
proper.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry could not help but agree with the unknown Thicknesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So what are we going to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to use the only means of transport left to us, the only
ones the Trace can&amp;rsquo;t detect, because we don&amp;rsquo;t need to cast spells to
use them: brooms, Thestrals and Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s motorbike&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 40
[page numbers from the UK Pottermore editions]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trace apparently allows the Ministry to know &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; about the
location of underage wizards, in order to determine if they are
breaking the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage
Sorcery.  The Ministry has separate, unspecified ways of knowing when
and where magic is performed in the United Kingdom; the Trace does
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; specifically tell the Ministry when an underage witch or wizard
&lt;em&gt;performs&lt;/em&gt; magic.  The Trace, in conjunction with the aforementioned
unspecified magic detection mechanisms, allows the Ministry to know
when magic is performed in close proximity to an underage witch or
wizard (the canny reader will see from the above quote that there&amp;rsquo;s
already a problem; but we&amp;rsquo;ll come to that).  This is what leads to the
Ministry issuing Harry with a warning when Dobby explodes a cake in #4
Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Mr Potter,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have received intelligence that a Hover Charm was used at your
place of residence this evening at twelve minutes past nine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As you know, underage wizards are not permitted to perform spells
outside school, and further spellwork on your part may lead to
expulsion from said school (Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of
Underage Sorcery, 1875, Paragraph C).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would also ask you to remember that any magical activity which
risks notice by members of the non-magical community (Muggles) is a
serious offence, under section 13 of the International Confederation
of Warlocks&amp;rsquo; Statute of Secrecy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy your holidays!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mafalda Hopkirk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improper Use of Magic Office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ministry of Magic&lt;/em&gt;  (&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, sadly, this is all a terrible vicious lie.  The Trace does not
exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t it exist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;, Dumbledore shows Harry the recorded memory
of Morfin&amp;rsquo;s meeting with Voldemort.  Dumbledore explains that it is
nearly certain that Voldemort Stunned Morfin, took his wand, and
murdered the Riddle family.  Harry points out a rather large problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But how come the Ministry didn&amp;rsquo;t realise that Voldemort had done
all that to Morfin?&amp;rdquo; Harry asked angrily.  &amp;ldquo;He was under age at the
time, wasn&amp;rsquo;t he?  I thought they could detect under-age magic!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are quite right&amp;mdash;they can detect magic, but not the
perpetrator: you will remember that you were blamed by the Ministry
for the Hover Charm that was, in fact, cast by&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dobby,&amp;rdquo; growled Harry; this injustice still rankled.  &amp;ldquo;So if you&amp;rsquo;re
under age and you do magic inside an adult witch or wizard&amp;rsquo;s house,
the Ministry won&amp;rsquo;t know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They will certainly be unable to tell who performed the magic,&amp;rdquo;
said Dumbledore, smiling slightly at the look of great indignation
on Harry&amp;rsquo;s face.  &amp;ldquo;They rely on witch and wizard parents to enforce
their offspring&amp;rsquo;s obedience while within their walls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s rubbish,&amp;rdquo; snapped Harry. &amp;ldquo;Look what happened here,
look what happened to Morfin!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we basically already knew that because of the Dobby thing.  We
already know why Voldemort didn&amp;rsquo;t get in trouble for doing magic at
the Gaunt House.  But &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;there were no other witches or wizards at the
Riddle house when Voldemort killed them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  How did the Ministry fail
to notice &lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter
Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;three uses of Avada Kedavra by a sixteen-year old in a
Muggle home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few theories have surfaced to explain this inconsistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Talk:The_Trace#As_to_the_inconsistency_regarding_Tom_Riddle...&#34; title=&#34;Talk page for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot; on the Harry Potter Wikia&#34;&gt;Voldemort was not underage when he killed the Riddles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cedric Diggory was 17 in his sixth year, allowing him to enter the
Triwizard Tournament.  Wikia user Thanksherman proposes that
Voldemort was similarly old for his age, allowing him to come of
age and act without the Trace in his sixth year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this theory is twofold: Not only does Dumbledore
not contradict Harry above when Harry asks how Voldemort could
have done magic without it being detected by the Ministry,
Dumbledore explicitly claims that Voldemort was then Harry&amp;rsquo;s
age&amp;mdash;and Harry wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn 17 for some time.  When discussing
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s conversation with Horace Slughorn (which occurs after
the Riddle House incident), Dumbledore says to Harry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am sure you understood the significance of what we just
heard.  At the same age as you are now, give or take a few
months, Tom Riddle was doing all he could to find out how to
make himself immortal&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt; 332).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trace works in strange ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only sketchy descriptions of the Trace in the books,
leaving open the possibility that the Trace works in unintuitive
ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that the Trace breaks when a witch or wizard
turns 17, and the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Muggles%27_Guide_to_Harry_Potter/Magic/Underage_Sorcery#Analysis&#34; title=&#34;Wikibooks: Muggles&#39; Guide to Harry Potter---Underage Sorcery&#34;&gt;keep tabs on the locations of adult wizards&lt;/a&gt;;
otherwise in &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt; they would have chased after any
adult witches and wizards found in odd locations; Harry, Ron, and
Hermione would have been caught in short order.  (How the hell they
know that Harry casts his Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;in
the presence of a Muggle&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Dudley&amp;mdash;would be another troubling
question, if the Trace exists.  But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Ministry can&amp;rsquo;t track the locations of underage witches and
wizards &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;d be forgiven for thinking so, since as
much is implied in &lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wondered,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione tentatively, &amp;ldquo;whether Harry could
still have the Trace on him?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Impossible,&amp;rdquo; said Lupin. Ron looked smug, and Harry felt hugely
relieved. &amp;ldquo;Apart from anything else, they&amp;rsquo;d know for sure Harry
was here if he still had the Trace on him, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they? But I
can&amp;rsquo;t see how they could have tracked you to Tottenham Court
Road, that&amp;rsquo;s worrying, really worrying&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 143).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the quote at the very beginning of this essay, Moody states
explicitly that the Ministry &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; track underage witches and
wizards.  If they could, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether Harry traveled
from Privet Drive by Portkey, Thestral, broom, or Apparition.  And
in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;, Scrimgeour asks Harry where he went with Dumbledore
before the latter&amp;rsquo;s death, something he would know if the Trace
allowed the Ministry to actually track underage witches and
wizards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; can the Ministry know whether a bit
of magic, performed near a Traced person, is plausibly underage
sorcery or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry might keep a list of underage wizards &lt;em&gt;known to be
alone&lt;/em&gt; or otherwise without magical supervision.  Harry would fall
in this category, as well as Muggleborns and other special cases
(like Voldemort at the orphanage).  Warnings are only sent when
magic is performed in the vicinity of these people&amp;rsquo;s homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this this just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem true: when the Advance Guard
removes Harry from Privet Drive, Tonks casts several spells,
apparently with no repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace#Limitations&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;, section on
\&amp;quot;Limitations\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;usual reply here&lt;/a&gt; is that the Ministry is notified when adult
witches and wizards (Arthur Weasley in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;,
Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;) are going to visit.  The Ministry then
supposedly ignores magic for the duration of the visit.  But the
Ministry does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know that the Advance Guard removed Harry from
Privet Drive.  Allowing the &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; to take Harry
to the home of &lt;em&gt;Sirius Black&lt;/em&gt; does not seem like something the
Fudge administration would do.  Moreover, during Harry&amp;rsquo;s
disciplinary hearing, it&amp;rsquo;s made explicit that the Ministry
believes him to be still residing at Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry,&amp;rdquo; said Harry nervously.  &amp;ldquo;I&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the time
had been changed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That is not the Wizengamot&amp;rsquo;s fault,&amp;rdquo; said the voice. &amp;ldquo;An
owl was sent to you this morning. Take your seat&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;
108).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there&amp;rsquo;s some wiggle-room here as well; Fudge and
Umbridge are trying to get Harry expelled, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible they
arranged to have the letter sent to the wrong address.  But if
they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; figure out that Harry was living at #12 Grimmauld
Place, the Noble and Most Ancient House of Black, they would
surely suspect him of having contact with the last Black family
member (a fine excuse to detain him for questioning and
harassment).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No way is there such a thing as &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s really going on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, why does everyone think it does?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the characters in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; are pretty stupid.  Dumbledore
&lt;em&gt;tells&lt;/em&gt; Harry that underage witches and wizards can do magic in the
home of an adult witch or wizard, and Harry &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t do magic
at the Burrow until he turns 17 and gets all excited.  Dumbledore
nearly allows Katie Bell &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Ron to die because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like
confronting Malfoy about his whole assassination plan in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood
Prince&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron never realized he&amp;rsquo;s allowed to do magic at home and
peels sprouts by hand for 17 years.  Hermione&amp;rsquo;s pretty smart I guess,
but she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really show a strong understanding of the Trace
either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; stretch to assume that it&amp;rsquo;s a lie spread by the
(equally inept) Ministry to control the magical population.  The
Ministry is too stupid to actually implement the Trace, and the rest
are stupid enough to believe in it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But questions remain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Dobby&amp;rsquo;s Hover Charm in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Aunt Marge&amp;rsquo;s big mistake, in order
to send people to Privet Drive to deflate her?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did Ministry learn about Harry&amp;rsquo;s Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the
Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best guess at an answer to all three is &amp;hellip; Mrs Figg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Whaaaaaa?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I don&amp;rsquo;t like these sorts of conspiracy theories either.  But
she&amp;rsquo;s always near Privet Drive, and the only not-obviously-canon claim
I&amp;rsquo;m making is that she works for the Ministry rather than for
Dumbledore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;mdash;or one of her cats&amp;mdash;saw the Hover Charm (whether or not they
saw Dobby), saw Marge explode, and saw the Patronus.  She did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
see the Weasleys travel to the Dursley&amp;rsquo;s by Floo Powder, or see the
Advance Guard arrive in &lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, or Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;.  Maybe she was
asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the books state that she &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see the Patronus, and so she could
have communicated with the Ministry immediately after (using her own
Patronus&amp;mdash;if she&amp;rsquo;s only pretending to be a Squib&amp;mdash;or using a mirror
like the one Sirius gives to Harry or a Protean-Charmed object like
the DA coins).  That situation was already suspicious, because she
claims that she knew about Mundungus running off right away, but
didn&amp;rsquo;t bother contacting Harry and telling him to stay inside.  So
either she was lying about that, or knew Mundungus left to buy
cauldrons but had Ministry orders not to warn Harry (the Dementors
&lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; sent by Umbridge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose Mrs Figg was spying on Harry for the Ministry because he&amp;rsquo;s
important and the Ministry wants to keep tabs on him.  Other
high-profile witches and wizards presumably get the same treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;An objection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might cry: &amp;ldquo;But surely a simpler explanation is just as you
said&amp;mdash;the Ministry is inept!  It&amp;rsquo;s not that the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist,
but rather the Ministry is just really bad about following up on the
instances of magic it detects.  Depending on how the Trace works,
either they just didn&amp;rsquo;t notice Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s magic performed at the
Riddle House, or they failed to see that Tonks cast &lt;em&gt;Lumos&lt;/em&gt; and some
stupid trunk-packing spell when the Advance Guard came to get Harry.
See, no need to drag poor Mrs Figg into your wild imagination!&amp;rdquo;  (This
objection is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zayalhawa&#34; title=&#34;Twitter
profile&#34;&gt;Aziza&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be a better explanation, but for one thing.  As I noted
above, when the Ministry takes Harry to task for his Patronus in
&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, they know something that only Mrs Figg (or another spy) could
know: that Harry performed magic in the presence of a Muggle: Dudley.
If the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t track the relatively small adult magical
population, the idea that they might be tracking all Muggles is pretty
wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they be tracking just a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; Muggles of importance?&amp;rdquo;
Dudley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; important, though; he already knows about magic, so
seeing &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; magic isn&amp;rsquo;t a major breach of the Statute of Secrecy.
The Ministry just &lt;em&gt;pretends&lt;/em&gt; it is while they&amp;rsquo;re trying to expel
Harry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The complete guide to wand ownership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wands</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wands</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Until &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;, we all thought &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; was just a
nifty spell that causes people to drop their wands and sometimes
knocks them over (which is why we had all those Tower Truthers saying
that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beyondhogwarts.com/harry-potter/articles/dumbledore-clues.html&#34; title=&#34;Beyond Hogwarts&#34;&gt;Dumbledore wasn&amp;rsquo;t
dead&lt;/a&gt;).
But then it turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;totally bonkers&lt;/em&gt;. Apparently
disarming someone actually &lt;em&gt;transfers their wand&amp;rsquo;s loyalty to you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is totally bonkers because &lt;em&gt;everybody disarms everybody&lt;/em&gt; at some
point.  So to figure out whose wand is whose and what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;
happened, let&amp;rsquo;s catalog every instance of disarming ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do that, though, we need to figure out when exactly a wand
changes owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not &lt;em&gt;exactly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Disarming for Dummies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason Harry has to finish He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named in the
&lt;em&gt;very same way&lt;/em&gt; that he beats You-Know-Who when he&amp;rsquo;s only a baby;
namely, by having Lord Thingy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra&lt;/em&gt; bounce off the Chosen
Boy like he&amp;rsquo;s some sort of magic mirror. In order to pull it off,
Rowling drops this tidbit on us two-thirds of the way through
&lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hawthorn and unicorn hair. Ten inches precisely. Reasonably
springy. This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Was?&amp;rdquo; repeated Harry. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it still his?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps not. If you took it&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;I did&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;then it may be yours.  Of course, the manner of taking matters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I took this wand from Draco Malfoy by force,&amp;rdquo; said Harry.  &amp;ldquo;Can I
use it safely?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think so. Subtle laws govern wand ownership, but the conquered
wand will usually bend its will to its new master&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 334&amp;ndash;335).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re prone to fits of charitability, you might think that all
this means is that, when you disarm someone else by force and take
their wand, &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; the wand &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;bend its will&amp;rdquo; to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you would be wrong! Check out this exchange from Harry&amp;rsquo;s rap
battle with Voldy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You still don&amp;rsquo;t get it, Riddle, do you? Possessing the wand isn&amp;rsquo;t
enough!  Holding it, using it, doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it really yours.  Didn&amp;rsquo;t
you listen to Ollivander?  &lt;em&gt;The wand chooses the wizard&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip; the
Elder Wand recognised a new master before Dumbledore died, someone
who never even laid a hand on it.  The new master removed the wand
from Dumbledore against his will, never realising exactly what he
had done, or that the world&amp;rsquo;s most dangerous wand had given him its
allegiance &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s chest rose and fell rapidly, and Harry could feel the
curse coming, feel it building inside the wand pointed at his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The true master of the Elder Wand was Draco Malfoy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blank shock showed in Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s face for a moment, but then it was
gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But what does it matter?&amp;rdquo; he said softly. &amp;ldquo;Even if you are right,
Potter, it makes no difference to you and me.  You no longer have
the phoenix wand: we duel on skill alone &amp;hellip; and after I have killed
you, I can attend to Draco Malfoy &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you&amp;rsquo;re too late,&amp;rdquo; said Harry.  &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve missed your chance.  I
got there first.  I overpowered Draco weeks ago.  I took this wand
from him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry twitched the hawthorn wand, and he felt the eyes of everyone
in the Hall upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So it all comes down to this, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; whispered Harry.  &amp;ldquo;Does
the wand in your hand know its last master was Disarmed?  Because if
it does &amp;hellip; I am the true master of the Elder Wand&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 497).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t even have to &lt;em&gt;touch&lt;/em&gt; a wand to win it. And not only that,
when you disarm someone &lt;em&gt;you get all the wands &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;they&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/em&gt;* won*.
That&amp;rsquo;s how Harry gets the Elder Wand by disarming Draco, even though
it&amp;rsquo;s tucked away in Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s tomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at least you do have to disarm the other person &lt;em&gt;by force&lt;/em&gt;, like
Ollivander says, right?  WRONG AGAIN:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now Harry was hurrying along a dark corridor in stout little
Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s wake as he held a lantern aloft: Gregorovitch burst
into the room at the end of the passage and his lantern illuminated
what looked like a workshop; wood-shavings and gold gleamed in the
swinging pool of light, and there on the window ledge sat perched,
like a giant bird, a young man with golden hair.  In the split
second that the lantern&amp;rsquo;s light illuminated him, Harry saw the
delight upon his handsome face, then the intruder shot a Stunning
Spell from his wand and jumped neatly backwards out of the window
with a crow of laughter (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 194).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grindelwald wins the Elder Wand by just sneaking into Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s
bedroom and nicking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we could get into fussy debates over &lt;em&gt;intention&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;malice&lt;/em&gt;,
and try to lay down some criteria for when nabbing someone else&amp;rsquo;s
wand &lt;em&gt;really counts&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;disarming&amp;rdquo; them and so transfers the
ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would be &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s just assume that anyone who grabs
someone else&amp;rsquo;s wand or otherwise disarms them gains ownership of
every wand that person owns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, which wands belong to who?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Swaps that happen before Harry starts at Hogwarts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just saw how Grindelwald steals the Elder wand from Gregorovitch.
Let&amp;rsquo;s write that down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 482:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think he knew it, I think he knew what frightened me.  I delayed
meeting him until, finally, it would have been too shameful to
resist any longer.  People were dying and he seemed unstoppable, and
I had to do what I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you know what happened next.  I won the duel. I won the
wand.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.  He lost Dumbledore long ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 476:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snape reacted so fast it was as though he had been expecting an
attack: dropping his bag, he plunged his hand inside his robes and
his wand was halfway into the air when James shouted,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor Snivellus can never catch a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing. No wand, no dignity (we all saw his undies,
remember?), no Lily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 454:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a blinding, jagged jet of white light flew through the air:
Harry thought of lightning, but Snape had dropped to his knees and
his wand had flown out of his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t kill me!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was not my intention.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any sound of Dumbledore Apparating had been drowned by the sound of
the wind in the branches.  He stood before Snape with his robes
whipping around him, and his face was illuminated from below in the
light cast by his wand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like an &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;; Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s too weird for
any normal spells. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly some sort of disarming,
but&amp;mdash;woops&amp;mdash;James already disarmed Snivellus. Snape doesn&amp;rsquo;t own his
wand anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how things stand going into the first book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS&lt;/em&gt; 121:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hermione had sunk to the floor in fright; Ron pulled out his own
wand&amp;mdash;not knowing what he was going to do he heard himself cry the
first spell that came into his head: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Wingardium Leviosa!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The club flew suddenly out of the troll&amp;rsquo;s hand, rose high, high up
into the air, turned slowly over&amp;mdash;and dropped, with a sickening
crack, on to its owner&amp;rsquo;s head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because why should we limit this to wands? How very close-minded. The
wand chooses the wizard, but the club chooses the mindless death
machine, too. (Ron is pretty mindless, so the club chose well here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club and his own wand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 130:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them swung their wands up and over their shoulders. Snape
cried: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  There was a dazzling flash of scarlet light
and Lockhart was blasted off his feet: he flew backwards off the
stage, smashed into the wall and slid down it to sprawl on the
floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good for Snivellus, he owns a wand again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing but his looks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 162:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percy said, &amp;ldquo;As a school Prefect&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;, but Harry had lost his temper.
He pulled out his wand and shouted, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and just as
Snape had disarmed Lockhart, so Malfoy found the diary shooting out
of his hand into the air.  Ron, grinning broadly, caught it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has his own wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; is going to have to buy new books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 200:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry reached his wand just in time. Lockhart had barely raised his,
when Harry bellowed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  Lockhart was blasted
backwards, falling over his trunk.  His wand flew high into the air;
Ron caught it, and flung it out of the open window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dang, Lockhart already lost his wands.  Ron is actually throwing
&lt;em&gt;Snape&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; wand out the window.  &lt;strong&gt;No changes&lt;/strong&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 203:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get up,&amp;rdquo; said Ron sharply, pointing his wand at Lockhart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lockhart got to his feet&amp;mdash;then he dived at Ron, knocking him to the
ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry jumped forward, but too late. Lockhart was straightening up,
panting, Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand in his hand and a gleaming smile back on his
face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t Harry just &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; him again here? Possibly
because Harry&amp;rsquo;s an idiot; but who knows, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 227:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry, Ron, Hermione, Fred, George and Ginny got a compartment to
themselves. They made the most of the last few hours in which they
were allowed to do magic before the holidays. They played Exploding
Snap, set off the very last of Fred and George&amp;rsquo;s Filibuster
Fireworks, and practised disarming each other by magic. Harry was
getting very good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, since we don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; disarms &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; here (THANKS, J.K.),
let&amp;rsquo;s just suppose that, since &amp;ldquo;Harry was getting very good at it&amp;rdquo;,
he disarmed everyone else.  That makes sense, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands, and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s review the scores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands, and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has his own wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has a library card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 14:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it when Dad won the&lt;/em&gt; Daily Prophet &lt;em&gt;Draw.  Seven
hundred galleons!  Most of it&amp;rsquo;s gone on this holiday, but they&amp;rsquo;re
going to buy me a new wand for next year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron gets a new wand!  Since it probably &amp;ldquo;chose&amp;rdquo; him at Ollivander&amp;rsquo;s, I
don&amp;rsquo;t think it knows or cares that Lockhart disarmed him the previous
year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s old wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 221:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Sirius Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he croaked, pointing Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s and Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wands shot out of their hands, high in the
air, and Black caught them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like Sirius took Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand by force, then did some badass
double-disarmery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s new wand along with Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s,
Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; still has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 222:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Black&amp;rsquo;s free hand had found Harry&amp;rsquo;s throat&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; he hissed. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve waited too long&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fingers tightened, Harry choked, his glasses askew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he saw Hermione&amp;rsquo;s foot swing out of nowhere.  Black let go of
Harry with a grunt of pain.  Ron had thrown himself on Black&amp;rsquo;s wand
hand and Harry heard a faint clatter&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron proves himself not entirely useless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and
Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands, along with his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 224:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Lupin shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand flew once more out of his hand; so did the two Hermione
was holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione was holding her and Ron&amp;rsquo;s wands, but she didn&amp;rsquo;t take them by
force from Ron; he still owns them (and Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand), and Lupin
doesn&amp;rsquo;t disarm &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think Lupin wins anything here. He
wins whatever wands are Hermione&amp;rsquo;s and Harry&amp;rsquo;s, which are none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 236:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry made up his mind in a split second. Before Snape could take
even one step towards him, he had raised his wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he yelled&amp;mdash;except that his wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only voice
that shouted. There was a blast that made the door rattle on its
hinges; Snape was lifted off his feet and slammed into the wall,
then slid down it to the floor, a trickle of blood oozing from under
his hair. He had been knocked out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry looked around. Both Ron and Hermione had tried to disarm Snape
at exactly the same moment.  Snape&amp;rsquo;s wand soared in a high arc and
landed on the bed next to Crookshanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shit.  &lt;em&gt;Exactly&lt;/em&gt; the same moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boring interpretation is that since no one person disarmed Snape,
nobody wins his wands.  But that&amp;rsquo;s not our only option: look where the
wand lands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt; 249:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettigrew had dived for Lupin&amp;rsquo;s dropped wand. Ron, unsteady on his
bandaged leg, fell. There was a bang, a burst of light&amp;mdash;and Ron lay
motionless on the ground.  Another bang&amp;mdash;Crookshanks flew into the
air and back to the earth in a heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Harry yelled, pointing his own wand at Pettigrew;
Lupin&amp;rsquo;s wand flew high into the air and out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wands and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pettigrew&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and
Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands, along with his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s old wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 42:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss the fun, but Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s second
ornament narrowly missed his left ear, and on balance he thought it
best to leave the situation to Mr Weasley.  He stepped into the
fire, looking over his shoulder as he said, &amp;ldquo;The Burrow!&amp;rdquo;; his last
fleeting glimpse of the living room was of Mr Weasley blasting a
third ornament out of Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s hand with his wand, Aunt
Petunia screaming and lying on top of Dudley, and Dudley&amp;rsquo;s tongue
lolling around like a great slimy python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the Dursleys are going to have a pretty barren Christmas
tree, because &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; still has an epic mustache, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 459:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was starting to fight my father&amp;rsquo;s Imperius Curse.  There were
times when I was almost myself again. There were brief periods when
I seemed outside his control.  It happened, there, in the Top Box.
It was like waking from a deep sleep.  I found myself out in public,
in the middle of the match, and I saw a wand sticking out of a boy&amp;rsquo;s
pocket in front of me.  I had not been allowed a wand since before
Azkaban.  I stole it.  Winky didn&amp;rsquo;t know.  Winky is frightened of
heights.  She had her face hidden.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; still has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books, even though he doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve
them. He hasn&amp;rsquo;t read anything since Hermione started doing his
homework for him in the first year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 423&amp;ndash;424:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was no use&amp;mdash;the spider was either so large, or so magical,
that the spells were doing no more than aggravating it&amp;mdash;Harry had
one horrifying glimpse of eight shining black eyes, and razor-sharp
pincers, before it was upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was lifted into the air in its front legs; struggling madly, he
tried to kick it; his leg connected with the pincers, and next
moment he was in excruciating pain&amp;mdash;he could hear Cedric yelling
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; too, but his spell had no more effect than
Harry&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;Harry raised his wand as the spider opened its pincers
once more, and shouted,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked&amp;mdash;the Disarming spell made the spider drop him, but that
meant that Harry fell twelve feet onto his already injured leg,
which crumpled beneath him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After disarming the spider, Harry no longer feels alienated from his
own body. He finds that he is more comfortable in his own skin and in
fact has better motor control too. (Now you might say, &amp;ldquo;Alex, that&amp;rsquo;s
stupid.&amp;rdquo;  Yes.  &lt;em&gt;But how else could he survive the graveyard?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 444:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voldemort was ready. As Harry shouted &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, Voldemort
cried &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A jet of green light issued from Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand just as a jet of
red light blasted from Harry&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;they met in mid-air&amp;mdash;and suddenly
Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand was vibrating as though an electric charge was surging
through it; his hand had seized up around it; he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have
released it if he&amp;rsquo;d wanted to&amp;mdash;and a narrow beam of light was now
connecting the two wands, neither red nor green, but bright, deep
gold&amp;mdash;and Harry, following the beam with his astonished gaze, saw
that Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s long white fingers, too, were gripping a wand that
was shaking and vibrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody gets disarmed here, we just get some &lt;em&gt;Priori Incantatem&lt;/em&gt;
nonsense.  So there are &lt;strong&gt;no changes&lt;/strong&gt; of wand ownership during this
&lt;em&gt;geist ex whatthefuck&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not enough changes here to do a whole recap of who-owns-what. Let&amp;rsquo;s
move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 293:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room was suddenly full of shouts of &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;.  Wands flew
in all directions; missed spells hit books on shelves and sent them
flying into the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 293:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry was too quick for Neville, whose wand went spinning out of his
hand, hit the ceiling in a shower of sparks and landed with a
clatter on top of a bookshelf, from which Harry retrieved it with a
Summoning Charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 293:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; said Neville, and Harry, caught unawares, felt his
wand fly out of his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 293&amp;ndash;294:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something very odd was happening to Zacharias Smith.  Every time he
opened his mouth to disarm Anthony Goldstein, his own wand would fly
out of his hand, yet Anthony did not seem to be making a sound.
Harry did not have to look far to solve the mystery: Fred and George
were several feet from Smith and taking it in turns to point their
wands at his back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginny was teamed with Michael Corner; she was doing very well,
whereas Michael was either very bad or unwilling to jinx her.  Ernie
Macmillan was flourishing his wand unnecessarily, giving his partner
time to get in under his guard; the Creevey brothers were
enthusiastic but erratic and mainly responsible for all the books
leaping off the shelves around them; Luna Lovegood was similarly
patchy, occasionally sending Justin Finch-Fletchley&amp;rsquo;s wand spinning
out of his hand, at other times merely causing his hair to stand on
end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, my dad is very supportive of any anti-Ministry action!&amp;rdquo; said
Luna Lovegood proudly from just behind Harry; evidently she had been
eavesdropping on his conversation while Justin Finch-Fletchley
attempted to disentangle himself from the robes that had flown up
over his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and her wands and his hair and his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zacharias&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justin&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 295:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was really, really good, Harry,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, when finally
it was just her, Harry and Ron who were left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, it was!&amp;rdquo; said Ron enthusiastically, as they slipped out of
the door and watched it melt back into stone behind them.  &amp;ldquo;Did you
see me disarm Hermione, Harry?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Hermione&amp;rsquo;s inexplicable attraction to Ron (the boy so solid he
cannot apparate half an inch across a room and who nobody likes) is
due to the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s always got her wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 546:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take his wand,&amp;rdquo; she barked at someone he could not see, and he felt
a hand grope inside the chest pocket of his robes and remove the
wand. &amp;ldquo;Hers, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry heard a scuffle over by the door and knew that Hermione had
also just had her wand wrested from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to know why you are in my office,&amp;rdquo; said Umbridge, shaking
the fist clutching his hair so that he staggered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it&amp;rsquo;s Malfoy disarming Harry and Millicent Bulstrode taking
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wand. (It&amp;rsquo;s always Millicent who gets Hermione. I wonder
if Hermione smells like Millicent&amp;rsquo;s cat because of the Polyjuice
episode and that makes Millicent inexplicably attracted to Hermione.
Huh.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Harry still doesn&amp;rsquo;t own a wand. Too bad Draco didn&amp;rsquo;t relieve
Harry of his homework planner, too; then Draco would get his books
back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione doesn&amp;rsquo;t have shit either.  &lt;strong&gt;No changes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 546:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a commotion outside and several large Slytherins entered,
each gripping Ron, Ginny, Luna and&amp;mdash;to Harry&amp;rsquo;s
bewilderment&amp;mdash;Neville, who was trapped in a stranglehold by Crabbe
and looked in imminent danger of suffocation.  All four of them had
been gagged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only gagged but also, presumably, disarmed.  The tricky thing here
is figuring out who disarmed who.  Warrington is holding Ron and
Crabbe has Neville, so they probably also took their wands, but the
other Slytherins are unnamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s
and Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands and Ron&amp;rsquo;s new wand, as well as his own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s and his wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and Luna&amp;rsquo;s wands and their own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 559:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you get away?&amp;rdquo; asked Harry in amazement, taking his wand
from Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couple of Stunners, a Disarming Charm, Neville brought off a really
nice little Impediment Jinx,&amp;rdquo; said Ron airily, now handing back
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wand, too. &amp;ldquo;But Ginny was best, she got
Malfoy&amp;mdash;Bat-Bogey Hex&amp;mdash;it was superb, his whole face was covered
in the great flapping things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginny probably disarmed Malfoy, but otherwise we don&amp;rsquo;t have much to
help us figure out who disarmed who, or how they got their wands back
from the Slytherins in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to just say that each of our Heroes snatched their
wand from the person holding them&amp;mdash;their physical injuries support
this, maybe&amp;mdash;but even then, who got Millicent? The person who
disarmed Millicent was whoever cast the Disarming Charm
(&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;, obvs), so it likely wasn&amp;rsquo;t Neville or Ginny. Given
Luna&amp;rsquo;s relative ineptitude with the spell, there&amp;rsquo;s a fair chance it
wasn&amp;rsquo;t her. So let&amp;rsquo;s say Ron disarmed Millicent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s,
Sirius&amp;rsquo;, Millicent&amp;rsquo;s and Warrington&amp;rsquo;s wands, along with his own new
wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club. (Dang. For someone so useless Ron sure
is useful.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own, as
well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 580:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry launched himself across the floor and grabbed the Death Eater
around the knees, causing him to topple and his aim to go awry.
Neville overturned a desk in his anxiety to help; and pointing his
wand wildly at the struggling pair, he cried:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;EXPELLIARMUS!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Harry&amp;rsquo;s and the Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wands flew out of their hands and
soared back towards the entrance to the Hall of Prophecy; both
scrambled to their feet and charged after them, the Death Eater in
front, Harry hot on his heels, and Neville bringing up the rear,
plainly horrorstruck by what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt; 582:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry fell to his knees beside her as Neville crawled rapidly
towards her from under the desk, his wand held up in front of
him. The Death Eater kicked out hard at Neville&amp;rsquo;s head as he
emerged&amp;mdash;his foot broke Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand in two and connected with
his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably counts as a disarming. Neville&amp;rsquo;s wands must have
finally realized how inept he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dolohov&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own (Neville&amp;rsquo;s is destroyed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s,
Sirius&amp;rsquo;, Millicent&amp;rsquo;s and Warrington&amp;rsquo;s wands, along with his own new
wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own, as
well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing (the Creeveys have all the books).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; has an epic mustache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt; 95:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I thought Gran would be angry about all the publicity,&amp;rdquo; said
Neville, &amp;ldquo;but she was really pleased. Says I&amp;rsquo;m starting to live up
to my dad at long last. She bought me a new wand, look!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pulled it out and showed it to Harry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cherry and unicorn hair,&amp;rdquo; he said proudly. &amp;ldquo;We think it was one of
the last Ollivander ever sold, he vanished next day&amp;mdash;oi, come back
here, Trevor!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand and does not have Trevor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt; 387&amp;ndash;388:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry hurried over to the door leading to the spiral staircase, but
his hand had only just closed upon the iron ring of the door when he
heard running footsteps on the other side.  He looked round at
Dumbledore, who gestured to him to retreat.  Harry backed away,
drawing his wand as he did so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door burst open and somebody erupted through it and shouted
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s body became instantly rigid and immobile, and he felt
himself fall back against the Tower wall, propped like an unsteady
statue, unable to move or speak. He could not understand how it had
happened&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; was not a Freezing Charm&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, by the light of the Mark, he saw Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s wand flying in
an arc over the edge of the ramparts and understood &amp;hellip; Dumbledore
had wordlessly immobilised Harry, and the second he had taken to
perform the spell had cost him the chance of defending himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oooh, this is the important one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s, and his
own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt; 400:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Potter!&amp;rdquo; screamed Snape. There was a loud BANG and Harry was
soaring backwards, hitting the ground hard again, and this time his
wand flew out of his hand. He could hear Hagrid yelling and Fang
howling as Snape closed in and looked down on him where he lay,
wandless and defenceless as Dumbledore had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La la la, Harry doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a wand. But here we can at least
appreciate how J.K. uses all caps to great effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to repeat everyone&amp;rsquo;s wand ownership status again
because not much changed and this damn thing is getting so long. But
we&amp;rsquo;re almost done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 49:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry sent Stunning Spell after Stunning Spell back at their
pursuers, barely holding them off.  He shot another blocking jinx at
them: the closest Death Eater swerved to avoid it and his hood
slipped, and by the red light of his next Stunning Spell, Harry saw
the strangely blank face of Stanley Shunpike&amp;mdash;Stan&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Harry yelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Stan&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The youngest-ever Minister of Magic&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 50:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the pain from Harry&amp;rsquo;s scar forced his eyes shut, his wand acted
of its own accord.  He felt it drag his hand round like some great
magnet, saw a spurt of golden fire through his half-closed eyelids,
heard a crack and a scream of fury.  The remaining Death Eater
yelled; Voldemort screamed, &amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for sure a disarming. But Voldy&amp;rsquo;s using Lucius Malfoy&amp;rsquo;s wand,
so does Harry own that wand now? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so, because Lucius
wasn&amp;rsquo;t really disarmed. He was &lt;em&gt;coerced&lt;/em&gt; to give Voldemort his wand,
sure, but that probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 152:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mundungus scrambled up and pulled out his wand; Hermione, however,
was too quick for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mundungus&amp;rsquo;s wand soared into the air and Hermione caught it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mundungus&lt;/strong&gt; still has his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 287:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophilius licked his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They took my Luna,&amp;rdquo; he whispered. &amp;ldquo;Because of what I’ve been
writing. They took my Luna and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where she is, what
they&amp;rsquo;ve done to her. But they might give her back to me if I&amp;mdash;if
I&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we learn later, Luna lost her wand when she got pulled off the
Hogwarts Express.  Presumably a Death Eater took it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and Luna&amp;rsquo;s and
his own wands, as well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 305&amp;ndash;306:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get up, vermin.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknown hands dragged Harry roughly off the ground. Before he could
stop them, someone had rummaged through his pockets and removed the
blackthorn wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get&amp;mdash;off&amp;mdash;her!&amp;rdquo; Ron shouted.  There was the unmistakable sound of
knuckles hitting flesh: Ron grunted in pain and Hermione screamed,
&amp;ldquo;No! Leave him alone, leave him alone!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your boyfriend&amp;rsquo;s going to have worse than that done to him if he&amp;rsquo;s
on my list,&amp;rdquo; said the horribly familiar, rasping voice.  &amp;ldquo;Delicious
girl &amp;hellip; what a treat &amp;hellip; I do enjoy the softness of the skin &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone still got a wand?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; said Ron and Hermione from either side of him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, crap.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got even less to go on here than in Umbridge&amp;rsquo;s
office.  Greyback is the head of this band of Snatchers, so it might
be reasonable to assume that he&amp;rsquo;s just giving orders and not actually
disarming anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn a few pages later that Harry was disarmed by Scabior:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know &amp;lsquo;e&amp;rsquo;s swollen, ma&amp;rsquo;am, but it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;im!&amp;rdquo; piped up Scabior.  &amp;ldquo;If
you look a bit closer, you&amp;rsquo;ll see &amp;lsquo;is scar.  And this &amp;lsquo;ere, see the
girl?  The Mudblood who&amp;rsquo;s been travelling around with &amp;lsquo;im,
ma&amp;rsquo;am.  There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;im, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got &amp;lsquo;is wand as well!
&amp;lsquo;Ere, ma&amp;rsquo;am&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Narcissa Malfoy scrutinising his swollen face.  Scabior
thrust the blackthorn wand at her.  She raised her eyebrows (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt;
311).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think all we can say is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scabior&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand (hahaha holy shit if he only knew).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 1&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 2&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s, Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s,
Ginny&amp;rsquo;s, Sirius&amp;rsquo;, and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 3&lt;/strong&gt; has Dean&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands (Dean is picked by the
same group of Snatchers).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a bang and a flash of red light: Harry knew that the
Snatcher had been Stunned. There was a roar of anger from his
fellows: Scabior drew his wand.  &amp;ldquo;What d&amp;rsquo;you think you&amp;rsquo;re playing
at, woman?&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; she screamed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were no match for her, even though there were four of them
against one of her: she was a witch, as Harry knew, with prodigious
skill and no conscience. They fell where they stood, all except
Greyback, who had been forced into a kneeling position, his arms
outstretched. Out of the corners of his eyes, Harry saw Bellatrix
bearing down upon the werewolf, the sword of Gryffindor gripped
tightly in her hand, her face waxen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where did you get this sword?&amp;rdquo; she whispered to Greyback as she
pulled his wand out of his unresisting grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really too bad that Greyback didn&amp;rsquo;t disarm Harry et al., instead
of Scabior and the other idiot Snatchers. Too bad Bellatrix didn&amp;rsquo;t
disarm instead of stun them. Then she would have &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. Oh
well; the truth is sacred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greyback&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 320:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And we&amp;rsquo;ll have that,&amp;rdquo; whispered Ron, tugging Wormtail&amp;rsquo;s wand from
his other hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ollivander says this should work, but Barty Crouch Jr. owns Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s
wand, so Ron&amp;rsquo;s out of luck. &lt;strong&gt;No changes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 321:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron had burst into the drawing room; Bellatrix looked round,
shocked; she turned her wand to face Ron instead&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he roared, pointing Wormtail&amp;rsquo;s wand at Bellatrix,
and hers flew into the air and was caught by Harry, who had sprinted
after Ron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ronnie the Bear shows his quality!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yeah, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking: Harry caught the wand, so are we
sure &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t own it? Pretty sure. If Filch had caught the Elder
wand as it fell from the tower when Dumbledore was disarmed, would he
have been the true owner of the Elder Wand?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s and Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 322:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chandelier crashed to the floor in an explosion of crystal and
chains, falling on top of Hermione and the goblin, who still
clutched the sword of Gryffindor.  Glittering shards of crystal flew
in all directions: Draco doubled over, his hands covering his bloody
face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ron ran to pull Hermione out of the wreckage, Harry took his
chance; he leapt over an armchair and wrested the three wands from
Draco&amp;rsquo;s grip, pointed all of them at Greyback and yelled:
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; The werewolf was lifted off his feet by the triple
spell, flew up to the ceiling and then smashed to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, damn, it looks like J.K. Rowling&amp;rsquo;s wacky scheme might work!
Draco was holding his, Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s, and Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Draco&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, and Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 322:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kill him, Cissy!&amp;rdquo; shrieked Bellatrix, but there was another loud
&lt;em&gt;crack&lt;/em&gt;, and Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand, too, flew into the air and landed on the
other side of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You dirty little monkey!&amp;rdquo; bawled Bellatrix.  &amp;ldquo;How dare you take a
witch&amp;rsquo;s wand, how dare you defy your masters?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dobby&lt;/strong&gt; has Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NO MASTER&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narcissa&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 351:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Ollivander had sent Luna a new wand that morning. She was out on
the back lawn at that moment, testing its capabilities in the late
afternoon sun. Dean, who had lost his wand to the Snatchers, was
watching rather gloomily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has her new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands as well as Luna&amp;rsquo;s old wands, and Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 425:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s that Mudblood! &lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Hermione dive aside and his fury that Crabbe had aimed to
kill wiped all else from his mind.  He shot a Stunning Spell at Crabbe,
who lurched out of the way, knocking Malfoy&amp;rsquo;s wand out of his hand; it
rolled out of sight beneath a mountain of broken furniture and boxes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t kill him!  DON&amp;rsquo;T KILL HIM!&amp;rdquo;  Malfoy yelled at Crabbe and
Goyle, who were both aiming at Harry: their split second&amp;rsquo;s
hesitation was all Harry needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyle&amp;rsquo;s wand flew out of his hand and disappeared into the bulwark
of objects beside him; Goyle leapt foolishly on the spot, trying to
retrieve it; Malfoy jumped out of range of Hermione&amp;rsquo;s second
Stunning Spell and Ron, appearing suddenly at the end of the aisle,
shot a full Body-Bind Curse at Crabbe, which narrowly missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draco didn&amp;rsquo;t really own his mother&amp;rsquo;s wand, and he certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t
own his own, so Crabbe doesn&amp;rsquo;t get anything out of disarming his
boss. But he&amp;rsquo;s about to die, so that&amp;rsquo;s really the least of his
worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goyle&lt;/strong&gt; has his health, which is more than we can say for
Crabbe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 442:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Kill&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a terrible scream. Harry saw Snape&amp;rsquo;s face losing the
little colour it had left, it whitened as his black eyes widened, as
the snake&amp;rsquo;s fangs pierced his neck, as he failed to push the
enchanted cage off himself, as his knees gave way, and he fell to
the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I regret it,&amp;rdquo; said Voldemort coldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned away; there was no sadness in him, no remorse.  It was
time to leave this shack and take charge, with a wand that would now
do his full bidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahahaha, Snape hasn&amp;rsquo;t owned a wand since the last time he was in the
Shrieking Shack, way back in the third book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a real disarming. But if we can trust Voldemort, the
ownership of the Wand of Destiny can be transferred through killing:
&amp;ldquo;The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard who killed its last owner&amp;rdquo;
(&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 441). Perhaps this quality is exclusive to the Elder Wand. If
Snape had any non-Elder wands, Voldemort might not have won them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;no changes&lt;/strong&gt; occur, because neither of these jerks have wands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 489:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Voldemort broke off: Harry heard a scuffle and a shout, then
another bang, a flash of light and a grunt of pain; he opened his
eyes an infinitesimal amount. Someone had broken free of the crowd
and charged at Voldemort: Harry saw the figure hit the ground,
Disarmed, Voldemort throwing the challenger&amp;rsquo;s wand aside and laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And who is this?&amp;rdquo; he said, in his soft snake&amp;rsquo;s hiss. &amp;ldquo;Who has
volunteered to demonstrate what happens to those who continue to
fight when the battle is lost?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bellatrix gave a delighted laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is Neville Longbottom, my Lord! The boy who has been giving the
Carrows so much trouble! The son of the Aurors, remember?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t throw Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand away, idiot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 497&amp;ndash;498:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A red-gold glow burst suddenly across the enchanted sky above them,
as an edge of dazzling sun appeared over the sill of the nearest
window.  The light hit both of their faces at the same time, so that
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s was suddenly a flaming blur.  Harry heard the high voice
shriek as he, too, yelled his best hope to the heavens, pointing
Draco&amp;rsquo;s wand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bang was like a cannon-blast and the golden flames that erupted
between them, at the dead centre of the circle they had been
treading, marked the point where the spells collided. Harry saw
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s green jet meet his own spell, saw the Elder Wand fly
high, dark against the sunrise, spinning across the enchanted ceiling
like the head of Nagini, spinning through the air towards the master
it would not kill, who had come to take full possession of it at
last. And Harry, with the unerring skill of the Seeker, caught the
wand in his free hand as Voldemort fell backwards, arms splayed, the
slit pupils of the scarlet eyes rolling upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like Harry is the master of the Elder Wand, after all. But this
whole thing still doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, and Harry really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
have thrown away the Elder Wand afterward since he doesn&amp;rsquo;t own his
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands, and Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing (and is dead).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;The final tally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands, and Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goyle&lt;/strong&gt; has his health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has her new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands as well as Luna&amp;rsquo;s old wands, and Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dobby&lt;/strong&gt; has Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand and no master.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narcissa&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s and Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wands and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greyback&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scabior&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 1&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 2&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s, Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Sirius&amp;rsquo; and his own
wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 3&lt;/strong&gt; has Dean&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mundungus&lt;/strong&gt; has his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stan&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dolohov&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; has an epic mustache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Page numbers are from the Pottermore [UK] ebooks.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>