<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Philosophy on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/philosophy/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2013-04-27 00:00:00 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;It is too late, you understand me?&#8221;: Time travel in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/time</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/time</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here at &lt;em&gt;Baruffio&lt;/em&gt; we sometimes cast a critical eye on &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter,&lt;/em&gt;
and amuse ourselves by pointing out inconsistencies in the books (then
&lt;a href=&#34;/p/trace&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s no Such
Thing as the Trace&#34;&gt;weaving them into conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;).  But time travel in &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; is a
model of consistency, illustrating wonderfully how time travel
works&amp;mdash;if it&amp;rsquo;s possible at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The past is past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumbledore held up his hand to stem the flood of explanations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;It is your turn to listen, and I beg you will not interrupt me,
because there is very little time,&amp;rsquo; he said quietly. &amp;lsquo;There is not a
shred of proof to support Black&amp;rsquo;s story, except your word&amp;mdash;and the
word of two thirteen-year-old wizards will not convince anybody. A
street full of eye-witnesses swore they saw Sirius murder
Pettigrew. I myself gave evidence to the Ministry that Sirius had
been the Potters&amp;rsquo; Secret Keeper.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Professor Lupin can tell you&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo; Harry said, unable to stop himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Professor Lupin is currently deep in the Forest, unable to tell
anyone anything. By the time he is human again, it will be too late,
Sirius will be worse than dead. I might add that werewolves are so
mistrusted by most of our kind that his support will count for very
little&amp;mdash;and the fact that he and Sirius are old friends&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Listen to me, Harry&lt;/em&gt;. It is too late, you understand me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just so everyone&amp;rsquo;s on the same page, let&amp;rsquo;s review the events that lead
up to this conversation.  Hermione finds Scabbers the rat in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s
cabin, and she, Harry, Ron, and Scabbers leave &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the execution
of Buckbeat the Hippogriff is scheduled to take place&amp;mdash;at sunset.
Sirius Black, in his Animagus form of a dog, drags Ron into the secret
passage under the Whomping Willow, and Ron takes Scabbers with him.
Crookshanks hits a switch at the base of the Willow and freezes it,
allowing him and Harry and Hermione to follow Sirius, Ron, and
Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupin follows them into the Shrieking Shack, and then Snape comes soon
after&amp;mdash;maybe 20 minutes after sunset.  He finds the Invisibility
Cloak that Harry dropped and enters the Shrieking Shack, but is
stunned and never sees Pettigrew.  Lupin convinces Harry, Ron, and
Hermione of Sirius&amp;rsquo; innocence; Pettigrew is revealed and forced to
admit that he, not Sirius, betrayed Harry&amp;rsquo;s parents to Voldemort.
Then the whole party exists the Whomping Willow, intending to take
Pettigrew up to Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the full moon is out.  Lupin transforms into a werewolf, Pettigrew
escapes, and Harry, Hermione, and Sirius are surrounded by Dementors
and fall unconscious.  When Harry and Hermione wake up in the hospital
wing, Sirius is locked in a room upstairs and Cornelius Fudge has
ordered that he recieve the Dementor&amp;rsquo;s Kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Dumbledore speaks with Harry and Hermione&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>