<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Hogwarts on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/hogwarts/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2013-11-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are ways to stop even a Hufflepuff from finding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so&amp;mdash;apparently&amp;mdash;incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not immediately obvious how this is possible.  Some of the
simpler and more obvious proposals as to how Unplottability might work
turn out to be no good.  Unplottability cannot not say anything about
what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of paper.  It&amp;rsquo;s possible with
magic to prevent the information from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted,&lt;/em&gt; but this
won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work is something more drastic: Unplottability has to
prevent us from &lt;em&gt;inferring&lt;/em&gt; the location of a place from other
information.  The benefit of this radical solution is that it
preserves the spirit of Unplottability, which is prevent people from
figuring out where Hogwarts is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on&amp;mdash;how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; 121; page references are
from the UK versions of the &lt;em&gt;Pottermore&lt;/em&gt; ebooks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists or whatever, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point here.
Just what on earth does it &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; for something to be Unplottable?
(The text is silent on whether Hogwarts itself is Unplottable, but
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaiaonline.com/forum/harry-potter/if-hogwarts-castle-is-unplottable/t.13491169_15/#15&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;If Hogwarts castle is unplottable...\&amp;quot; at Gaia Online&#34;&gt;Durmstrang is&lt;/a&gt;, and so it&amp;rsquo;s likely that Hogwarts is as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;I can draw a map and write &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; on it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above I said that Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t say anything about what I can
or can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of paper.  More precisely, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to
stop me from encoding certain information on a map.  But why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how someone might try to prevent us from encoding that
sort of information.  Whatever they do, I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;ll manage
it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose a witch or wizard managed to cast an enchantment that had
the following effect: whenever someone writes &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; (or
something sufficiently similar) at roughly the point where Hogwarts
is located on a map, the enchantment erases what you&amp;rsquo;ve written.
This obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, because you could refer to
Hogwarts using a different name.  This is a ban on &lt;em&gt;using
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; to refer to Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;.  It is not a ban on plotting
Hogwarts on a map.  If I am trying to make you a map with Hogwarts
on it, I could tell you &amp;ldquo;I will write &amp;lsquo;Pigfarts&amp;rsquo; instead of
&amp;lsquo;Hogwarts&amp;rsquo;&amp;ldquo;, and then when I write &amp;ldquo;Pigfarts&amp;rdquo;, I am plotting
Hogwarts on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second problem with this approach is that if the enchantment
only detects when I&amp;rsquo;ve written &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;, my writing will be
visible until I finish that string of letters.  If you are
watching over my shoulder as I work, you will see me get at least
as far as &amp;ldquo;Hogwart&amp;rdquo; and will probably infer my intention (to plot
Hogwarts on this map), and the enchantment will be foiled.  In
order to work, the enchantment would have to determine our
&lt;em&gt;intentions&lt;/em&gt; and act before we can even start writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of &lt;em&gt;intention&lt;/em&gt; brings us to a second possible method
to make it impossible to encode information about a place&amp;rsquo;s
location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose it&amp;rsquo;s possible, somehow, to determine when I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;intending&lt;/em&gt;
to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Maybe an enchantment could figure out
when I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about Hogwarts in a certain way while mapmaking,
or whatever.  When this happens, the enchantment makes me forget
what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, or triggers something like the Tongue-Tying Curse
except for writing, or in some other way prevents me from
fulfilling my intention to plot Hogwarts on a map.  Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
this work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work because it&amp;rsquo;s possible for someone to make
something that &lt;em&gt;functions&lt;/em&gt; as a map showing the location of
Hogwarts without intending to.  Suppose a Muggle child is drawing
fake maps for fun and &lt;em&gt;accidentally&lt;/em&gt; draws one with a castle in
just the right place on an accurate representation of the Scottish
highlands.  It&amp;rsquo;s even possible that&amp;mdash;by a massive
coincidence&amp;mdash;the child could decide to label this castle
&amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a sense in which this Muggle child
hasn&amp;rsquo;t really plotted Hogwarts on a map, the following scenario
could still occur, if this is all Unplottability amounts to: the
child drops their map while leaving King&amp;rsquo;s Cross, and it is picked
up by a witch or wizard, who has been seeking the location of
Hogwarts.  They assume that someone plotted Hogwarts on a map and
then dropped it.  They guide themselves using this map, and as a
result arrive at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first solution was obviously insufficient, in part because it
failed to account for a mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s intention.  But in our examination
of the second solution, we can see that accounting for the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
intention won&amp;rsquo;t work either.  Our scenario, involving the child
serendipitously writing &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; in exactly the right place on a map
of the Scottish highlands, might be a scenario in which it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;strictly
false&lt;/em&gt; that Hogwarts was plotted on a map, but the spirit of the idea
has clearly been violated.  The &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of unplottability is to keep
people from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; maps to locate Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we should look next at how a witch or wizard would &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; a map to
find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;But I can&amp;rsquo;t use that map to find Hogwarts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crucial detail of our scenario above was that the witch or wizard
who finds the child&amp;rsquo;s map &lt;em&gt;assumes&lt;/em&gt; that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot
Hogwarts on their map.  They believe&amp;mdash;incorrectly, in this
case&amp;mdash;that the map was written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  The
witch or wizard believes&amp;mdash;again incorrectly&amp;mdash;that they &lt;em&gt;recognize
the communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to communicate to
the reader the location of Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose our witch or wizard had not made this mistake.  Suppose they
overheard the Muggle child taking about the map before dropping it,
and realized that it was pure coincidence that led the child to label
a map with &amp;ldquo;Hogwarts&amp;rdquo;.  If the witch or wizard nonetheless picked up
the map, they would not mistake it for a map showing the location of
Hogwarts because they would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; take themselves to recognize the
author&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.  They would not think that the map
was written with a communicative intent.  They would not learn
anything from the map because they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is
anything to learn.  Information transmission of this sort requires the
belief in a communicative intention, and when this is missing it will
not occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this was how Unplottability works, even if a witch or wizard finds
a map on which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of
Unplottability would be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s
communicative intention.  The reader would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are
reading a map showing the location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in
a situation similar to the witch or wizard who knows that they are
looking at the scrawlings of a Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the Muggle child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but that&amp;rsquo;s no objection to the theory: it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an objection to this theory (which was
brought to my attention by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and
therefore&amp;mdash;because we used the Map to find the relative location of
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking that this loophole probably only affects
Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  So who cares, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just consist in preventing me from recognizing
a communicative intention.  It has to be something more, if it&amp;rsquo;s going
to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, and if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, therefore &amp;hellip; what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/docs/unplottable.html&#34;&gt;earlier version&lt;/a&gt; of this
essay concluded that Unplottability was impossible.  Jacob T. Levy,
Tomlinson Professor of Political Theory at McGill University, found
that pessimism unwarranted and proposed a solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s easy;just use an SEP field! Interfere with the intention to *either* draw a map or use a map (or 2 maps)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429670387501117441&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; This combines #2 and #3 w rule that if I try to put Marauder&amp;#39;s Map &amp;amp; Hogsmeade maps together I... ooh! shiny!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429671149165752320&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An S.E.P., or Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s Problem, field,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hitchhikers.wikia.com/wiki/Somebody_Else&#34; title=&#34;s_Problem_field
&amp;quot;Hitchhiker Wiki&#34;&gt;utilizes a person&amp;rsquo;s natural tendency to ignore things they don&amp;rsquo;t easily accept&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by causing them to simply &lt;em&gt;ignore&lt;/em&gt; certain
information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any object around which a S.E.P. [field] is applied will cease to be
noticed, because any problems one may have understanding it (and
therefore accepting its existence) become Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s. An object
becomes not so much invisible as unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect example of this would be a ship covered in a S.E.P. field at
a cricket match. A star ship taking the appearance of a large pink
elephant is ideal &amp;hellip; you can see it, but because it is so
inconceivable, your mind can&amp;rsquo;t accept it. Therefore it can&amp;rsquo;t exist,
thus [you ignore it].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proposal raises difficult and delicate questions in the
philosophy of mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to answer.  But it also
suggests an even simpler solution: whenever I try to infer &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; some
pieces of information &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts, the
Unplottability enchantment blocks that inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walk from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, measuring the distance, I may
end up with this bit of knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I walked 1km, northwest, from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be obvious at first, but just knowing that does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean
that one automatically knows this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hogwarts is 1km southeast of Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; (2) from (1), but I have to know some other things as
well.  Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;i&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walk a certain distance from point &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; to point &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is that far from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is a certain distance from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is the same distance from &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is northwest of &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is southeast of &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course all these things are &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;, so we don&amp;rsquo;t usually think
about how we rely on them for drawing equally obvious conclusions like
(2).  But we do rely on them, and we also rely on &lt;em&gt;inference rules&lt;/em&gt;
that allow us to move from our premises to our conclusion.  For
example, just to conclude that Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade, I have
to reason like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore&lt;/em&gt;, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore&amp;rdquo; marks the point at which I make an inference.  If I
somehow fail to see that there is a valid inference to be made, I may
be left with only the first two pieces of information, not knowing
whether Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I suggest, is exactly the situation I will be in, because the
Unplottability enchantment will prevent me from making inferences
that would allow me to learn the location of Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>