<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Harry on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/harry/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-03-23 12:00:00 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&amp;#8217;s no such thing as the Trace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/trace</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 12:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/trace</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Much is made in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; about &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;, the charm on
underage witches and wizards that is used by the Ministry to detect
illegal spellwork.  The problem is that there is no such thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo; supposed to be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second problem: you&amp;rsquo;re under-age, which means you&amp;rsquo;ve still got the
Trace on you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Trace, the Trace!&amp;rdquo; said Mad-Eye impatiently.  &amp;ldquo;The charm that
detects magical activity around under-seventeens, the way the
Ministry finds out about under-age magic!  If you, or anyone around
you, casts a spell to get you out of here, Thicknesse is going to
know about it, and so will the Death Eaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the Trace to break, because the moment you turn
seventeen you&amp;rsquo;ll lose all the protection your mother gave you.  In
short: Pius Thicknesse thinks he&amp;rsquo;s got you cornered good and
proper.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry could not help but agree with the unknown Thicknesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So what are we going to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to use the only means of transport left to us, the only
ones the Trace can&amp;rsquo;t detect, because we don&amp;rsquo;t need to cast spells to
use them: brooms, Thestrals and Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s motorbike&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 40
[page numbers from the UK Pottermore editions]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trace apparently allows the Ministry to know &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; about the
location of underage wizards, in order to determine if they are
breaking the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage
Sorcery.  The Ministry has separate, unspecified ways of knowing when
and where magic is performed in the United Kingdom; the Trace does
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; specifically tell the Ministry when an underage witch or wizard
&lt;em&gt;performs&lt;/em&gt; magic.  The Trace, in conjunction with the aforementioned
unspecified magic detection mechanisms, allows the Ministry to know
when magic is performed in close proximity to an underage witch or
wizard (the canny reader will see from the above quote that there&amp;rsquo;s
already a problem; but we&amp;rsquo;ll come to that).  This is what leads to the
Ministry issuing Harry with a warning when Dobby explodes a cake in #4
Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Mr Potter,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have received intelligence that a Hover Charm was used at your
place of residence this evening at twelve minutes past nine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As you know, underage wizards are not permitted to perform spells
outside school, and further spellwork on your part may lead to
expulsion from said school (Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of
Underage Sorcery, 1875, Paragraph C).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would also ask you to remember that any magical activity which
risks notice by members of the non-magical community (Muggles) is a
serious offence, under section 13 of the International Confederation
of Warlocks&amp;rsquo; Statute of Secrecy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy your holidays!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mafalda Hopkirk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improper Use of Magic Office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ministry of Magic&lt;/em&gt;  (&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, sadly, this is all a terrible vicious lie.  The Trace does not
exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t it exist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;, Dumbledore shows Harry the recorded memory
of Morfin&amp;rsquo;s meeting with Voldemort.  Dumbledore explains that it is
nearly certain that Voldemort Stunned Morfin, took his wand, and
murdered the Riddle family.  Harry points out a rather large problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But how come the Ministry didn&amp;rsquo;t realise that Voldemort had done
all that to Morfin?&amp;rdquo; Harry asked angrily.  &amp;ldquo;He was under age at the
time, wasn&amp;rsquo;t he?  I thought they could detect under-age magic!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are quite right&amp;mdash;they can detect magic, but not the
perpetrator: you will remember that you were blamed by the Ministry
for the Hover Charm that was, in fact, cast by&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dobby,&amp;rdquo; growled Harry; this injustice still rankled.  &amp;ldquo;So if you&amp;rsquo;re
under age and you do magic inside an adult witch or wizard&amp;rsquo;s house,
the Ministry won&amp;rsquo;t know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They will certainly be unable to tell who performed the magic,&amp;rdquo;
said Dumbledore, smiling slightly at the look of great indignation
on Harry&amp;rsquo;s face.  &amp;ldquo;They rely on witch and wizard parents to enforce
their offspring&amp;rsquo;s obedience while within their walls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s rubbish,&amp;rdquo; snapped Harry. &amp;ldquo;Look what happened here,
look what happened to Morfin!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we basically already knew that because of the Dobby thing.  We
already know why Voldemort didn&amp;rsquo;t get in trouble for doing magic at
the Gaunt House.  But &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;there were no other witches or wizards at the
Riddle house when Voldemort killed them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  How did the Ministry fail
to notice &lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter
Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;three uses of Avada Kedavra by a sixteen-year old in a
Muggle home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few theories have surfaced to explain this inconsistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Talk:The_Trace#As_to_the_inconsistency_regarding_Tom_Riddle...&#34; title=&#34;Talk page for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot; on the Harry Potter Wikia&#34;&gt;Voldemort was not underage when he killed the Riddles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cedric Diggory was 17 in his sixth year, allowing him to enter the
Triwizard Tournament.  Wikia user Thanksherman proposes that
Voldemort was similarly old for his age, allowing him to come of
age and act without the Trace in his sixth year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this theory is twofold: Not only does Dumbledore
not contradict Harry above when Harry asks how Voldemort could
have done magic without it being detected by the Ministry,
Dumbledore explicitly claims that Voldemort was then Harry&amp;rsquo;s
age&amp;mdash;and Harry wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn 17 for some time.  When discussing
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s conversation with Horace Slughorn (which occurs after
the Riddle House incident), Dumbledore says to Harry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am sure you understood the significance of what we just
heard.  At the same age as you are now, give or take a few
months, Tom Riddle was doing all he could to find out how to
make himself immortal&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt; 332).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trace works in strange ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only sketchy descriptions of the Trace in the books,
leaving open the possibility that the Trace works in unintuitive
ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that the Trace breaks when a witch or wizard
turns 17, and the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Muggles%27_Guide_to_Harry_Potter/Magic/Underage_Sorcery#Analysis&#34; title=&#34;Wikibooks: Muggles&#39; Guide to Harry Potter---Underage Sorcery&#34;&gt;keep tabs on the locations of adult wizards&lt;/a&gt;;
otherwise in &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt; they would have chased after any
adult witches and wizards found in odd locations; Harry, Ron, and
Hermione would have been caught in short order.  (How the hell they
know that Harry casts his Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;in
the presence of a Muggle&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Dudley&amp;mdash;would be another troubling
question, if the Trace exists.  But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Ministry can&amp;rsquo;t track the locations of underage witches and
wizards &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;d be forgiven for thinking so, since as
much is implied in &lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wondered,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione tentatively, &amp;ldquo;whether Harry could
still have the Trace on him?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Impossible,&amp;rdquo; said Lupin. Ron looked smug, and Harry felt hugely
relieved. &amp;ldquo;Apart from anything else, they&amp;rsquo;d know for sure Harry
was here if he still had the Trace on him, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they? But I
can&amp;rsquo;t see how they could have tracked you to Tottenham Court
Road, that&amp;rsquo;s worrying, really worrying&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 143).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the quote at the very beginning of this essay, Moody states
explicitly that the Ministry &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; track underage witches and
wizards.  If they could, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether Harry traveled
from Privet Drive by Portkey, Thestral, broom, or Apparition.  And
in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;, Scrimgeour asks Harry where he went with Dumbledore
before the latter&amp;rsquo;s death, something he would know if the Trace
allowed the Ministry to actually track underage witches and
wizards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; can the Ministry know whether a bit
of magic, performed near a Traced person, is plausibly underage
sorcery or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry might keep a list of underage wizards &lt;em&gt;known to be
alone&lt;/em&gt; or otherwise without magical supervision.  Harry would fall
in this category, as well as Muggleborns and other special cases
(like Voldemort at the orphanage).  Warnings are only sent when
magic is performed in the vicinity of these people&amp;rsquo;s homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this this just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem true: when the Advance Guard
removes Harry from Privet Drive, Tonks casts several spells,
apparently with no repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace#Limitations&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;, section on
\&amp;quot;Limitations\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;usual reply here&lt;/a&gt; is that the Ministry is notified when adult
witches and wizards (Arthur Weasley in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;,
Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;) are going to visit.  The Ministry then
supposedly ignores magic for the duration of the visit.  But the
Ministry does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know that the Advance Guard removed Harry from
Privet Drive.  Allowing the &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; to take Harry
to the home of &lt;em&gt;Sirius Black&lt;/em&gt; does not seem like something the
Fudge administration would do.  Moreover, during Harry&amp;rsquo;s
disciplinary hearing, it&amp;rsquo;s made explicit that the Ministry
believes him to be still residing at Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry,&amp;rdquo; said Harry nervously.  &amp;ldquo;I&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the time
had been changed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That is not the Wizengamot&amp;rsquo;s fault,&amp;rdquo; said the voice. &amp;ldquo;An
owl was sent to you this morning. Take your seat&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;
108).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there&amp;rsquo;s some wiggle-room here as well; Fudge and
Umbridge are trying to get Harry expelled, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible they
arranged to have the letter sent to the wrong address.  But if
they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; figure out that Harry was living at #12 Grimmauld
Place, the Noble and Most Ancient House of Black, they would
surely suspect him of having contact with the last Black family
member (a fine excuse to detain him for questioning and
harassment).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No way is there such a thing as &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s really going on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, why does everyone think it does?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the characters in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; are pretty stupid.  Dumbledore
&lt;em&gt;tells&lt;/em&gt; Harry that underage witches and wizards can do magic in the
home of an adult witch or wizard, and Harry &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t do magic
at the Burrow until he turns 17 and gets all excited.  Dumbledore
nearly allows Katie Bell &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Ron to die because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like
confronting Malfoy about his whole assassination plan in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood
Prince&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron never realized he&amp;rsquo;s allowed to do magic at home and
peels sprouts by hand for 17 years.  Hermione&amp;rsquo;s pretty smart I guess,
but she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really show a strong understanding of the Trace
either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; stretch to assume that it&amp;rsquo;s a lie spread by the
(equally inept) Ministry to control the magical population.  The
Ministry is too stupid to actually implement the Trace, and the rest
are stupid enough to believe in it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But questions remain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Dobby&amp;rsquo;s Hover Charm in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Aunt Marge&amp;rsquo;s big mistake, in order
to send people to Privet Drive to deflate her?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did Ministry learn about Harry&amp;rsquo;s Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the
Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best guess at an answer to all three is &amp;hellip; Mrs Figg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Whaaaaaa?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I don&amp;rsquo;t like these sorts of conspiracy theories either.  But
she&amp;rsquo;s always near Privet Drive, and the only not-obviously-canon claim
I&amp;rsquo;m making is that she works for the Ministry rather than for
Dumbledore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;mdash;or one of her cats&amp;mdash;saw the Hover Charm (whether or not they
saw Dobby), saw Marge explode, and saw the Patronus.  She did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
see the Weasleys travel to the Dursley&amp;rsquo;s by Floo Powder, or see the
Advance Guard arrive in &lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, or Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;.  Maybe she was
asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the books state that she &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see the Patronus, and so she could
have communicated with the Ministry immediately after (using her own
Patronus&amp;mdash;if she&amp;rsquo;s only pretending to be a Squib&amp;mdash;or using a mirror
like the one Sirius gives to Harry or a Protean-Charmed object like
the DA coins).  That situation was already suspicious, because she
claims that she knew about Mundungus running off right away, but
didn&amp;rsquo;t bother contacting Harry and telling him to stay inside.  So
either she was lying about that, or knew Mundungus left to buy
cauldrons but had Ministry orders not to warn Harry (the Dementors
&lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; sent by Umbridge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose Mrs Figg was spying on Harry for the Ministry because he&amp;rsquo;s
important and the Ministry wants to keep tabs on him.  Other
high-profile witches and wizards presumably get the same treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;An objection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might cry: &amp;ldquo;But surely a simpler explanation is just as you
said&amp;mdash;the Ministry is inept!  It&amp;rsquo;s not that the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist,
but rather the Ministry is just really bad about following up on the
instances of magic it detects.  Depending on how the Trace works,
either they just didn&amp;rsquo;t notice Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s magic performed at the
Riddle House, or they failed to see that Tonks cast &lt;em&gt;Lumos&lt;/em&gt; and some
stupid trunk-packing spell when the Advance Guard came to get Harry.
See, no need to drag poor Mrs Figg into your wild imagination!&amp;rdquo;  (This
objection is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zayalhawa&#34; title=&#34;Twitter
profile&#34;&gt;Aziza&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be a better explanation, but for one thing.  As I noted
above, when the Ministry takes Harry to task for his Patronus in
&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, they know something that only Mrs Figg (or another spy) could
know: that Harry performed magic in the presence of a Muggle: Dudley.
If the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t track the relatively small adult magical
population, the idea that they might be tracking all Muggles is pretty
wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they be tracking just a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; Muggles of importance?&amp;rdquo;
Dudley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; important, though; he already knows about magic, so
seeing &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; magic isn&amp;rsquo;t a major breach of the Statute of Secrecy.
The Ministry just &lt;em&gt;pretends&lt;/em&gt; it is while they&amp;rsquo;re trying to expel
Harry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>