<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ps on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/p/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-06-19 20:00:00 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philosopher&#8217;s Stoned: an Opinionated Introduction to Proper Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/names</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 20:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/names</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Snape was wrong when he suggested that the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is &amp;ldquo;plainly
full of Dark Magic,&amp;rdquo; but it really is a remarkably powerful artifact
and it&amp;rsquo;s not at all obvious how it works.  How does it know your name,
in order to label your dot as it tracks you throughout the castle?  To
figure that out, we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to start from the beginning, and
figure out what names even &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;, and how &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sonorous!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map and how does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a map showing every detail of the Hogwarts castle and
 grounds. But the truly remarkable thing was the tiny ink dots
 moving around it, each labelled with a name in minuscule
 writing. Astounded, Harry bent over it. A labelled dot in the top
 left corner showed that Professor Dumbledore was pacing his study;
 the caretaker&amp;rsquo;s cat, Mrs Norris, was prowling the second floor, and
 Peeves the poltergeist was currently bouncing around the trophy
 room (&lt;em&gt;PoA&lt;/em&gt;, Chapter 10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea here is pretty straightforward: the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a map
of Hogwarts that also reveals the location of everyone inside the
castle&amp;mdash;or at least, the locations of people and certain cats.  It
reveals your location by placing a dot on the section of the map that
corresponds to where you are in the castle, and by labeling that dot
with your name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the books, the Map has no problem figuring out everyone&amp;rsquo;s name and
labeling them correctly.  But how does it do that?  How does it know
our names?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to answer that question, we first need to settle a more basic
question about the relationship between words and the world.  This
question might seem silly, but there is actually a great deal of
controversy over the correct answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the relationship between someone&amp;mdash;like Harry Potter&amp;mdash;and
their name&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;?  (Or their &lt;em&gt;names&lt;/em&gt;, if, like Alastor
Moody, they sometimes go by a different name.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we should start by making an assumption that&amp;rsquo;s common among
philosophers of language, which is that names &lt;em&gt;designate&lt;/em&gt;. In other
words, names (at least most of them) stand in a particular relation to
things in the world.  It&amp;rsquo;s because of this designation relation that
names &lt;em&gt;hook onto the world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like an obvious assumption, but not everyone agrees.
Before moving on, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss an objection to this assumption, and
why we&amp;rsquo;re going to stick with it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Some people don&amp;rsquo;t think names designate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some philosophers, influenced by Ludwig Wittgenstein, have argued that
the answer we gave above, and the evocative metaphor of words hooking
onto the world, is altogether misguided.  The objection is that
instead of thinking of words as &lt;em&gt;labels&lt;/em&gt; that stick to various
objects, we should think of words, including names, as &lt;em&gt;tools&lt;/em&gt; that we
&lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; to do things.  On page 78 of his &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language: A
Contemporary Introduction&lt;/em&gt; (Second Edition), William Lycan suggests
that this is what Wittgenstein himself was getting at in his later
work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein [offered] a further analogy
[in &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;]: A builder and his assistant
have just four kinds of building stones that they use. They speak a
little primitive language that has just four corresponding words in
it: &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pillar&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;beam&amp;rdquo;. They build things,
engaging in their nonlinguistic activities aided by a certain
primitive sort of linguistic activity: the builder says &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo;, and
the assistant brings a stone of the appropriate shape. Now, someone
might say, &amp;ldquo;Of course, that word &amp;lsquo;slab&amp;rsquo; bears the [designation]
relation to a block of this shape, and its meaning is the
proposition that the assistant is to bring such a block to the
builder.&amp;rdquo; But according to Wittgenstein this would be missing the
point. In this little primitive language-game, the word &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo; does
have a function that is obviously connected with blocks of that
shape, but the point is the function and not the [designation]
relation. The point of the builder&amp;rsquo;s making the noise &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo; is just
to get the assistant to do something, to trigger conventionally (the
assistant having learned his trade) a pattern of useful
activity. The activity does involve things of this shape, but the
primary point is to initiate action, not to [designate].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea here, roughly, is that names, and words in general, are less
like &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; and more like &lt;em&gt;hammers&lt;/em&gt;. Instead of asking what a name is
&lt;em&gt;attached to&lt;/em&gt;, we should ask what a name is &lt;em&gt;used for&lt;/em&gt;. In
Wittgenstein&amp;rsquo;s example, the words &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pillar&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;slab&amp;rdquo;, and
&amp;ldquo;beam&amp;rdquo; are used to make the assistant retrieve certain building
materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to this sort of theory, words in general work a lot like
spell-words do.  Here&amp;rsquo;s an example from &lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, right
after Gilderoy Lockhart admits that he didn&amp;rsquo;t do any of the brave
things he claimed to do in his books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pulled out his wand and turned to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Awfully sorry, boys, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put a Memory Charm on you
now. Can&amp;rsquo;t have you blabbing my secrets all over the place.  I&amp;rsquo;d
never sell another book &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry reached his wand just in time. Lockhart had barely raised his,
when Harry bellowed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt;, Chapter 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make much sense to ask what &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo;
designated there.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t designate &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;.  It was &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; by
Harry to disarm Lockhart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Problems with the words-as-tools theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As appealing as this words-as-tools theory is, it&amp;rsquo;s got some real
problems. Here&amp;rsquo;s one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look again at how we talked about the &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; case: we said
that &amp;ldquo;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make much sense to ask what &amp;lsquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rsquo;
designated &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  It &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; seem to make much sense to ask what
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designated &lt;em&gt;in that context&lt;/em&gt;, but it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make sense
to ask what &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo;
is the name of a spell.  When we use the word &amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;re
not always using it to cast a spell.  Sometimes we just want to talk
about the spell, like Harry and Zacharias Smith do during the first
meeting of Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s Army:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Right,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, [&amp;hellip;] &amp;ldquo;shall we get practising then? I was
thinking, the first thing we should do is Expelliarmus, you know,
the Disarming Charm. I know it&amp;rsquo;s pretty basic but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it
really useful&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, please,&amp;rdquo; said Zacharias Smith, rolling his eyes and folding his
arms. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think Expelliarmus is exactly going to help us
against You-Know-Who, do you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve used it against him,&amp;rdquo; said Harry quietly. &amp;ldquo;It saved my life in
June&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, Chapter 18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the right conclusion to draw here is that, while
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; designates &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;, we don&amp;rsquo;t always &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Expelliarmus&amp;rdquo; to talk about &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;.  Sometimes, as we&amp;rsquo;ve
seen, we use it to cast the spell.  Just because a word designates a
certain thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we can&amp;rsquo;t use it to do things other
than talk about what it designates.  Malfoy does just this in
&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, look who it is,&amp;rdquo; said Malfoy in his usual lazy drawl, pulling
open the compartment door. &amp;ldquo;Potty and the Weasel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; designates, but it&amp;rsquo;s not Harry.  And &amp;ldquo;the
Weasel&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t designate Ron&amp;mdash;many philosophers of language think
that the determiner &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; means that &amp;ldquo;the Weasel&amp;rdquo; can only designate
the &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt; Weasel, and so doesn&amp;rsquo;t designate anything in a world with
many weasels, such the world of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;. But Malfoy is
nonetheless using &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; to talk about Harry and using &amp;ldquo;the Weasel&amp;rdquo;
to talk about Ron.  Let&amp;rsquo;s introduce another bit of technical language
and say that while &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; does not &lt;em&gt;designate&lt;/em&gt; Harry, Malfoy is using
it, in this context, to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context is important for &lt;em&gt;referring&lt;/em&gt;, but not for &lt;em&gt;designating&lt;/em&gt;.  If
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter, it does so all the time, and
whether or not anyone is using the name.  But Malfoy has to be in the
right sort of situation in order to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry using &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo;.
Basically, he has to be in a situation where the people he&amp;rsquo;s talking
to realize he&amp;rsquo;s using &amp;ldquo;Potty&amp;rdquo; as if it was a name for Harry.  This is
how Kent Bach describes it on page 518 of &amp;ldquo;What Does it Take to
Refer?&amp;rdquo; in the &lt;em&gt;Oxford Handbook of Philosophy of Language:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker reference is a four-place relation between a speaker, an
expression, an audience, and a referent: you use an expression to
refer someone to something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between designation and reference will be important
later on, but the point of bringing it up now is to show that while
the words-as-tools theory is &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; to say that we use words for
different purposes in different contexts, that &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; mean we
should think that words never designate anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other objections to the words-as-tools theory.  One is that
while it might be true for some words and maybe even some phrases,
it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;generally&lt;/em&gt; true; some words and phrases might be tools, but
some aren&amp;rsquo;t.  We&amp;rsquo;re interested in names right now, and names seem the
&lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; like tools; they really do seem more like labels or tags.
(And this objection could be pushed a little further: aren&amp;rsquo;t tags
ultimately a &lt;em&gt;sort of tool?&lt;/em&gt;  Even if all words &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; tools, does that
really rule out words that are meant to be used as tags?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another objection to words-as-tools is that even if I understand the
conventional ways to use English words, that&amp;rsquo;s not all there is to
&lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; English.  This is one of William Lycan&amp;rsquo;s objections,
from page 81 of &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I not know the use of an expression, and fall in with it,
mechanically, without understanding it? I have known undergraduates
who are geniuses at picking up academic jargon of one sort or
another and slinging it around with great facility, but without
understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A similar example is in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;, when Harry and Ron make up
predictions about what will happen to them instead of really doing
Divination, but aren&amp;rsquo;t caught by Professor Trelawny because they write
the sort of stuff she expects to hear.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could program a computer (or enchant a hat) to reply to English
sentences with other English sentences; it might be well-designed
enough to give replies that a fluent English speaker would give.  But
if the computer&amp;rsquo;s replies were chosen by making statistical
generalizations from a database of recorded conversations, we would
probably say that the computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; English.
It &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; use English words, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what they &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more that could be said on both sides, but let&amp;rsquo;s put away the
words-as-tools theory, and accept for the time being that names really
do designate things.  Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;The meaning of names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we&amp;rsquo;ve just talked about whether or not names designate things.
But at least for most words, you&amp;rsquo;re probably more familiar with the
question, &amp;ldquo;what does this word &lt;em&gt;mean?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  We&amp;rsquo;re going to stay focused
just on names, so our question is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;what do names mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have no problem explaining what most words mean, so it may seem odd
that the meaning of names is such a big problem.  For example, the
meaning of &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;person without magical power but with at least
one parent who is a witch or wizard.&amp;rdquo;  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;thestral&amp;rdquo; is
something like &amp;ldquo;winged horse visible only to those who have seen and
understood death.&amp;rdquo;  But it&amp;rsquo;s not nearly as obvious what the meaning of
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to look at three different theories of names, which each
provide a different answer to the question, &amp;ldquo;what is the meaning of
&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;  The first theory is &lt;strong&gt;Descriptivism&lt;/strong&gt;, the second is
&lt;strong&gt;Millianism&lt;/strong&gt;, and the third is &lt;strong&gt;Nominal Descriptivism&lt;/strong&gt;. I think
Nominal Descriptivism is the correct theory, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why, but
keep in mind that there are many philosophers who disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Descriptivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As its name suggests, Descriptivism claims that the meaning of a name
is a &lt;em&gt;description&lt;/em&gt; of the person or object designated by that name.
According to this theory, names such as &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; are a lot like
general terms like &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;thestral&amp;rdquo;.  The meanings of those
words also describe the things they designate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t be just any description that
describes Harry Potter.  For example, the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
can&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s true that &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo; is
commonly used to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to Harry Potter, and has become associated in
the popular imagination with Harry Potter, but &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo;
doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;uniquely&lt;/em&gt; describe Harry.  Strictly speaking, any living boy
is a boy who lived; Harry is not really unique in that respect.  And
as I mentioned above, &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; implies uniqueness.  There are many maps,
but only one Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map, so it is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.  If there
were multiple Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Maps, then it would not be correct to use
&amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo;.  &amp;ldquo;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map&amp;rdquo; only designates the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map while
it is the unique&amp;mdash;the only&amp;mdash;Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo; does not designate Harry, even
though it is very often used to refer to him.  So if Descriptivism is
true, then the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; has to be something other
than &amp;ldquo;the boy who lived&amp;rdquo;.  It has to be something that uniquely
describes Harry, something like &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily
Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort
on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;.  &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; describes nobody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Descriptivism, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is really nothing more than
an &lt;em&gt;abbreviation&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31
July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;.  The only difference between the following two
sentences is their length:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981,
lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet
Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Descriptivism is correct, then we use &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; instead of
&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo; only
because it&amp;rsquo;s more convenient; the meaning is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;How would the Map work in a Descriptivist world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose that Descriptivism is correct.  What would that tell us
about how the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map works?  We&amp;rsquo;re not worried about how it
determines that &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; person is in, for example, the Gryffindor
common room; presumably that&amp;rsquo;s taken care of by the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.wikia.com/wiki/Marauder%27s_Map&#34; title=&#34;entry for the Marauder&#39;s Map on the Pottermore wiki&#34;&gt;Homonculous Charm&lt;/a&gt;.  What we want
to know is how the Map goes further, and determines &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; that person
is.  Without asking anyone, how does it figure out your name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make some assumptions about Hogwarts in order to make this
easier.  We&amp;rsquo;ll suppose that the Map already has access to the names of
everyone who is in the castle.  If the Map didn&amp;rsquo;t have the names, then
it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how the Map could match up people with their names.
It would have to be able to deduce a person&amp;rsquo;s name just from &amp;ldquo;looking&amp;rdquo;
at them; and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why are we allowed to assume that the Map already has access to
the names of everyone in the castle?  I think we&amp;rsquo;re allowed to do so
for the following reason: Hogwarts is protected from intruders by a
number of enchantments.  One of these enchantments might well be an
enchantment that prevents unauthorized people from entering the
castle.  At the beginning of the year, the Headmaster or Headmistress
teaches Hogwarts the names of the new students, so that they may
enter.  Individuals who never attended the school but are either
permanent or temporary residents&amp;mdash;Peeves, Filch, Mrs. Norris, the
visitors from Beauxbatons and Durmstrang&amp;mdash;are added on a case-by-case
basis.  Hogwarts determines who is designated by each name, and allows
them entry.  The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map simply piggy-backs off this system of
enchantments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: Hogwarts learns the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, and therefore the
Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map does too.  How does the Map then take that name and
figure out who it designates?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Descriptivism is true, then what the Map learns when it learns the
name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;the
wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;.  So in order
to label Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;s dot on the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map, the Map just needs
to discover which of the people within Hogwarts is the wizard born to
James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse
cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.  Whoever in fact fits that
description is Harry Potter, according to this theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the Map actually goes about this investigation is something
J.K. Rowling might have to tell us.  How the Map can reach back into
the past and figure out with complete certainty which of these people
&lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; in the castle was &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; the wizard who survived a Killing Curse
is a complicated question.  It&amp;rsquo;s also a question that we&amp;rsquo;re not going
to try to answer.  We now know &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the Map needs to do in order to
label its dots, if Descriptivism is true.  &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; it does that is a
question for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it might not even be worth trying to answer this second question,
because Descriptivism is probably not the correct theory anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Problems with Descriptivism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism is intuitive and straightforward, but it has some big
problems.  Here are two:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; just means &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily
Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, than anyone who understands the
name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;just on the basis of
understanding the name!&amp;mdash;that Harry Potter survived a Killing
Curse cast by Voldemort.  But surely this isn&amp;rsquo;t right: we only
know that Harry survived Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s Killing Curse because we have
historical evidence about what happened that Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en.  It&amp;rsquo;s not
something we can learn simply by knowing what &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
means.  And if Harry&amp;rsquo;s name alone told us that he was born on 31
July 1980, then this could not have happened in &lt;em&gt;The Goblet of
Fire&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry looked around; the whole class was staring at him. He sat
up straight; he had been almost dozing off, lost in the heat and
his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was saying, my dear, that you were clearly born under the
baleful influence of Saturn,&amp;rdquo; said Professor Trelawney, a faint
note of resentment in her voice at the fact that he had
obviously not been hanging on her words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Born under&amp;mdash;what, sorry?&amp;rdquo; said Harry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Saturn, dear, the planet Saturn!&amp;rdquo; said Professor Trelawney,
sounding definitely irritated that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t riveted by this
news. &amp;ldquo;I was saying that Saturn was surely in a position of
power in the heavens at the moment of your birth &amp;hellip; your dark
hair &amp;hellip; your mean stature &amp;hellip; tragic losses so young in life
&amp;hellip; I think I am right in saying, my dear, that you were born in
mid-winter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, &amp;ldquo;I was born in July&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems perfectly true to say &amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry
Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;
If Lily hadn&amp;rsquo;t died trying to save him, her love wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have
protected him from Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s curse, and he would also have died.
But if Descriptivism is true, then the following are equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that the wizard born to James and Lily Potter
on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981 did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while the first is true, the second seems false.  How could it
be that the wizard, whoever it is, who survived a Killing Curse
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have survived that Killing Curse?  We seem to be
contradicting ourselves.  But we are definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
contradicting ourselves by saying that Harry Potter might not have
survived that Killing Curse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I think that Descriptivism cannot be the correct
theory of names.  So we should move on to examine Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Millianism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two problems for Descriptivism that I listed above were originally
presented by Saul Kripke in a series of lectures at Princeton in 1972.
Descriptivism was much more widely accepted then than it is now, and
it was Kripke&amp;rsquo;s lectures that caused philosophers to abandon
Descriptivism and look for a better theory of names.  Many settled on
Millianism, which is called that because it was inspired by the
philosophy of John Stuart Mill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Millianism, the meaning of a name &lt;em&gt;just is&lt;/em&gt; the
designation of the name.  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is nothing
more than the person designated by that name&amp;mdash;Harry Potter, the
wizard himself.  Compare this with Descriptivism: according to that
theory, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter because the meaning of
the name&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980,
who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in
1981&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;uniquely describes Harry Potter.  According to Millianism,
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates Harry Potter because the meaning of the name
just &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Harry Potter.  The meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t something
that describes or &lt;em&gt;picks out&lt;/em&gt; that wizard; the meaning &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that
wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theory does not face the two problems that face Descriptivism:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and
Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, then understanding the name
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; not &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; require knowing that Harry Potter
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort, or knowing when Harry
was born.  Understanding the name just requires knowing who it
designates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Millianism is true, then the following are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that Harry Potter did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that
Killing Curse cast by Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It could have been that the wizard born to James and Lily Potter
on 31 July 1980, who survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981 did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; survive that Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there is nothing strange about denying the second while
agreeing with the first, if Millianism is correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while Millianism avoids the problems that plagued Descriptivism,
it faces its own set of challenges, as we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  But first let&amp;rsquo;s
look at how the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map would function &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; Millianism were
true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;How would the Map work in a Millian world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Millianism is true, what the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map has to do in order to
label its dots is actually very little.  Since the meaning of a name,
according to Millianism, just is the thing designated by that name,
when the Map learns the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, what it learns is &lt;em&gt;who
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So just learning &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; gives the Map everything it needs to
pinpoint and label Harry Potter.  Descriptivism gave the Map only a
description of Harry Potter; Millianism gives the Map Harry Potter
himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, because we don&amp;rsquo;t have to ask Rowling how the Map can
investigate who fits the descriptions associated with names.  But
unfortunately, Millianism has serious problems that make it a less
attractive theory than you might think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;Problems with Millianism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people have multiple names.  Alastor Moody is more often
known as &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo;.  If, like Millianism says, the meaning
of &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; and the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; are both
just the ex-Auror, then they should be completely
&lt;em&gt;interchangeable&lt;/em&gt;. But they&amp;rsquo;re not, because we often don&amp;rsquo;t realize
that two names designate the same person:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are those who&amp;rsquo;ll turn innocent occasions to their
advantage,&amp;rdquo; Moody retorted in a menacing voice. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my job to
think the way Dark wizards do, Karkaroff&amp;mdash;as you ought to
remember &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alastor!&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore warningly.  Harry wondered for a
moment whom he was speaking to, but then realised &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye&amp;rdquo;
could hardly be Moody&amp;rsquo;s real first name (&lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt;, Chapter 17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Millianism was true, then &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody is Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo;
is &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt; true, because the two names are perfect synonyms.
If Millianism was true, then nobody would &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; disagree with
&amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody is the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher at
Hogwarts&amp;rdquo; while agreeing with &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody is the Defense
Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts.&amp;rdquo;  But before Harry&amp;rsquo;s
name came out of the Goblet of Fire, he would have done just that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is just Harry Potter, then if Harry
Potter &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&lt;/em&gt;, the name is meaningless!  If the only
meaning it has is the person it designates, then there&amp;rsquo;s no
meaning if there&amp;rsquo;s no person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Harry Potter is alive, while he &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; exist, &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter
doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo; is a perfectly meaningful sentence&amp;mdash;except that
it&amp;rsquo;s false.  But when Harry ceases to exist, there is no longer
anything for &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; to designate, so &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter doesn&amp;rsquo;t
exist&amp;rdquo; is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; meaningful, because &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; has quite
literally lost its meaning.  Just when we would want to say that
Harry Potter doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, it seems that we no longer can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These objections are convincing enough for me to think that Millianism
cannot be the correct theory of names either.  Fortunately we have one
more candidate that is better than either Descriptivism or Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_10&#34;&gt;Nominal Descriptivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory of Nominal Descriptivism was given that name by Kent Bach.
The name makes perfect sense, because this is what the theory says:
the meaning of any name &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;the thing designated by &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;
(Since we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about names of people, from now on we&amp;rsquo;ll say
“the &lt;em&gt;person&lt;/em&gt; designated by &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, Nominal Descriptivism says that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;  According to
this theory, the following differ only in length:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The person designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; lives in the cupboard under
the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet
Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simple theory avoids the problems that plagued &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; (regular)
Descriptivism and Millianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_11&#34;&gt;How Nominal Descriptivism avoids the Descriptivist problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism had the bizarre consequence that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;true by
definition&lt;/em&gt; that Harry Potter survived a Killing Curse.  This
meant that anyone who understands the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby
knows that Harry survived a Killing Curse, just like anyone who
understands the word &amp;ldquo;squib&amp;rdquo; knows that squibs don&amp;rsquo;t have magical
power.  All &lt;em&gt;Nominal Descriptivism&lt;/em&gt; says is that anyone who
understands &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; thereby knows that Harry Potter is
designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  That&amp;rsquo;s not a bizarre consequence at
all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Descriptivism was forced to deny that Harry Potter might not have
survived the Killing Curse cast by Voldemort, because part of the
&lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; was &amp;ldquo;the wizard who survived a Killing
Curse cast by Voldemort&amp;rdquo;.  As it turns out, Nominal Descriptivism
denies this too, but for a very different reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nominal Descriptivism says that the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; is
&amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;  That is a &lt;em&gt;definite&lt;/em&gt;
description, and we saw above that definite descriptions&amp;mdash;like
&amp;ldquo;the wizard born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in
1981&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;are supposed to &lt;em&gt;uniquely&lt;/em&gt; designate someone.  This means
that the sentence &amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; lives
in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey&amp;rdquo; is only true, strictly speaking, if there is
just &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; person designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  If there is more
than one person in the world named &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, then it&amp;rsquo;s not
&lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; true that &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;
lives in the cupboard under the stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little
Whinging, Surrey.  And if Nominal Descriptivism is true, then it&amp;rsquo;s
likewise &lt;em&gt;false&lt;/em&gt; that Harry Potter lives in the cupboard under the
stairs of 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, pretty much everything said using the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
will be literally false if there is more than one person named
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  But this is not as bad as it seems!  A lot of
what we say is literally false, even though we don&amp;rsquo;t realize it:
suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a party in Gryffindor Tower and Fred says &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s
no butterbeer.&amp;rdquo;  He&amp;rsquo;s actually saying something false because he&amp;rsquo;s
denying that there&amp;rsquo;s butterbeer, &lt;em&gt;period&lt;/em&gt;.  And surely there&amp;rsquo;s
butterbeer &lt;em&gt;somewhere;&lt;/em&gt; in the Hogwarts kitchens, in the Three
Broomsticks, and so on.  But &lt;em&gt;what Fred meant&lt;/em&gt; is that there&amp;rsquo;s no
butterbeer in Gryffindor Tower.  For the same reason, if Harry
says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Harry Potter,&amp;rdquo; he&amp;rsquo;s technically uttering a falsehood,
but as long as the people he&amp;rsquo;s talking to understand that he&amp;rsquo;s
referring them to himself (remember that &lt;em&gt;reference&lt;/em&gt; is a
four-place relation between a speaker, audience, name and object),
everyone knows what he means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for this reason that &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter might not have survived
that Killing Curse cast by Voldemort&amp;rdquo; is literally false; there
are almost certainly multiple people named &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  But
depending on who the speaker intends to &lt;em&gt;refer&lt;/em&gt; to when they say
that Harry Potter might not have survived that Killing Curse cast
by Voldemort, what they &lt;em&gt;meant&lt;/em&gt; (“&lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; might not have survived”)
may be true or false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you still think that this is a big problem for Nominal
Descriptivism, keep in mind that we never discussed how regular
Descriptivism and Millianism deal with multiple people sharing a
name.  If there is even one other Harry Potter, then &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t just mean &amp;ldquo;the wizard born to &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (like
Descriptivism says), and it can&amp;rsquo;t mean &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Harry Potter (like
Millianism says), because what about the other Harry Potter(s)?
These theories would have to be tweaked to cope with this
complication, and those tweaks may end up being just as
unintuitive.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_12&#34;&gt;How Nominal Descriptivism avoids the Millian problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A big problem for Millianism was that it gave us the strange result
that there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no difference between names that designate
the same person&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; should be
interchangeable everywhere.  But if Nominal Descriptivism is
correct, then &amp;ldquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;the person designated by
&amp;lsquo;Mad-Eye Moody&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;the person designated
by &amp;lsquo;Alastor Moody&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;  Now the names are no longer synonymous, and
there is no mystery as to how Harry could fail to realize that
Mad-Eye Moody is Alastor Moody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millianism also seemed unable to make sense of statements like
&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter does not exist.&amp;rdquo;  Nominal Descriptivism has no
problem with these &lt;em&gt;negative existentials:&lt;/em&gt; if Harry Potter means
&amp;ldquo;the person designated by &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;,&amp;rdquo; then everything becomes
clear: we are just denying that anyone is designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_13&#34;&gt;How does the Map work in a Nominal Descriptivist world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a bit complicated.  Remember that in a (regular)
Descriptivist world, when the map learns &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, it learns
that Harry Potter is the wizard, whoever it is, who was born to James
and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, and who survived a Killing Curse cast
by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981.  In a Millian world, the Map
simply learns who Harry Potter is.  But in our Nominal Descriptivist
world, all the Map can learn is that the name &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
designates whoever it in fact designates.  Not very helpful at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Nominal Descriptivist world, unlike the previous worlds we
examined, learning the meaning of a name does not give you enough
information to determine who is designated by that name.  So the Map
will have to look elsewhere for information about who&amp;rsquo;s designated by
what names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where will we look next?  We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to figure out a &lt;em&gt;semantic&lt;/em&gt;
fact: what individual(s) are designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  Previously
we were able to figure this out using another semantic fact&amp;mdash;the
meaning of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  But now that semantic fact has failed us.
So we will have to look at &lt;em&gt;metasemantic&lt;/em&gt; facts: in particular, the
facts about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates the individuals it does.
How did it come to be that Harry Potter (&lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Harry Potter; the
wizard, the hero of our stories) came to be designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rdquo;?  How did he get his name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_14&#34;&gt;Semantic and metasemantic facts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned above that Saul Kripke argued against Descriptivism in a
series of lectures, later published as &lt;em&gt;Naming and Necessity&lt;/em&gt;. An
important feature of his argument is that while he insists that the
meaning of a proper name like &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; cannot be some definite
description like &amp;ldquo;the wizard who was born to James and Lily Potter on
31 July 1980 and survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on
Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, he admits (on pages 57&amp;ndash;58) that a description
like that &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be used to &lt;em&gt;fix the designation&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems plausible to suppose that, in some cases, the [designation]
of a name is indeed fixed &lt;em&gt;via&lt;/em&gt; a description in the same way that
the metric system was fixed. When [someone] first saw
Hesperus, he may well have fixed [the designation] by saying, &amp;ldquo;I shall
use &amp;lsquo;Hesperus&amp;rsquo; as a name of the heavenly body appearing in yonder
position in the sky.&amp;rdquo; He then fixed the [designation] of &amp;ldquo;Hesperus&amp;rdquo; by
its apparent celestial position.  Does it then follow that it is a
part of the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of the name that Hesperus has such and such a
position at the time in question?  Surely not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that there are multiple ways to name something or someone.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine Lily Potter naming her baby.  There are at least two
different ways she could do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She could say &amp;ldquo;let &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; designate the wizard, whoever it
is, who was born to James and Lily Potter on 31 July 1980, and who
survived a Killing Curse cast by Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;
(of course, unless she is a Seer, she would not have used that exact
description).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She can point at the baby and say &amp;ldquo;let &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; child be named &amp;lsquo;Harry
Potter&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important point here is that when Lily says these things, she is
fixing the designation of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;, but she is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; giving a
&lt;em&gt;definition&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;.  We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen why &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;
cannot be defined as meaning &amp;ldquo;the wizard who was born to James and
Lily Potter on 31 July 1980 and survived a Killing Curse cast by
Voldemort on Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en in 1981&amp;rdquo;, or as meaning the person himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Lily fixed the designation of &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; by, let&amp;rsquo;s
say, pointing and saying &amp;ldquo;that child shall be &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; is
therefore &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a semantic fact.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a fact that can be
expressed as &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; means such-and-such&amp;rdquo;, nor can it be
expressed as &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; designates the so-and-so.&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s a
&lt;em&gt;metasemantic&lt;/em&gt; fact that tells us &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; the semantic facts.  Knowing
this metasemantic fact, we can then use it to figure out the semantic
fact that &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; designates the baby that Lily Potter pointed
at when she said &amp;ldquo;that child shall be &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s this
semantic question&amp;mdash;who is designated by &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;?&amp;mdash;that the
Map needs to answer, in order to label Harry when he arrives at
Hogwarts.  But it won&amp;rsquo;t be able to answer that question without first
learning some metasemantic facts about how Harry got his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We face again the question of how the Map reaches back into the past.
How can it know for certain when and how a person was named, so that
it can learn what name they were given?  I&amp;rsquo;m afraid this is a question
for another day.  We now know &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the Map needs to know.  I won&amp;rsquo;t
here try to answer &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it might come to know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_15&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bach,
Kent (2002). &lt;a href=&#34;http://userwww.sfsu.edu/kbach/Bach.Giorgione.pdf&#34; title=&#34;PDF&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Giorgione was so-called because of his name&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Philosophical Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; volume 16, pages 73&amp;ndash;103.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hinchliff, Mark (2012). &amp;ldquo;Has the theory of reference rested on a mistake?&amp;rdquo;
in &lt;em&gt;Reference and Referring&lt;/em&gt;, edited by William Kabasenche, Michael
O&amp;rsquo;Rourke, and Matthew Slater, MIT Press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kripke, Saul (1980). &lt;em&gt;Naming and Necessity&lt;/em&gt;, Harvard University Press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lycan, William (2008). &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Language: A Contemporary
Introduction&lt;/em&gt;, Routledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;It is too late, you understand me?&#8221;: Time travel in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 21:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/time</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here at &lt;em&gt;Baruffio&lt;/em&gt; we sometimes cast a critical eye on &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter,&lt;/em&gt;
and amuse ourselves by pointing out inconsistencies in the books (then
&lt;a href=&#34;/p/trace&#34; title=&#34;There&#39;s no Such
Thing as the Trace&#34;&gt;weaving them into conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;).  But time travel in &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; is a
model of consistency, illustrating wonderfully how time travel
works&amp;mdash;if it&amp;rsquo;s possible at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Going back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 21 of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban,&lt;/em&gt; Harry and Hermione wake up in
the hospital wing to learn that Sirius Black is about to receive the
Dementor&amp;rsquo;s Kiss.  It is, as Dumbledore tells them, too late to save
him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sirius has not acted like an innocent man. The attack on the Fat
Lady&amp;mdash;entering Gryffindor Tower with a knife&amp;mdash;without Pettigrew,
alive or dead, we have no chance of overturning Sirius&amp;rsquo; sentence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you believe us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I do,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore quietly. &amp;ldquo;But I have no power to make
other men see the truth, or to overrule the Minister for Magic &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry stared up into the grave face and felt as though the ground
beneath him was falling sharply away.  He had grown used to the idea
that Dumbledore could solve anything.  He had expected Dumbledore to
pull some amazing solution out of the air.  But no &amp;hellip; their last
hope was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What we need,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore slowly, and his light-blue eyes
moved from Harry to Hermione, &amp;ldquo;is more &lt;em&gt;time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo; Hermione began. And then her eyes became very round. &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, pay attention,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore, speaking very low, and very
clearly.  &amp;ldquo;Sirius is locked in Professor Flitwick&amp;rsquo;s office on the
seventh floor.  Thirteenth window from the right of the West Tower.
If all goes well, you will be able to save more than one innocent
life tonight.  But remember this, both of you. &lt;em&gt;You must not be
seen.&lt;/em&gt; Miss Granger, you know the law&amp;mdash;you know what is at stake
&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;you&amp;mdash;must&amp;mdash;not&amp;mdash;be&amp;mdash;seen”&lt;/em&gt; (Chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so they go back in time, to rescue Buckbeak the Hippogriff and
Sirius Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;You must not be seen, and you &lt;em&gt;will not&lt;/em&gt; be seen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry and Hermione go back in time with the intention of preventing
Buckbeak from being killed.  But it&amp;rsquo;s very important to realize that
&lt;em&gt;Buckbeak never was killed.&lt;/em&gt;  When Hermione spins the Time-Turner to
send her and Harry back three hours, Buckbeak isn&amp;rsquo;t dead.  They&amp;rsquo;d
already saved him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to make this clear because Rowling leaves Buckbeak&amp;rsquo;s
fate deliberately ambiguous the first time around, in Chapter 16
and 17.  When Hermione, Harry, Ron, and Scabbers leave Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s hut at
sundown, they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they hear Buckbeak being killed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rat was squealing wildly, but not loudly enough to cover up the
sounds drifting from Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s garden. There was a jumble of
indistinct male voices, a silence and then, without warning, the
unmistakeable swish and thud of an axe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione swayed on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They did it!&amp;rdquo; she whispered to Harry. &amp;ldquo;I d-don&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;mdash;they
did it!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s mind had gone blank with shock. The three of them stood
transfixed with horror under the Invisibility Cloak. The very last
rays of the setting sun were casting a bloody light over the
long-shadowed grounds. Then, behind them, they heard a wild howling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hagrid,&amp;rdquo; Harry muttered. Without thinking about what he was doing,
he made to turn back, but both Ron and Hermione seized his arms
(Chapters 16&amp;ndash;17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they&amp;rsquo;re leaving the cabin, they don&amp;rsquo;t see Buckbeak getting killed.
They hear Hagrid howling, but they can&amp;rsquo;t hear it clearly.  This is
because Buckbeak &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; get killed, and Hagrid is howling from joy,
not from grief.  When Harry and Hermione go back in time, the first
thing they do is rescue Buckbeak.  While Hagrid, Dumbledore, a
Ministry committee member, and the executioner Macnair are in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s
hut, Harry unties Buckbeak and leads him away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s back door had opened with a bang. Harry, Hermione and
Buckbeak stood quite still; even the Hippogriff seemed to be
listening intently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silence &amp;hellip; then&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where is it?&amp;rdquo; said the reedy voice of the Committee member. &amp;ldquo;Where
is the beast?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was tied here!&amp;rdquo; said the executioner furiously. &amp;ldquo;I saw it! Just
here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How extraordinary,&amp;rdquo; said Dumbledore. There was a note of amusement
in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beaky!&amp;rdquo; said Hagrid huskily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a swishing noise, and the thud of an axe. The executioner
seemed to have swung it into the fence in anger. And then came the
howling, and &lt;strong&gt;this time they could hear Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s words through his
sobs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gone! Gone! Bless his little beak, he&amp;rsquo;s gone! Musta pulled himself
free! Beaky, yeh clever boy!&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 21, my emphasis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve emphasized the important clause above.  It was never true that
Buckbeak got executed.  Hagrid is sobbing with joy &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; times we see
this scene.  When Harry and Hermione are under the Invisibility Cloak
with Ron and Scabbers, they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they are listening to Macnair
killing the Hippogriff, but they are &lt;em&gt;wrong:&lt;/em&gt; Buckbeak had already
been rescued&amp;mdash;by them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the past when he casts his Patronus, either.
After he, Hermione, Ron, Sirius, Lupin, Snape, and Pettigrew leave the
Shrieking Shack, the full moon comes out and Lupin transforms into a
werewolf.  Pettigrew escapes in the confusion, and Sirius chases after
him.  Harry and Hermione find Sirius at the edge of the Hogwarts lake,
surrounded by Dementors.  Sirius and Hermione faint, and just before
Harry&amp;rsquo;s soul is sucked from his body by the Dementor&amp;rsquo;s Kiss, something
miraculous happens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something was driving the Dementors back &amp;hellip; it was circling around
him and Sirius and Hermione &amp;hellip; the rattling, sucking sounds of the
Dementors were fading. They were leaving &amp;hellip; the air was warm again
&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With every ounce of strength he could muster, Harry raised his head
a few inches and saw an animal amidst the light, galloping away
across the lake. Eyes blurred with sweat, Harry tried to make out
what it was &amp;hellip; it was bright as a unicorn.  Fighting to stay
conscious, Harry watched it canter to a halt as it reached the
opposite shore.  For a moment, Harry saw, by its brightness,
somebody welcoming it back &amp;hellip; raising his hand to pat it
&amp;hellip; someone who looked strangely familiar &amp;hellip; but it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be
&amp;hellip; (Chapter 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry thinks he was saved by his father, but he&amp;rsquo;s wrong.  He saved
himself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry raised his head to look at the circle of Dementors across the
lake.  One of them was lowering its hood.  It was time for the
rescuer to appear&amp;mdash;but no one was coming to help this time&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it hit him&amp;mdash;he understood. He hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen his father&amp;mdash;he
had seen &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry flung himself out from behind the bush and pulled out his
wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;EXPECTO PATRONUM!&amp;rdquo; he yelled (Chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Harry does this, he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changing the past.  The person who
cast the Patronus was him, all along:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;mdash;you conjured up a Patronus that drove
away all those Dementors! That&amp;rsquo;s very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; advanced magic &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew I could do it this time,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, &amp;ldquo;because I&amp;rsquo;d already
done it &amp;hellip; Does that make sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything Harry and Hermione do in Chapter 21 has already occurred
when Hermione spins the Time-Turner three times.  They don&amp;rsquo;t change
the past; everything they have to do, they have already done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why don&amp;rsquo;t they change the past &lt;em&gt;anyway?&lt;/em&gt; Harry wants to; he tries
to convince Hermione to capture Pettigrew while Pettigrew&amp;mdash;in the
form of Scabbers&amp;mdash;is still in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with Harry and
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s past selves.  But Hermione won&amp;rsquo;t let him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hermione,&amp;rdquo; said Harry suddenly, &amp;ldquo;what if we&amp;mdash;we just run in there,
and grab Pettigrew&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo; said Hermione in a terrified whisper. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you understand?
We&amp;rsquo;re breaking one of the most important wizarding laws!  Nobody&amp;rsquo;s
supposed to change time, nobody! You heard Dumbledore, if we&amp;rsquo;re
seen&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;d only be seen by ourselves and Hagrid!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, what do you think you&amp;rsquo;d do if you saw yourself bursting into
Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s house?&amp;rdquo; said Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d gone mad,&amp;rdquo; said Harry, &amp;ldquo;or I&amp;rsquo;d think there was
some Dark Magic going on&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Exactly!&lt;/em&gt; You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand, you might even attack yourself!
Don&amp;rsquo;t you see? Professor McGonagall told me what awful things have
happened when wizards have meddled with time &amp;hellip; loads of them ended
up killing their past or future selves by mistake!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Hermione gives as to why they don&amp;rsquo;t change the past is that
it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;dangerous.&lt;/em&gt;  She seems to believe this herself, because she
thinks she and Harry &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; changing the past, and breaking the law in
doing so.  As far as she and Harry know, Buckbeak &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; executed, and
they&amp;rsquo;re trying to change that.  Because Hermione thinks they are
changing the past, and because she thinks it&amp;rsquo;s very dangerous, she
panics whenever Harry tries to change things without thinking about
the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione tells Harry not to change this part of the past because it&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;em&gt;dangerous.&lt;/em&gt; She thinks the past shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be changed except in very
rare circumstances, but she thinks it is possible to change the past.
Indeed, she and Harry think they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; going to change the past when
they rescue Buckbeak.  They don&amp;rsquo;t know that he was never killed; they
thinks he &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; killed, and they&amp;rsquo;re trying to change that.  Hermione
believes that while they&amp;rsquo;re taking a big risk in rescuing Buckbeak, it
would be an even bigger risk to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But she needn&amp;rsquo;t have worried.  Not only is changing the past not
dangerous, it&amp;rsquo;s simply &lt;em&gt;impossible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The past is fixed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it impossible to change the past?  Why is it impossible for
Harry to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers?  Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough
way of explaining why it&amp;rsquo;s impossible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry, standing outside and wondering if he should burst into
Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, can remember sitting inside with Scabbers.  He can
also remember &lt;em&gt;leaving&lt;/em&gt; Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with Scabbers, and he
remembers nobody bursting in and trying to grab Scabbers.  His
memory is correct&amp;mdash;what he remembers happening is what happens, so
it&amp;rsquo;s too late to try to change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explanation should strike you as odd; who cares if he remembers
nobody bursting into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin?  Of course nobody has &lt;em&gt;yet,&lt;/em&gt; but
the question is whether he, Harry, &lt;em&gt;will.&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s nothing in the past
that rules out Harry bursting into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, so why can&amp;rsquo;t he?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rough explanation &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; odd, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s actually more or
less right.  To see why, we need to take a detour and introduce some
new terms for talking about time: &amp;ldquo;external time&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;personal time.&amp;rdquo;
These terms were coined by David Lewis in his 1976 paper
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kieranhealy.org/files/misc/lewis-paradoxes.pdf&#34; title=&#34;PDF&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Paradoxes of Time Travel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;  Lewis proposes that we think about time travel as involving &amp;ldquo;a
discrepancy between time and time&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any traveler departs and then arrives at his destination; the time
elapsed from departure to arrival (positive, or perhaps zero) is the
duration of the journey.  But if he is a time traveler, the
separation in time between departure and arrival does not equal the
duration of his journey.  He departs; he travels for an hour, let us
say; then he arrives.  The time he reaches is not the time one hour
after his departure.  It is later, if he has traveled toward the
future; earlier, if he has traveled toward the past.  If he has
traveled far toward the past, it is earlier even than his
departure.  How can it be that the same two events, his departure
and his arrival, are separated by two unequal amounts of time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this puzzle requires distinguishing &amp;ldquo;external time&amp;rdquo; from
&amp;ldquo;personal time.&amp;rdquo;  External time is what is recorded by clock-towers
and atomic clocks; when Harry and Hermione go back in time, they are
going three hours backward in &lt;em&gt;external time.&lt;/em&gt; But they are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
going back in &lt;em&gt;personal time.&lt;/em&gt; Personal time is what is recorded by
Harry&amp;rsquo;s wristwatch.  If Harry checked his watch before and after
Hermione spins the Time-Turner, the hands would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have moved three
hours back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When David Lewis says that time travel involves a discrepancy between
&amp;ldquo;time and time,&amp;rdquo; he means that there is a discrepancy between external
time and personal time; the two come apart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The time traveler&amp;rsquo;s] journey takes an hour of his personal time,
let us say; his wristwatch reads an hour later at arrival than at
departure.  But the arrival is more than an hour after the departure
in external time, if he travels toward the future; or the arrival is
before the departure in external time (or less than an hour after),
if he travels toward the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of Harry and Hermione&amp;rsquo;s journey&amp;mdash;when they appear in the
Entrance Hall&amp;mdash;is a few seconds &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;, in &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; time, the
beginning of their journey&amp;mdash;when Hermione spins the Time-Turner in
the hospital wing.  But, remember, the end of their journey is three
hours &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; its beginning in &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another way of thinking about the difference between external
and personal time, if you&amp;rsquo;re still confused: External time is time in
the third person; personal time is time in the first person.  External
time is the same for everyone; if you could step back and observe the
universe like God, you would watch it progress in external time.
Personal time is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the same for everyone; your personal time
corresponds to your &lt;em&gt;development&lt;/em&gt; through time.  From Harry&amp;rsquo;s
perspective, he appears in the Entrance Hall a few seconds &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;
Hermione spins the Time-Turner.  He remembers being in the hospital
wing immediately prior, his watch has moved a few seconds forward, and
the physical age of his body is only a few seconds older.  (That last
bit is important: I can be confused about the progress of my own
personal time, like when I wake up and can&amp;rsquo;t remember how long I&amp;rsquo;ve
slept.  But my body has aged a certain number of hours, and I&amp;rsquo;ve moved
&lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; many hours ahead in personal time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the life of a person, and their progress
through history, we use personal time.  Harry fainted at the edge of
the lake, surrounded by Dementors, then woke up in the hospital wing,
&lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; went back in time, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; cast the Patronus to save himself.
Those events all occurred, and they occurred &lt;em&gt;in that order&lt;/em&gt; for
Harry.  And most importantly, this is a &lt;em&gt;perfectly accurate&lt;/em&gt; way of
describing the events at the end of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban.&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s no
less accurate than a description of those events in external time.
(An external-time description would be: Harry cast the Patronus to
save himself, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; fainted at the edge of the lake, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; woke up
in the hospital wing, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; went back in time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think of external time as &lt;em&gt;objective&lt;/em&gt; and personal time
as &lt;em&gt;subjective,&lt;/em&gt; external time as &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt; and personal time as
&lt;em&gt;secondary;&lt;/em&gt; but both are equally legitimate.  Personal time isn&amp;rsquo;t
just our &lt;em&gt;opinion&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;feeling&lt;/em&gt; about the passage of time.  Like I
said earlier, we can be unsure about how far we&amp;rsquo;ve proceeded in
personal time: if we are unconscious, we lose the ability to detect
the passage of time.  But there are other, largely objective, ways to
measure how far we move forward in personal time.  When you wake up,
even if &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think you&amp;rsquo;ve only been asleep for a few minutes, your
watch might say otherwise, and your body will have aged as many hours
as you&amp;rsquo;ve been asleep.  You&amp;rsquo;ve progressed a certain determinate number
of hours in personal time.  And &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; fact&amp;mdash;that you&amp;rsquo;ve moved
forward a number of hours in personal time&amp;mdash;is just as &lt;em&gt;objectively
true&lt;/em&gt; as the fact that you&amp;rsquo;ve moved forward (or backward, if you&amp;rsquo;re
time traveling) a number of hours in external time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Harry and Hermione go back in time, the &lt;em&gt;fact&lt;/em&gt; that only a few
seconds of personal time has elapsed for each of them is just as
objectively true as is the fact that they&amp;rsquo;ve moved backward three
hours in external time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our original, rough explanation of why it&amp;rsquo;s
impossible to change the past: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry, standing outside and wondering
if he should burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, can remember sitting inside
with Scabbers.  He can also remember&lt;/em&gt; leaving &lt;em&gt;Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with
Scabbers, and he remembers nobody bursting in and trying to grab
Scabbers.  His memory is correct&amp;mdash;what he remembers happening is what
happens, so it&amp;rsquo;s too late to try to change it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My appeal to what Harry remembers was a rough way of trying to
describe his journey in terms of &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; time.  Let&amp;rsquo;s write out
this series of events explicitly in terms of personal time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Hermione find Scabbers in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin; then left the
cabin with Ron, Hermione and Scabbers; then saw Scabbers escape and
get dragged (with Ron) into the Whomping Willow; then went into the
Shrieking Shack and out again; then fainted at the lake&amp;rsquo;s edge; then
woke up in the hospital wing; then went back in time; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt;
suggested to Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab
the rat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, these events all occur, and they occur &lt;em&gt;in this order&lt;/em&gt; for
Harry and Hermione.  It&amp;rsquo;s because they occur in this order that when
Harry suggests to Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, it&amp;rsquo;s
too late.  They &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; left the cabin with Scabbers, and nobody
burst in.  Harry &lt;em&gt;remembers&lt;/em&gt; this&amp;mdash;he remembers being in in the
cabin, and leaving the cabin, with nobody bursting in.  And he
remembers correctly!  That really happened, and it happened long
before Harry suggests he and Hermione burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin, so
there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Is the future fixed as well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordering events in terms of personal time is no less accurate than
ordering them in terms of external time.  But when we think through
what this means, we&amp;rsquo;ll notice a surprising consequence: if time travel
is possible, then parts of the future are just as fixed as the past
is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think about Harry&amp;rsquo;s fight with the Dementors at the lake&amp;rsquo;s edge.
Harry, about to collapse, sees his Patronus running across the lake,
back to his future self.  Just because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize himself
doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s any less true that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; on the other side of
the lake.  By the time he faints, he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; cast the
Patronus&amp;mdash;in external time.  But since this has already happened in
external time, at some point in Harry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt;-time future he will
&lt;em&gt;have to&lt;/em&gt; be at that spot, and he will have to cast the Patronus
Charm.  His future actions must and &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; eventually lead him there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry, on the verge of collapse at the edge of the lake, has certain
things he is &lt;em&gt;determined&lt;/em&gt; to do in his personal future, because Harry,
standing on the the other side of the lake, is &lt;em&gt;doing those things&lt;/em&gt; at
the very same external time.  But all this shows is that there are
things that Harry has to do at &lt;em&gt;some point&lt;/em&gt; in his personal future.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t there some flexibility about when he gets around to doing them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no.  We&amp;rsquo;ve agreed that when Harry finally faints at the
edge of the lake, he&amp;rsquo;s already (in terms of external time) cast the
Patronus.  That means that he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; already done all the individual
actions that brought him to the spot where he cast the Patronus.  He&amp;rsquo;s
already hid in the forest, watching Snape pick up his Invisibility
Cloak; he&amp;rsquo;s already rescued Buckbeak; he&amp;rsquo;s already suggested to
Hermione that they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin; and he&amp;rsquo;s already
appeared in the Entrance Hall after traveling back in time with
Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can illustrate Harry&amp;rsquo;s journey through the last chapters of
&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;no-border&#34; src=&#34;/img/time-split.png&#34; title=&#34;External time is a horizontal teal line; personal time is a red line curving back to represent backward time travel; the period of time between the beginning of the backward journey in time and its end is fixed.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; represent moments in external
 time.  &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; represent moments in
 personal time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is walking with Ron and Hermione to
visit Hagrid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is sitting in Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin with
Ron and Hermione and Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry faints after being saved by the stag
Patronus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry watches Hermione spin the Time-Turner
three times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is traveling back in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry appears in the Entrance Hall with
Hermione.  (Only a few seconds separate &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry is suggesting to Hermione that
they burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry casts his Patronus for the first time,
driving away the Dementors from across the lake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is when Harry runs with Hermione to the door of the
hospital wing after helping Sirius escape on Buckbeak:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am going to lock you in,&amp;rdquo; they heard [Dumbledore] saying. &amp;ldquo;It
is five minutes to midnight. Miss Granger, three turns should do
it. Good luck.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumbledore backed out of the room, closed the door and took out
his wand to magically lock it. Panicking, Harry and Hermione ran
forwards. Dumbledore looked up, and a wide smile appeared under
the long silver moustache. &amp;ldquo;Well?&amp;rdquo; he said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We did it!&amp;rdquo; said Harry breathlessly. &amp;ldquo;Sirius has gone, on
Buckbeak &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumbledore beamed at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well done. I think&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo; he listened intently for any sound within
the hospital wing. &amp;ldquo;Yes, I think you&amp;rsquo;ve gone, too&amp;rdquo; (Chapter 22).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at things exclusively from the perspective of external time,
you&amp;rsquo;ll see that &lt;em&gt;e&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is simultaneous with &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a hard time seeing why it&amp;rsquo;s too late
for Harry to burst into Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin and grab Scabbers.  But what
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to show is that the perspective of external time is &lt;em&gt;just a
perspective,&lt;/em&gt; and that it&amp;rsquo;s not the only way to look at time.  When
you look at things from the perspective of Harry&amp;rsquo;s personal time,
&lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; simultaneous.  When Harry
is standing outside Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s cabin at &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
is long past, and so is his opportunity to seize Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By appreciating both the external and personal perspectives on time,
we can see more clearly how parts of Harry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt; are fixed, as
well as his past. At &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; Harry is collapsing at the edge
of the lake, but he sees his future self, standing on the other side
of the lake &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; He&amp;rsquo;s able to see into his personal future
because &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;em&gt;externally&lt;/em&gt;
simultaneous. But the fact that he can see his future means that it&amp;rsquo;s
predetermined. If his future self had walked around the lake and
revived him using &lt;em&gt;Rennervate,&lt;/em&gt; Harry could have told himself, in
perfect detail, everything that he would do in his next three
hours. And there would be nothing Harry &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; do but walk that path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all a bit mind-bending, but the upshot is that when Harry goes
back in time three hours, everything that happens during those three
hours is fixed.  Harry already (in personal time) &lt;em&gt;lived&lt;/em&gt; those three
hours, and he can&amp;rsquo;t change that.  He can go back and &lt;em&gt;relive&lt;/em&gt; those
three hours&amp;mdash;which he does&amp;mdash;but he can&amp;rsquo;t undo what he did the first
time around.  Once you&amp;rsquo;ve lived through a period of time, it&amp;rsquo;s fixed;
going back in time doesn&amp;rsquo;t change that.  And it&amp;rsquo;s fixed for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of
us, not just the time-travelers: since Harry&amp;rsquo;s future includes his
casting the Patronus Charm from across the lake, nobody else can
&lt;em&gt;possibly&lt;/em&gt; do anything that would prevent him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem alarming and implausible, but think about it: how
could Professor Trelawney make &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; correct predictions otherwise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Postscript: Pottermore? How about Potter&lt;em&gt;less!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.com&#34;&gt;Pottermore&lt;/a&gt; entry for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pottermore.wikia.com/wiki/Time-Turner&#34; title=&#34;Pottermore Wikia&#34;&gt;Time-Turners&lt;/a&gt; includes this alarming statement from Department
of Mysteries employee Saul Croaker:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All attempts to travel back further than a few hours have resulted
in catastrophic harm to the witch or wizard involved. It was not
realised for many years why time travellers over great distances
never survived their journeys. All such experiments have been
abandoned since 1899, when Eloise Mintumble became trapped, for a
period of five days, in the year 1402. Now we understand that her
body had aged five centuries in its return to the present and,
irreparably damaged, she died in St Mungo&amp;rsquo;s Hospital for Magical
Maladies and Injuries shortly after we managed to retrieve her. What
is more, her five days in the distant past caused great disturbance
to the life paths of all those she met, changing the course of their
lives so dramatically that no fewer than twenty-five of their
descendants vanished in the present, having been &amp;ldquo;un-born.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen, this is impossible.  The notion of time-travel that
exists in the popular imagination and in films like &lt;em&gt;Back to the
Future,&lt;/em&gt; where Marty McFly sees his childhood photos begin to fade
when he threatens to prevent his parents from meeting, are
nonsensical.  We must therefore conclude that the above statement from
Professor Croaker is in error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can&#39;t spell &#8220;OotP&#8221; without &#8220;OTP&#8221;: an essay in Ronbledore apologetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/otp</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/otp</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, J.K. Rowling finally admitted that Ron and
Hermione should not have ended up together.  While this led us to
ponder what
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn/status/429878749941596161&#34;&gt;alternate endings&lt;/a&gt;
Rowling might have secretly preferred, it offered powerful support for
the once-maligned
&lt;a href=&#34;http://the-toast.net/2014/02/03/regret-pairing-ron-hermione-together-ron-time-traveling-dumbledore-jk-rowling-admits/&#34;&gt;Ronbledore Theory&lt;/a&gt;,
which maintains that Ron &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Dumbledore, and at some point went back
in time to live the majority of his life as the eldest son of Percival
and Kendra Dumbledore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure illustrating the Ronbledore theory&#34; title=&#34;Figure illustrating the Ronbledore theory&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Figure 1, above: The blue line represents the &amp;ldquo;Ron&amp;rdquo; period of Ronbledore&amp;rsquo;s life, and the green represents the &amp;ldquo;Dumbledore&amp;rdquo; period.  The exact point at which Ronbledore went back in time (represented by the cyan line) is unknown, but this essay will help to narrow the possibilites.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of the Ronbledore Theory has by now been pretty well
established, but I would like to shore up its foundations with some
new evidence, evidence that will help explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; Ronbledore went
back in time, as well as&amp;mdash;roughly&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;She doesn&amp;rsquo;t get your humor like I do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step of this essay may seem to be a &lt;em&gt;non sequitur&lt;/em&gt;, but its
relevance will soon become apparent.  The first step is to show that
&lt;strong&gt;Ron and Luna Lovegood&lt;/strong&gt; are soulmates.  This is easily accomplished.
Allow me to draw your attention to two passages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, from &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron is here declaring his
intention to exert his prefect powers over Gregory Goyle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For heaven&amp;rdquo;s sake, Ron &amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll make Goyle do lines, it&amp;rsquo;ll kill him, he hates writing,&amp;rdquo; said
Ron happily. He lowered his voice to Goyle&amp;rdquo;s low grunt and, screwing
up his face in a look of pained concentration, mimed writing in
midair. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I … must … not … look … like … a … baboon&amp;rdquo;s … backside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone laughed, but nobody laughed harder than Luna Lovegood. She
let out a scream of mirth that caused Hedwig to wake up and flap her
wings indignantly and Crookshanks to leap up into the luggage rack,
hissing. Luna laughed so hard her magazine slipped out of her grasp,
slid down her legs and on to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was &lt;em&gt;funny!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her prominent eyes swam with tears as she gasped for breath, staring
at Ron. Utterly nonplussed, he looked around at the others, who were
now laughing at the expression on Ron&amp;rsquo;s face and at the ludicrously
prolonged laughter of Luna Lovegood, who was rocking backwards and
forwards, clutching her sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you taking the mickey?&amp;rdquo; said Ron, frowning at her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baboon&amp;rsquo;s … backside!&amp;rdquo; she choked, holding her ribs (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter
10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luna is the only person who truly appreciates Ron&amp;rsquo;s humor.  This point
is repeated in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;He says very funny things
sometimes, doesn&amp;rdquo;t he?&amp;ldquo;), and we also learn that Ron find&amp;rsquo;s Luna&amp;rsquo;s wit
equally enchanting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could hear the match commentary from here,&amp;rdquo; said Ron, his voice
now shaking with laughter. &amp;ldquo;I hope Luna always commentates from now
on … &lt;em&gt;Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy&lt;/em&gt; … &amp;ldquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside.  Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy.  Surely, true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True love, however, was not to be.  Ron ended up with Hermione&amp;mdash;for a
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;“It is too late, you understand me?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did Ron end up with Hermione, when our souls cried out in protest
and even Rowling knew it was wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, ultimately, is that &lt;em&gt;it had to be so&lt;/em&gt;.  The course of Time
is fixed, and Ron&amp;rsquo;s choice of Hermione over Luna was a matter of cruel
necessity.  The course of Time is fixed: it is forever true that
Ronbledore went back in time, and so nothing can occur that would
alter that fact.  &lt;strong&gt;And Ron would not have gone back in time,
had he married Luna.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had he married his soulmate, had the baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside been blessed to
suffer from Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy for all of his days, then Ron would have
been happy.  He would have lived his life, content, no longer jealous
of Harry&amp;rsquo;s fame because the one person in the world who understands
him would be always by his side.  There would have been no dissatisfaction,
no reckless urges to break free of a dreary day-to-day and make a
dramatic break with the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But happiness was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron married Hermione, and suffered.  It was for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; reason that he
eventually went back in time, to escape the marriage he knew was wrong
and to &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; something of himself, somewhere where he would not
always be compared to the Boy Who Lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere?  Some&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;How to keep soulmates apart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question remains, however, that torments all gentle hearts: how is
it &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that Ron ended up with Hermione, when true love was
staring him in the face?  What could have prevented such a man from
pursuing Luna Lovegood and winning her hand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, or who?&lt;/strong&gt;  Attend to this passage from &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s a Gurdyroot,&amp;rdquo; she said, stuffing the cat litter and the
toadstool back into her bag. &amp;ldquo;You can keep it if you like, I&amp;rsquo;ve got
a few of them. They&amp;rsquo;re really excellent for warding off Gulping
Plimpies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she walked away, leaving Ron chortling, still clutching the
Gurdyroot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know, she&amp;rsquo;s grown on me, Luna,&amp;rdquo; he said, as they set off again
for the Great Hall. &amp;ldquo;I know she&amp;rdquo;s insane, but it&amp;rdquo;s in a good&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped talking very suddenly. Lavender Brown was standing at the
foot of the marble staircase looking thunderous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi,&amp;rdquo; said Ron nervously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;C&amp;rsquo;mon,&amp;rdquo; Harry muttered to Hermione, and they sped past, though not
before they had heard Lavender say, &amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you tell me you were
getting out today? And why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; with you?&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you beginning to understand?  When Lavender says &amp;ldquo;why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;
with you&amp;rdquo;, she is not referring to Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now look!  Look at this passage from &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I like this song,&amp;rdquo; said Luna, swaying in time to the waltz-like
tune, and a few seconds later she stood up and glided on to the
dance floor, where she revolved on the spot, quite alone, eyes
closed and waving her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s great, isn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo; said Ron admiringly. &amp;ldquo;Always good value.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the smile vanished from his face at once: Viktor Krum had
dropped into Luna&amp;rsquo;s vacant seat. Hermione looked pleasurably
flustered, but this time Krum had not come to compliment her. With a
scowl on his face he said, &amp;ldquo;Who is that man in the yellow?&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt;
chapter 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever Ron admires Luna, whenever his heart is on the verge of
telling him its truth, &lt;strong&gt;a time-traveling witch or wizard arrives to
distract him.&lt;/strong&gt;  The most heartbreaking part of this is that these
magical anti-Cupids are most likely sent by Ronbledore himself, during
his Dumbledore years.  He knows that he &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; marry Hermione in order
to fulfill his destiny, and so deliberately undermines his own
happiness for the sake of the wizarding world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me now in a moment of silence for the &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; great sacrifices
Ronbledore makes: first, his life, and then his love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are ways to stop even a Hufflepuff from finding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/unplottable</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, places like Hogwarts are hidden from unwelcome eyes
with a number of protective enchantments.  One of these enchantments
makes the building &lt;em&gt;unplottable&lt;/em&gt;, and so&amp;mdash;apparently&amp;mdash;incapable
of being plotted on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not immediately obvious how this is possible.  Some of the
simpler and more obvious proposals as to how Unplottability might work
turn out to be no good.  Unplottability cannot not say anything about
what I can and can&amp;rsquo;t draw on a piece of paper.  It&amp;rsquo;s possible with
magic to prevent the information from being &lt;em&gt;transmitted,&lt;/em&gt; but this
won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to prevent us from using maps to find Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work is something more drastic: Unplottability has to
prevent us from &lt;em&gt;inferring&lt;/em&gt; the location of a place from other
information.  The benefit of this radical solution is that it
preserves the spirit of Unplottability, which is to prevent people
from figuring out &lt;em&gt;where Hogwarts is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What we know about unplottability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of Unplottability is in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hidden,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, in surprise, &amp;ldquo;everyone
knows that &amp;hellip; well, everyone who&amp;rsquo;s read &lt;em&gt;Hogwarts: A History&lt;/em&gt;,
anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just you, then,&amp;rdquo; said Ron. &amp;ldquo;So go on&amp;mdash;how d&amp;rsquo;you hide a place
like Hogwarts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bewitched,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If a Muggle looks at it, all they
see is a mouldering old ruin with a sign over the entrance saying
DANGER, DO NOT ENTER, UNSAFE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Durmstrang&amp;rsquo;ll just look like a ruin to an outsider, too?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, shrugging, &amp;ldquo;or it might have
Muggle-Repelling Charms on it, like the World Cup Stadium. And to
keep foreign wizards from finding it, they&amp;rsquo;ll have made it
Unplottable&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can enchant a building so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to plot on a
map, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er &amp;hellip; if you say so,&amp;rdquo; said Harry (&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure how disguising Hogwarts as a ruin will keep out
Muggle archaeologists, but that&amp;rsquo;s beside the point.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got one
fact about Unplottability: it can apply to buildings and it makes it
impossible to plot them on a map.  But we learn in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;
that it applies to individual rooms as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harry Potter, sir,&amp;rdquo; squeaked Dobby, his great orblike eyes shining
in the firelight, &amp;ldquo;the Malfoy boy is breaking no rules that Dobby
can discover, but he is still keen to avoid detection. He has been
making regular visits to the seventh floor with a variety of other
students, who keep watch for him while he enters&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Room of Requirement!&amp;rdquo; said Harry, smacking himself hard on the
forehead with &lt;em&gt;Advanced Potion-Making&lt;/em&gt;. Hermione and Ron stared at
him. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s where he’s been sneaking off to!  That&amp;rsquo;s where he&amp;rsquo;s
doing … whatever he&amp;rsquo;s doing! And I bet that&amp;rsquo;s why he&amp;rsquo;s been
disappearing off the map&amp;mdash;come to think of it, I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen the
Room of Requirement on there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe the Marauders never knew the Room was there,&amp;rdquo; said Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;ll be part of the magic of the Room,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione. &amp;ldquo;If
you need it to be Unplottable, it will be&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting aside whether the Room &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Unplottable or not, all the
evidence we&amp;rsquo;ve got so far is compatible with Unplottability being
nothing more than a restriction on what can be written down on a map.
But if the &lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of Unplottability is to keep the location of a
place secret, this hardly seems sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s textual support in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; for
Unplottability being more than this sort of limited restriction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Number 12, Grimmauld Place is] ideal for Headquarters, of course,&amp;rdquo;
Sirius said. &amp;ldquo;My father put every security measure known to
wizardkind on it when he lived here. It&amp;rsquo;s unplottable, so Muggles
could never come and call&amp;mdash;as if they&amp;rsquo;d ever have wanted to&amp;mdash;and
now Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s added his protection, you&amp;rsquo;d be hard put to find a
safer house anywhere&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, Sirius can&amp;rsquo;t be right when he says that Muggles
could &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; come and call.  Durmstrang&amp;mdash;and, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume,
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;are Unplottable, but students have to be able to get there
somehow.  Likewise, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the fact that Number 12 is
&lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; protected by the Fidelius Charm, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how any sort of
&lt;em&gt;Unplottability&lt;/em&gt; could have prevented a Muggle from walking up to the
front door, unaided by any map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Unplottability can at least &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; prevent Muggles from
finding Number 12, then it&amp;rsquo;s clearly more than a restriction on what
can be drawn on a map.  But this leaves unexplained exactly what
Unplottability is and how it &lt;em&gt;works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Maybe I can draw you a map, but you can&amp;rsquo;t understand it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen that Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just be about what I can or can&amp;rsquo;t
draw on a piece of paper.  More precisely, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just prevent me
encoding certain information on a map.  It has to also keep people
from &lt;em&gt;getting&lt;/em&gt; to the place that&amp;rsquo;s Unplottable.  So the obvious idea
is that Unplottability somehow prevents us from &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; a map to
locate Hogwarts (or any other Unplottable location).  How would that work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read a map, I assume that the author &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to plot the
locations of certain places on their map.  I read the map with the
belief that it is written with a &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt;.  When I
find the location of a place on the map, I believe that I am
&lt;em&gt;recognizing the communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; of the author, which is to
communicate to me the location of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do not believe that there is this sort of communicative
intention, I will probably not assume that I can use the map to find
the locations of places.  If I am a schoolteacher and I have my
students create maps of imaginary places, I will not pore over them
later to learn the locations of the places &amp;ldquo;plotted&amp;rdquo; on the maps.  I
know that they were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; drawn with that sort of communicative
intention, and so I would not&amp;mdash;mistakenly&amp;mdash;take them to be real maps
of real geographic areas.  I would not &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; anything from the maps
because I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is anything to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s a possible explanation for how Unplottability works: it
prevents us from recognizing the &lt;em&gt;communicative intention&lt;/em&gt; behind maps
of Unplottable locations.  Even if a witch or wizard finds a map on
which Hogwarts &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been plotted, the effect of Unplottability would
be to block the recognition of the mapmaker&amp;rsquo;s communicative intention.
The reader would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; believe that they are reading a map showing the
location of Hogwarts, but will instead be in a situation similar to
the schoolteacher looking over the students&amp;rsquo; maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of unplottability would play out in strange ways.  If I
plotted a map of Hogwarts, then pushed it across the table at you,
saying &amp;ldquo;Look!  I plotted Hogwarts on this map; you can use it to learn
its location&amp;rdquo;, you would somehow nonetheless fail to recognize the
communicative intention of the map.  You might suppose that I
&lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I have plotted Hogwarts but haven&amp;rsquo;t, or that I am only
&lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to plot a map, like the students were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what it would be like to experience this
situation, but that&amp;rsquo;s no objection to the theory: &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s magic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an objection to this theory (which was
brought to my attention by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;I can still find Hogwarts if I can&amp;rsquo;t read your map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map is a &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; map of Hogwarts, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t,
strictly speaking, show the location of the castle.  But since it
shows the secret passages leading to Hogsmeade, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
figure out where Hogsmeade and Hogwarts are in relation to each other.
Hogsmeade is almost certainly plottable, so using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map
to learn the location of Hogsmeade is unproblematic.  But &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt;
Hogsmeade is plottable, we can easily find it on a map, and
therefore&amp;mdash;because we used the Map to find the relative location of
Hogwarts&amp;mdash;locate Hogwarts.  We&amp;rsquo;re using maps only to find plottable
locations, but by learning of the location of Hogsmeade &lt;em&gt;relative to
Hogwarts&lt;/em&gt;, this process allows us to bypass Hogwarts&amp;rsquo; unplottability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking that this loophole probably only affects
Hogwarts, because no other unplottable locations have (a)
comprehensive internal maps and (b) passages leading out towards
plottable locations.  So who cares, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things are actually much much worse than this.  We can learn the
location of Hogwarts relative to Hogsmeade by using the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s
Map, but we can also figure it out by &lt;em&gt;walking there&lt;/em&gt;.  The Map isn&amp;rsquo;t
actually the problem.  I can just as easily walk from Durmstrang to
the first plottable village.  &lt;em&gt;Boom&lt;/em&gt;, I know where Durmstrang is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Unplottability can&amp;rsquo;t just consist in preventing me from recognizing
a communicative intention.  It has to be something more, if it&amp;rsquo;s going
to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, and if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, therefore &amp;hellip; what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/docs/unplottable.html&#34;&gt;earlier version&lt;/a&gt; of this
essay concluded that Unplottability was impossible.  Jacob T. Levy,
Tomlinson Professor of Political Theory at McGill University, found
that pessimism unwarranted and proposed a solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s easy;just use an SEP field! Interfere with the intention to *either* draw a map or use a map (or 2 maps)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429670387501117441&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/helenoftroyius&#34;&gt;@helenoftroyius&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;@dunndunndunn&lt;/a&gt; This combines #2 and #3 w rule that if I try to put Marauder&amp;#39;s Map &amp;amp; Hogsmeade maps together I... ooh! shiny!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jtlevy (@jtlevy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jtlevy/statuses/429671149165752320&#34;&gt;February 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An S.E.P., or Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s Problem, field,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hitchhikers.wikia.com/wiki/Somebody_Else&#34; title=&#34;s_Problem_field
&amp;quot;Hitchhiker Wiki&#34;&gt;utilizes a person&amp;rsquo;s natural tendency to ignore things they don&amp;rsquo;t easily accept&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by causing them to simply &lt;em&gt;ignore&lt;/em&gt; certain
information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any object around which a S.E.P. [field] is applied will cease to be
noticed, because any problems one may have understanding it (and
therefore accepting its existence) become Somebody Else&amp;rsquo;s. An object
becomes not so much invisible as unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect example of this would be a ship covered in a S.E.P. field at
a cricket match. A star ship taking the appearance of a large pink
elephant is ideal &amp;hellip; you can see it, but because it is so
inconceivable, your mind can&amp;rsquo;t accept it. Therefore it can&amp;rsquo;t exist,
thus [you ignore it].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proposal raises difficult and delicate questions in the
philosophy of mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to answer.  But it also
suggests an even simpler solution: whenever I try to infer &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; some
pieces of information &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the location of Hogwarts, the
Unplottability enchantment blocks that inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walk from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, measuring the distance, I may
end up with this bit of knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I walked 1km, northwest, from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be obvious at first, but just knowing that does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean
that one automatically knows this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hogwarts is 1km southeast of Hogsmeade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; (2) from (1), but I have to know some other things as
well.  Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;i&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walk a certain distance from point &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; to point &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is that far from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is a certain distance from &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is the same distance from &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is northwest of &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is southeast of &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course all these things are &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;, so we don&amp;rsquo;t usually think
about how we rely on them for drawing equally obvious conclusions like
(2).  But we do rely on them, and we also rely on &lt;em&gt;inference rules&lt;/em&gt;
that allow us to move from our premises to our conclusion.  For
example, just to conclude that Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade, I have
to reason like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I walked 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore&lt;/em&gt;, Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Therefore&amp;rdquo; marks the point at which I make an inference.  If I
somehow fail to see that there is a valid inference to be made, I may
be left with only the first two pieces of information, not knowing
whether Hogwarts is 1km from Hogsmeade or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I suggest, is exactly the situation I will be in, because the
Unplottability enchantment will prevent me from making inferences
that would allow me to learn the location of Hogwarts.  I will be like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://alexdunn.info/docs/carroll1895.pdf&#34; title=&#34;What the Tortoise Said to Achilles&#34;&gt;Lewis Carroll&amp;rsquo;s Tortoise&lt;/a&gt;, except unable&amp;mdash;rather than
simply unwilling&amp;mdash;to see that if &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is true, and &lt;em&gt;A then B&lt;/em&gt; is
true, that &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; must be true as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, even if I know where Hogsmeade is, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; know that I have to
walk 1km from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, because Hogwarts is Unplottable I
&lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; use this information to determine where Hogwarts is, because
I simply fail to make the simple but necessary inferences.  Likewise,
after their adventure in the flying Ford Anglia in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets,&lt;/em&gt; Harry and Ron might know both where King&amp;rsquo;s Cross Station is
and how far they traveled to get to Hogwarts, but Unplottability
prevents them from thereby deducing where Hogwarts is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to think that this enchantment could only prevent
inferences from map-based information; it would hardly honor the
spirit of the spell to suppose that if I had learn where Hogsmeade is
without using a map, that I could then determine the location of
Hogwarts.  If the purpose of Unplottability is to keep the location of
a place secret, then a blanket ban on the sorts of inferences that
would betray that secret seems entirely plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#8217;s no such thing as the Trace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/trace</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 12:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/trace</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Much is made in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; about &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;, the charm on
underage witches and wizards that is used by the Ministry to detect
illegal spellwork.  The problem is that there is no such thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo; supposed to be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most extended explanation of the Trace is given by Mad-Eye Moody
in &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second problem: you&amp;rsquo;re under-age, which means you&amp;rsquo;ve still got the
Trace on you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Trace, the Trace!&amp;rdquo; said Mad-Eye impatiently.  &amp;ldquo;The charm that
detects magical activity around under-seventeens, the way the
Ministry finds out about under-age magic!  If you, or anyone around
you, casts a spell to get you out of here, Thicknesse is going to
know about it, and so will the Death Eaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the Trace to break, because the moment you turn
seventeen you&amp;rsquo;ll lose all the protection your mother gave you.  In
short: Pius Thicknesse thinks he&amp;rsquo;s got you cornered good and
proper.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry could not help but agree with the unknown Thicknesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So what are we going to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going to use the only means of transport left to us, the only
ones the Trace can&amp;rsquo;t detect, because we don&amp;rsquo;t need to cast spells to
use them: brooms, Thestrals and Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s motorbike&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter
4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trace apparently allows the Ministry to know &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; about the
location of underage wizards, in order to determine if they are
breaking the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage
Sorcery.  The Ministry has separate, unspecified ways of knowing when
and where magic is performed in the United Kingdom; the Trace does
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; specifically tell the Ministry when an underage witch or wizard
&lt;em&gt;performs&lt;/em&gt; magic.  The Trace, in conjunction with the aforementioned
unspecified magic detection mechanisms, allows the Ministry to know
when magic is performed in close proximity to an underage witch or
wizard (the canny reader will see from the above quote that there&amp;rsquo;s
already a problem; but we&amp;rsquo;ll come to that).  This is what leads to the
Ministry issuing Harry with a warning when Dobby explodes a cake in #4
Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Mr Potter,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have received intelligence that a Hover Charm was used at your
place of residence this evening at twelve minutes past nine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As you know, underage wizards are not permitted to perform spells
outside school, and further spellwork on your part may lead to
expulsion from said school (Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of
Underage Sorcery, 1875, Paragraph C).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would also ask you to remember that any magical activity which
risks notice by members of the non-magical community (Muggles) is a
serious offence, under section 13 of the International Confederation
of Warlocks&amp;rsquo; Statute of Secrecy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy your holidays!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mafalda Hopkirk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improper Use of Magic Office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ministry of Magic&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;CoS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, sadly, this is all a terrible vicious lie.  The Trace does not
exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t it exist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;, Dumbledore shows Harry the recorded memory
of Morfin&amp;rsquo;s meeting with Voldemort.  Dumbledore explains that it is
nearly certain that Voldemort Stunned Morfin, took his wand, and
murdered the Riddle family.  Harry points out a rather large problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But how come the Ministry didn&amp;rsquo;t realise that Voldemort had done
all that to Morfin?&amp;rdquo; Harry asked angrily.  &amp;ldquo;He was under age at the
time, wasn&amp;rsquo;t he?  I thought they could detect under-age magic!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are quite right&amp;mdash;they can detect magic, but not the
perpetrator: you will remember that you were blamed by the Ministry
for the Hover Charm that was, in fact, cast by&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dobby,&amp;rdquo; growled Harry; this injustice still rankled.  &amp;ldquo;So if you&amp;rsquo;re
under age and you do magic inside an adult witch or wizard&amp;rsquo;s house,
the Ministry won&amp;rsquo;t know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They will certainly be unable to tell who performed the magic,&amp;rdquo;
said Dumbledore, smiling slightly at the look of great indignation
on Harry&amp;rsquo;s face.  &amp;ldquo;They rely on witch and wizard parents to enforce
their offspring&amp;rsquo;s obedience while within their walls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s rubbish,&amp;rdquo; snapped Harry. &amp;ldquo;Look what happened here,
look what happened to Morfin!&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we basically already knew that because of the Dobby thing.  We
already know why Voldemort didn&amp;rsquo;t get in trouble for doing magic at
the Gaunt House.  But &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;there were no other witches or wizards at the
Riddle house when Voldemort killed them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  How did the Ministry fail
to notice &lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter
Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;three uses of Avada Kedavra by a sixteen-year old in a
Muggle home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few theories have surfaced to explain this inconsistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Talk:The_Trace#As_to_the_inconsistency_regarding_Tom_Riddle...&#34; title=&#34;Talk page for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot; on the Harry Potter Wikia&#34;&gt;Voldemort was not underage when he killed the Riddles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cedric Diggory was 17 in his sixth year, allowing him to enter the
Triwizard Tournament.  Wikia user Thanksherman proposes that
Voldemort was similarly old for his cohort, allowing him to come of
age and act without the Trace in his sixth year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this theory is twofold: Not only does Dumbledore
not contradict Harry above when Harry asks how Voldemort could
have done magic without it being detected by the Ministry,
Dumbledore explicitly claims that Voldemort was then Harry&amp;rsquo;s
age&amp;mdash;and Harry wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn 17 for some time.  When discussing
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s conversation with Horace Slughorn (which occurs after
the Riddle House incident), Dumbledore says to Harry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am sure you understood the significance of what we just
heard.  At the same age as you are now, give or take a few
months, Tom Riddle was doing all he could to find out how to
make himself immortal&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 23).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trace works in strange ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only sketchy descriptions of the Trace in the books,
leaving open the possibility that the Trace works in unintuitive
ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that the Trace breaks when a witch or wizard
turns 17, and the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Muggles%27_Guide_to_Harry_Potter/Magic/Underage_Sorcery#Analysis&#34; title=&#34;Wikibooks: Muggles&#39; Guide to Harry Potter---Underage Sorcery&#34;&gt;keep tabs on the locations of adult wizards&lt;/a&gt;;
otherwise in &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt; they would have chased after any
adult witches and wizards found in odd locations; Harry, Ron, and
Hermione would have been caught in short order.  (How the hell they
know that Harry casts his Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;in
the presence of a Muggle&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Dudley&amp;mdash;would be another troubling
question, if the Trace exists.  But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Ministry can&amp;rsquo;t track the locations of underage witches and
wizards &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt;.  You&amp;rsquo;d be forgiven for thinking so, since as
much is implied in &lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wondered,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione tentatively, &amp;ldquo;whether Harry could
still have the Trace on him?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Impossible,&amp;rdquo; said Lupin. Ron looked smug, and Harry felt hugely
relieved. &amp;ldquo;Apart from anything else, they&amp;rsquo;d know for sure Harry
was here if he still had the Trace on him, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they? But I
can&amp;rsquo;t see how they could have tracked you to Tottenham Court
Road, that&amp;rsquo;s worrying, really worrying&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the quote at the very beginning of this essay, Moody states
explicitly that the Ministry &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; track underage witches and
wizards.  If they could, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether Harry traveled
from Privet Drive by Portkey, Thestral, broom, or Apparition.  And
in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;, Scrimgeour asks Harry where he went with Dumbledore
before the latter&amp;rsquo;s death, something he would know if the Trace
allowed the Ministry to actually track underage witches and
wizards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; can the Ministry know whether a bit
of magic, performed near a Traced person, is plausibly underage
sorcery or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry might keep a list of underage wizards &lt;em&gt;known to be
alone&lt;/em&gt; or otherwise without magical supervision.  Harry would fall
in this category, as well as Muggleborns and other special cases
(like Voldemort at the orphanage).  Warnings are only sent when
magic is performed in the vicinity of these people&amp;rsquo;s homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this this just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem true: when the Advance Guard
removes Harry from Privet Drive, Tonks casts several spells,
apparently with no repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/The_Trace#Limitations&#34; title=&#34;Harry Potter Wikia entry for \&amp;quot;The Trace\&amp;quot;, section on
\&amp;quot;Limitations\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;usual reply here&lt;/a&gt; is that the Ministry is notified when adult
witches and wizards (Arthur Weasley in &lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;,
Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;) are going to visit.  The Ministry then
supposedly ignores magic for the duration of the visit.  But the
Ministry does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know that the Advance Guard removed Harry from
Privet Drive.  Allowing the &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; to take Harry
to the home of &lt;em&gt;Sirius Black&lt;/em&gt; does not seem like something the
Fudge administration would do.  Moreover, during Harry&amp;rsquo;s
disciplinary hearing, it&amp;rsquo;s made explicit that the Ministry
believes him to be still residing at Privet Drive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry,&amp;rdquo; said Harry nervously.  &amp;ldquo;I&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the time
had been changed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That is not the Wizengamot&amp;rsquo;s fault,&amp;rdquo; said the voice. &amp;ldquo;An
owl was sent to you this morning. Take your seat&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt;
chapter 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there&amp;rsquo;s some wiggle-room here as well; Fudge and
Umbridge are trying to get Harry expelled, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible they
arranged to have the letter sent to the wrong address.  But if
they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; figure out that Harry was living at #12 Grimmauld
Place, the Noble and Most Ancient House of Black, they would
surely suspect him of having contact with the last Black family
member (a fine excuse to detain him for questioning and
harassment).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No way is there such a thing as &amp;ldquo;the Trace&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s really going on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, why does everyone think it does?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; aren&amp;rsquo;t, well, &lt;em&gt;optimally rational&lt;/em&gt;.  Dumbledore
&lt;em&gt;tells&lt;/em&gt; Harry that underage witches and wizards can do magic in the
home of an adult witch or wizard, and Harry &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t do magic
at the Burrow until he turns 17 and gets all excited.  Dumbledore
nearly allows Katie Bell &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Ron to die because he can&amp;rsquo;t think of a plausible pretext to
confront Malfoy about his whole assassination plan in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood
Prince&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron never realized he&amp;rsquo;s allowed to do magic at home and
peels sprouts by hand for 17 years.  Hermione&amp;rsquo;s pretty smart I guess,
but she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really show a strong understanding of the Trace
either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; stretch to assume that it&amp;rsquo;s a lie spread by the
(equally inept) Ministry to control the magical population.  The
Ministry isn&amp;rsquo;t competent enough to actually implement the Trace, but the rest
are willing to believe in it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But questions remain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Dobby&amp;rsquo;s Hover Charm in &lt;em&gt;Chamber of
Secrets&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did the Ministry learn about Aunt Marge&amp;rsquo;s big mistake, in order
to send people to Privet Drive to deflate her?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did Ministry learn about Harry&amp;rsquo;s Patronus in &lt;em&gt;Order of the
Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best guess at an answer to all three is &amp;hellip; Mrs Figg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Whaaaaaa?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I don&amp;rsquo;t like these sorts of conspiracy theories either.  But
she&amp;rsquo;s always near Privet Drive, and the only not-obviously-canon claim
I&amp;rsquo;m making is that she works for the Ministry rather than for
Dumbledore. (You could even argue that there is textual support for
this claim.  The tents that Mr. Weasley borrows from his Ministry
colleague Perkins in &lt;em&gt;GoF&lt;/em&gt; are &amp;ldquo;furnished in exactly the same sort of
style as Mrs. Figg&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; apartment (chapter 7), and also smell of cats;
if Perkins modeled his tents after Figg&amp;rsquo;s apartment, then that
suggests she is in regular contact with at least one Ministry
employee.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arabella Figg&amp;mdash;or one of her cats&amp;mdash;saw the Hover Charm (whether or
not they saw Dobby), saw Marge explode, and saw the Patronus (even if
&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20110721042840/http://www.jkrowling.com/textonly/en/extrastuff_view.cfm?id=19&#34; title=&#34;Archive of JK Rowling&#39;s site: Extra Stuff \(Squibs\)&#34;&gt;she couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the Dementors&lt;/a&gt;).  She did
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; see the Weasleys travel to the Dursley&amp;rsquo;s by Floo Powder, or see
the Advance Guard arrive in &lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, or Dumbledore in &lt;em&gt;HBP&lt;/em&gt;.  Maybe she
was asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the books state that she &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see the Patronus, and so she could
have communicated with the Ministry immediately after (using her own
Patronus&amp;mdash;if she&amp;rsquo;s only pretending to be a Squib&amp;mdash;or using a mirror
like the one Sirius gives to Harry or a Protean-Charmed object like
the DA coins).  That situation was already suspicious, because she
claims that she knew about Mundungus running off right away, but
didn&amp;rsquo;t bother contacting Harry and telling him to stay inside.  So
either she was lying about that, or knew Mundungus left to buy
cauldrons but had Ministry orders not to warn Harry (the Dementors
&lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; sent by Umbridge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose Mrs Figg was spying on Harry for the Ministry because he&amp;rsquo;s
important and the Ministry wants to keep tabs on him.  Other
high-profile witches and wizards presumably get the same treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;An objection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might cry: &amp;ldquo;But surely a simpler explanation is just as you
said&amp;mdash;the Ministry is inept!  It&amp;rsquo;s not that the Trace doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist,
but rather the Ministry is just really bad about following up on the
instances of magic it detects.  Depending on how the Trace works,
either they just didn&amp;rsquo;t notice Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s magic performed at the
Riddle House, or they failed to see that Tonks cast &lt;em&gt;Lumos&lt;/em&gt; and some
silly trunk-packing spell when the Advance Guard came to get Harry.
See, no need to drag poor Mrs Figg into your wild imagination!&amp;rdquo;  (This
objection is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zayalhawa&#34; title=&#34;Twitter
profile&#34;&gt;Aziza&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be a better explanation, but for one thing.  As I noted
above, when the Ministry takes Harry to task for his Patronus in
&lt;em&gt;OotP&lt;/em&gt;, they know something that only Mrs Figg (or another spy) could
know: that Harry performed magic in the presence of a Muggle: Dudley.
If the Ministry doesn&amp;rsquo;t track the relatively small adult magical
population, the idea that they might be tracking all Muggles is pretty
wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they be tracking just a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; Muggles of importance?&amp;rdquo;
Dudley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; important, though; he already knows about magic, so
seeing &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; magic isn&amp;rsquo;t a major breach of the Statute of Secrecy.
The Ministry just &lt;em&gt;pretends&lt;/em&gt; it is while they&amp;rsquo;re trying to expel
Harry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The complete guide to wand ownership in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/wands</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 08:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/wands</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Until &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;, we all thought &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; was just a
nifty spell that causes people to drop their wands and sometimes
knocks them over (which is why we had all those Tower Truthers saying
that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beyondhogwarts.com/harry-potter/articles/dumbledore-clues.html&#34; title=&#34;Beyond Hogwarts&#34;&gt;Dumbledore wasn&amp;rsquo;t
dead&lt;/a&gt;).
But then it turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;totally bonkers&lt;/em&gt;. Apparently
disarming someone actually &lt;em&gt;transfers their wand&amp;rsquo;s loyalty to you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is totally bonkers because &lt;em&gt;everybody disarms everybody&lt;/em&gt; at some
point.  So to figure out whose wand is whose and what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;
happened, let&amp;rsquo;s catalog every instance of disarming ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do that, though, we need to figure out when exactly a wand
changes owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not &lt;em&gt;exactly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;How &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; works (maybe)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason Harry has to finish He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named in the
&lt;em&gt;very same way&lt;/em&gt; that he beats You-Know-Who when he&amp;rsquo;s only a baby;
namely, by having Lord Thingy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra&lt;/em&gt; bounce off the Chosen
Boy like he&amp;rsquo;s some sort of magic mirror. In order to pull it off,
Rowling drops this tidbit on us two-thirds of the way through
&lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hawthorn and unicorn hair. Ten inches precisely. Reasonably
springy. This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Was?&amp;rdquo; repeated Harry. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it still his?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps not. If you took it&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;I did&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;then it may be yours.  Of course, the manner of taking matters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I took this wand from Draco Malfoy by force,&amp;rdquo; said Harry.  &amp;ldquo;Can I
use it safely?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think so. Subtle laws govern wand ownership, but the conquered
wand will usually bend its will to its new master&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter
24).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re prone to fits of charitability, you might think that all
this means is that, when you disarm someone else by force and take
their wand, &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; the wand &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;bend its will&amp;rdquo; to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you would be wrong! Check out this exchange from Harry&amp;rsquo;s rap
battle with Voldy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You still don&amp;rsquo;t get it, Riddle, do you? Possessing the wand isn&amp;rsquo;t
enough!  Holding it, using it, doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it really yours.  Didn&amp;rsquo;t
you listen to Ollivander?  &lt;em&gt;The wand chooses the wizard&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip; the
Elder Wand recognised a new master before Dumbledore died, someone
who never even laid a hand on it.  The new master removed the wand
from Dumbledore against his will, never realising exactly what he
had done, or that the world&amp;rsquo;s most dangerous wand had given him its
allegiance &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s chest rose and fell rapidly, and Harry could feel the
curse coming, feel it building inside the wand pointed at his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The true master of the Elder Wand was Draco Malfoy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blank shock showed in Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s face for a moment, but then it was
gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But what does it matter?&amp;rdquo; he said softly. &amp;ldquo;Even if you are right,
Potter, it makes no difference to you and me.  You no longer have
the phoenix wand: we duel on skill alone &amp;hellip; and after I have killed
you, I can attend to Draco Malfoy &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you&amp;rsquo;re too late,&amp;rdquo; said Harry.  &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve missed your chance.  I
got there first.  I overpowered Draco weeks ago.  I took this wand
from him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry twitched the hawthorn wand, and he felt the eyes of everyone
in the Hall upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So it all comes down to this, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; whispered Harry.  &amp;ldquo;Does
the wand in your hand know its last master was Disarmed?  Because if
it does &amp;hellip; I am the true master of the Elder Wand&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter
36).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t even have to &lt;em&gt;touch&lt;/em&gt; a wand to win it. And not only that,
when you disarm someone &lt;em&gt;you get all the wands&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;they&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;won&lt;/em&gt;.
That&amp;rsquo;s how Harry gets the Elder Wand by disarming Draco, even though
it&amp;rsquo;s tucked away in Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s tomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at least you do have to disarm the other person &lt;em&gt;by force&lt;/em&gt;, like
Ollivander says, right?  WRONG AGAIN:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now Harry was hurrying along a dark corridor in stout little
Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s wake as he held a lantern aloft: Gregorovitch burst
into the room at the end of the passage and his lantern illuminated
what looked like a workshop; wood-shavings and gold gleamed in the
swinging pool of light, and there on the window ledge sat perched,
like a giant bird, a young man with golden hair.  In the split
second that the lantern&amp;rsquo;s light illuminated him, Harry saw the
delight upon his handsome face, then the intruder shot a Stunning
Spell from his wand and jumped neatly backwards out of the window
with a crow of laughter (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grindelwald wins the Elder Wand by just sneaking into Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s
bedroom and nicking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we could get into fussy debates over &lt;em&gt;intention&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;malice&lt;/em&gt;,
and try to lay down some criteria for when nabbing someone else&amp;rsquo;s
wand &lt;em&gt;really counts&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;disarming&amp;rdquo; them and so transfers the
ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would be &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s just assume that anyone who grabs
someone else&amp;rsquo;s wand or otherwise disarms them gains ownership of
every wand that person owns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, which wands belong to who?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Swaps that happen before Harry starts at Hogwarts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just saw how Grindelwald steals the Elder wand from Gregorovitch.
Let&amp;rsquo;s write that down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 35&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think he knew it, I think he knew what frightened me.  I delayed
meeting him until, finally, it would have been too shameful to
resist any longer.  People were dying and he seemed unstoppable, and
I had to do what I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you know what happened next.  I won the duel. I won the
wand.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.  He lost Dumbledore long ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snape reacted so fast it was as though he had been expecting an
attack: dropping his bag, he plunged his hand inside his robes and
his wand was halfway into the air when James shouted,
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor Snivellus can never catch a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing. No wand, no dignity (we all saw his undies,
remember?), no Lily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 33&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a blinding, jagged jet of white light flew through the air:
Harry thought of lightning, but Snape had dropped to his knees and
his wand had flown out of his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t kill me!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was not my intention.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any sound of Dumbledore Apparating had been drowned by the sound of
the wind in the branches.  He stood before Snape with his robes
whipping around him, and his face was illuminated from below in the
light cast by his wand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like an &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;; Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s too weird for
any normal spells. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly some sort of disarming,
but&amp;mdash;woops&amp;mdash;James already disarmed Snivellus. Snape doesn&amp;rsquo;t own his
wand anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how things stand going into the first book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hermione had sunk to the floor in fright; Ron pulled out his own
wand&amp;mdash;not knowing what he was going to do he heard himself cry the
first spell that came into his head: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Wingardium Leviosa!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The club flew suddenly out of the troll&amp;rsquo;s hand, rose high, high up
into the air, turned slowly over&amp;mdash;and dropped, with a sickening
crack, on to its owner&amp;rsquo;s head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because why should we limit this to wands? How very close-minded. The
wand chooses the wizard, but the club chooses the mindless death
machine, too. (Ron is pretty mindless, so the club chose well here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club and his own wand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them swung their wands up and over their shoulders. Snape
cried: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  There was a dazzling flash of scarlet light
and Lockhart was blasted off his feet: he flew backwards off the
stage, smashed into the wall and slid down it to sprawl on the
floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good for Snivellus, he owns a wand again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing but his looks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS&lt;/em&gt; chapter 13&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percy said, &amp;ldquo;As a school Prefect&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;, but Harry had lost his temper.
He pulled out his wand and shouted, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and just as
Snape had disarmed Lockhart, so Malfoy found the diary shooting out
of his hand into the air.  Ron, grinning broadly, caught it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has his own wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; is going to have to buy new books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_10&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 16&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry reached his wand just in time. Lockhart had barely raised his,
when Harry bellowed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;  Lockhart was blasted
backwards, falling over his trunk.  His wand flew high into the air;
Ron caught it, and flung it out of the open window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dang, Lockhart already lost his wands.  Ron is actually throwing
&lt;em&gt;Snape&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; wand out the window.  &lt;strong&gt;No changes&lt;/strong&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get up,&amp;rdquo; said Ron sharply, pointing his wand at Lockhart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lockhart got to his feet&amp;mdash;then he dived at Ron, knocking him to the
ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry jumped forward, but too late. Lockhart was straightening up,
panting, Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand in his hand and a gleaming smile back on his
face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t Harry just &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; him again here? Possibly
because Harry is pathetic; but who knows, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_11&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CoS,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 18&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry, Ron, Hermione, Fred, George and Ginny got a compartment to
themselves. They made the most of the last few hours in which they
were allowed to do magic before the holidays. They played Exploding
Snap, set off the very last of Fred and George&amp;rsquo;s Filibuster
Fireworks, and practised disarming each other by magic. Harry was
getting very good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, since we don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; disarms &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; here (THANKS, J.K.),
let&amp;rsquo;s just suppose that, since &amp;ldquo;Harry was getting very good at it&amp;rdquo;,
he disarmed everyone else.  That makes sense, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands, and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s review the scores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands, and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has his own wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has a library card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_12&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_13&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it when Dad won the&lt;/em&gt; Daily Prophet &lt;em&gt;Draw.  Seven
hundred galleons!  Most of it&amp;rsquo;s gone on this holiday, but they&amp;rsquo;re
going to buy me a new wand for next year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron gets a new wand!  Since it probably &amp;ldquo;chose&amp;rdquo; him at Ollivander&amp;rsquo;s, I
don&amp;rsquo;t think it knows or cares that Lockhart disarmed him the previous
year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s old wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_14&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 17&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Sirius Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he croaked, pointing Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s and Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wands shot out of their hands, high in the
air, and Black caught them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like Sirius took Ron&amp;rsquo;s wand by force, then did some badass
double-disarmery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s new wand along with Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s,
Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; still has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Black&amp;rsquo;s free hand had found Harry&amp;rsquo;s throat&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; he hissed. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve waited too long&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fingers tightened, Harry choked, his glasses askew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he saw Hermione&amp;rsquo;s foot swing out of nowhere.  Black let go of
Harry with a grunt of pain.  Ron had thrown himself on Black&amp;rsquo;s wand
hand and Harry heard a faint clatter&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron proves himself not entirely useless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and
Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands, along with his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Lupin shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand flew once more out of his hand; so did the two Hermione
was holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione was holding her and Ron&amp;rsquo;s wands, but she didn&amp;rsquo;t take them by
force from Ron; he still owns them (and Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand), and Lupin
doesn&amp;rsquo;t disarm &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think Lupin wins anything here. He
wins whatever wands are Hermione&amp;rsquo;s and Harry&amp;rsquo;s, which are none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_15&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 19&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry made up his mind in a split second. Before Snape could take
even one step towards him, he had raised his wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he yelled&amp;mdash;except that his wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only voice
that shouted. There was a blast that made the door rattle on its
hinges; Snape was lifted off his feet and slammed into the wall,
then slid down it to the floor, a trickle of blood oozing from under
his hair. He had been knocked out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry looked around. Both Ron and Hermione had tried to disarm Snape
at exactly the same moment.  Snape&amp;rsquo;s wand soared in a high arc and
landed on the bed next to Crookshanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shit.  &lt;em&gt;Exactly&lt;/em&gt; the same moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boring interpretation is that since no one person disarmed Snape,
nobody wins his wands.  But that&amp;rsquo;s not our only option: look where the
wand lands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_16&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PoA,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 20&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pettigrew had dived for Lupin&amp;rsquo;s dropped wand. Ron, unsteady on his
bandaged leg, fell. There was a bang, a burst of light&amp;mdash;and Ron lay
motionless on the ground.  Another bang&amp;mdash;Crookshanks flew into the
air and back to the earth in a heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Harry yelled, pointing his own wand at Pettigrew;
Lupin&amp;rsquo;s wand flew high into the air and out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wands and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pettigrew&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s and
Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands, along with his new wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockhart&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s old wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_17&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_18&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss the fun, but Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s second
ornament narrowly missed his left ear, and on balance he thought it
best to leave the situation to Mr Weasley.  He stepped into the
fire, looking over his shoulder as he said, &amp;ldquo;The Burrow!&amp;rdquo;; his last
fleeting glimpse of the living room was of Mr Weasley blasting a
third ornament out of Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s hand with his wand, Aunt
Petunia screaming and lying on top of Dudley, and Dudley&amp;rsquo;s tongue
lolling around like a great slimy python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the Dursleys are going to have a pretty barren Christmas
tree, because &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; still has an epic mustache, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_19&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 35&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was starting to fight my father&amp;rsquo;s Imperius Curse.  There were
times when I was almost myself again. There were brief periods when
I seemed outside his control.  It happened, there, in the Top Box.
It was like waking from a deep sleep.  I found myself out in public,
in the middle of the match, and I saw a wand sticking out of a boy&amp;rsquo;s
pocket in front of me.  I had not been allowed a wand since before
Azkaban.  I stole it.  Winky didn&amp;rsquo;t know.  Winky is frightened of
heights.  She had her face hidden.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; still has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books, even though he doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve
them. He hasn&amp;rsquo;t read anything since Hermione started doing his
homework for him in the first year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_20&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 31&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was no use&amp;mdash;the spider was either so large, or so magical,
that the spells were doing no more than aggravating it&amp;mdash;Harry had
one horrifying glimpse of eight shining black eyes, and razor-sharp
pincers, before it was upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was lifted into the air in its front legs; struggling madly, he
tried to kick it; his leg connected with the pincers, and next
moment he was in excruciating pain&amp;mdash;he could hear Cedric yelling
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; too, but his spell had no more effect than
Harry&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;Harry raised his wand as the spider opened its pincers
once more, and shouted,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked&amp;mdash;the Disarming spell made the spider drop him, but that
meant that Harry fell twelve feet onto his already injured leg,
which crumpled beneath him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After disarming the spider, Harry no longer feels alienated from his
own body. He finds that he is more comfortable in his own skin and in
fact has better motor control too. (Now you might say, &amp;ldquo;Alex, that&amp;rsquo;s
ridiculous.&amp;rdquo;  Yes.  &lt;em&gt;But how else could he survive the graveyard?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_21&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoF,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 34&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voldemort was ready. As Harry shouted &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, Voldemort
cried &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A jet of green light issued from Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand just as a jet of
red light blasted from Harry&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;they met in mid-air&amp;mdash;and suddenly
Harry&amp;rsquo;s wand was vibrating as though an electric charge was surging
through it; his hand had seized up around it; he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have
released it if he&amp;rsquo;d wanted to&amp;mdash;and a narrow beam of light was now
connecting the two wands, neither red nor green, but bright, deep
gold&amp;mdash;and Harry, following the beam with his astonished gaze, saw
that Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s long white fingers, too, were gripping a wand that
was shaking and vibrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody gets disarmed here, we just get some &lt;em&gt;Priori Incantatem&lt;/em&gt;
nonsense.  So there are &lt;strong&gt;no changes&lt;/strong&gt; of wand ownership during this
&lt;em&gt;geist ex whatthefuck&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not enough changes here to do a whole recap of who-owns-what. Let&amp;rsquo;s
move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_22&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_23&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 18&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room was suddenly full of shouts of &lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;.  Wands flew
in all directions; missed spells hit books on shelves and sent them
flying into the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry was too quick for Neville, whose wand went spinning out of his
hand, hit the ceiling in a shower of sparks and landed with a
clatter on top of a bookshelf, from which Harry retrieved it with a
Summoning Charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand and Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; said Neville, and Harry, caught unawares, felt his
wand fly out of his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Draco&amp;rsquo;s books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something very odd was happening to Zacharias Smith.  Every time he
opened his mouth to disarm Anthony Goldstein, his own wand would fly
out of his hand, yet Anthony did not seem to be making a sound.
Harry did not have to look far to solve the mystery: Fred and George
were several feet from Smith and taking it in turns to point their
wands at his back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginny was teamed with Michael Corner; she was doing very well,
whereas Michael was either very bad or unwilling to jinx her.  Ernie
Macmillan was flourishing his wand unnecessarily, giving his partner
time to get in under his guard; the Creevey brothers were
enthusiastic but erratic and mainly responsible for all the books
leaping off the shelves around them; Luna Lovegood was similarly
patchy, occasionally sending Justin Finch-Fletchley&amp;rsquo;s wand spinning
out of his hand, at other times merely causing his hair to stand on
end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, my dad is very supportive of any anti-Ministry action!&amp;rdquo; said
Luna Lovegood proudly from just behind Harry; evidently she had been
eavesdropping on his conversation while Justin Finch-Fletchley
attempted to disentangle himself from the robes that had flown up
over his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and her wands and his hair and his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zacharias&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justin&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was really, really good, Harry,&amp;rdquo; said Hermione, when finally
it was just her, Harry and Ron who were left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, it was!&amp;rdquo; said Ron enthusiastically, as they slipped out of
the door and watched it melt back into stone behind them.  &amp;ldquo;Did you
see me disarm Hermione, Harry?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Hermione&amp;rsquo;s inexplicable attraction to Ron (the boy so solid he
cannot apparate half an inch across a room and who nobody likes) is
due to the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s always got her wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_24&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 32&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take his wand,&amp;rdquo; she barked at someone he could not see, and he felt
a hand grope inside the chest pocket of his robes and remove the
wand. &amp;ldquo;Hers, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry heard a scuffle over by the door and knew that Hermione had
also just had her wand wrested from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to know why you are in my office,&amp;rdquo; said Umbridge, shaking
the fist clutching his hair so that he staggered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it&amp;rsquo;s Malfoy disarming Harry and Millicent Bulstrode taking
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wand. (It&amp;rsquo;s always Millicent who gets Hermione. I wonder
if Hermione smells like Millicent&amp;rsquo;s cat because of the Polyjuice
episode and that makes Millicent inexplicably attracted to Hermione.
Huh.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Harry still doesn&amp;rsquo;t own a wand. Too bad Draco didn&amp;rsquo;t relieve
Harry of his homework planner, too; then Draco would get his books
back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hermione doesn&amp;rsquo;t have shit either.  &lt;strong&gt;No changes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a commotion outside and several large Slytherins entered,
each gripping Ron, Ginny, Luna and&amp;mdash;to Harry&amp;rsquo;s
bewilderment&amp;mdash;Neville, who was trapped in a stranglehold by Crabbe
and looked in imminent danger of suffocation.  All four of them had
been gagged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only gagged but also, presumably, disarmed.  The tricky thing here
is figuring out who disarmed who.  Warrington is holding Ron and
Crabbe has Neville, so they probably also took their wands, but the
other Slytherins are unnamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s
and Sirius&amp;rsquo; wands and Ron&amp;rsquo;s new wand, as well as his own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s and his wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and Luna&amp;rsquo;s wands and their own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_25&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 33&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you get away?&amp;rdquo; asked Harry in amazement, taking his wand
from Ron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couple of Stunners, a Disarming Charm, Neville brought off a really
nice little Impediment Jinx,&amp;rdquo; said Ron airily, now handing back
Hermione&amp;rsquo;s wand, too. &amp;ldquo;But Ginny was best, she got
Malfoy&amp;mdash;Bat-Bogey Hex&amp;mdash;it was superb, his whole face was covered
in the great flapping things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginny probably disarmed Malfoy, but otherwise we don&amp;rsquo;t have much to
help us figure out who disarmed who, or how they got their wands back
from the Slytherins in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to just say that each of our Heroes snatched their
wand from the person holding them&amp;mdash;their physical injuries support
this, maybe&amp;mdash;but even then, who got Millicent? The person who
disarmed Millicent was whoever cast the Disarming Charm
(&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt;, obvs), so it likely wasn&amp;rsquo;t Neville or Ginny. Given
Luna&amp;rsquo;s relative ineptitude with the spell, there&amp;rsquo;s a fair chance it
wasn&amp;rsquo;t her. So let&amp;rsquo;s say Ron disarmed Millicent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s,
Sirius&amp;rsquo;, Millicent&amp;rsquo;s and Warrington&amp;rsquo;s wands, along with his own new
wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club. (Dang. For someone so useless Ron sure
is useful.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own, as
well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_26&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 35&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry launched himself across the floor and grabbed the Death Eater
around the knees, causing him to topple and his aim to go awry.
Neville overturned a desk in his anxiety to help; and pointing his
wand wildly at the struggling pair, he cried:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;EXPELLIARMUS!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Harry&amp;rsquo;s and the Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wands flew out of their hands and
soared back towards the entrance to the Hall of Prophecy; both
scrambled to their feet and charged after them, the Death Eater in
front, Harry hot on his heels, and Neville bringing up the rear,
plainly horrorstruck by what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry fell to his knees beside her as Neville crawled rapidly
towards her from under the desk, his wand held up in front of
him. The Death Eater kicked out hard at Neville&amp;rsquo;s head as he
emerged&amp;mdash;his foot broke Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand in two and connected with
his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably counts as a disarming. Neville&amp;rsquo;s wands must have
finally realized how inept he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dolohov&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own (Neville&amp;rsquo;s is destroyed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s, Ginny&amp;rsquo;s,
Sirius&amp;rsquo;, Millicent&amp;rsquo;s and Warrington&amp;rsquo;s wands, along with his own new
wand and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own, as
well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing (the Creeveys have all the books).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; has an epic mustache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_27&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_28&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I thought Gran would be angry about all the publicity,&amp;rdquo; said
Neville, &amp;ldquo;but she was really pleased. Says I&amp;rsquo;m starting to live up
to my dad at long last. She bought me a new wand, look!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pulled it out and showed it to Harry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cherry and unicorn hair,&amp;rdquo; he said proudly. &amp;ldquo;We think it was one of
the last Ollivander ever sold, he vanished next day&amp;mdash;oi, come back
here, Trevor!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand and does not have Trevor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_29&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 27&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry hurried over to the door leading to the spiral staircase, but
his hand had only just closed upon the iron ring of the door when he
heard running footsteps on the other side.  He looked round at
Dumbledore, who gestured to him to retreat.  Harry backed away,
drawing his wand as he did so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door burst open and somebody erupted through it and shouted
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry&amp;rsquo;s body became instantly rigid and immobile, and he felt
himself fall back against the Tower wall, propped like an unsteady
statue, unable to move or speak. He could not understand how it had
happened&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; was not a Freezing Charm&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, by the light of the Mark, he saw Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s wand flying in
an arc over the edge of the ramparts and understood &amp;hellip; Dumbledore
had wordlessly immobilised Harry, and the second he had taken to
perform the spell had cost him the chance of defending himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oooh, this is the important one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, Gregorovitch&amp;rsquo;s, and his
own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_30&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Potter!&amp;rdquo; screamed Snape. There was a loud BANG and Harry was
soaring backwards, hitting the ground hard again, and this time his
wand flew out of his hand. He could hear Hagrid yelling and Fang
howling as Snape closed in and looked down on him where he lay,
wandless and defenceless as Dumbledore had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La la la, Harry doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a wand. But here we can at least
appreciate how J.K. uses all caps to great effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s, and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has his new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to repeat everyone&amp;rsquo;s wand ownership status again
because not much changed and this damn thing is getting so long. But
we&amp;rsquo;re almost done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_31&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_32&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry sent Stunning Spell after Stunning Spell back at their
pursuers, barely holding them off.  He shot another blocking jinx at
them: the closest Death Eater swerved to avoid it and his hood
slipped, and by the red light of his next Stunning Spell, Harry saw
the strangely blank face of Stanley Shunpike&amp;mdash;Stan&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Harry yelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Stan&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The youngest-ever Minister of Magic&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the pain from Harry&amp;rsquo;s scar forced his eyes shut, his wand acted
of its own accord.  He felt it drag his hand round like some great
magnet, saw a spurt of golden fire through his half-closed eyelids,
heard a crack and a scream of fury.  The remaining Death Eater
yelled; Voldemort screamed, &amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for sure a disarming. But Voldy&amp;rsquo;s using Lucius Malfoy&amp;rsquo;s wand,
so does Harry own that wand now? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so, because Lucius
wasn&amp;rsquo;t really disarmed. He was &lt;em&gt;coerced&lt;/em&gt; to give Voldemort his wand,
sure, but that probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_33&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mundungus scrambled up and pulled out his wand; Hermione, however,
was too quick for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mundungus&amp;rsquo;s wand soared into the air and Hermione caught it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mundungus&lt;/strong&gt; still has his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_34&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 21&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophilius licked his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They took my Luna,&amp;rdquo; he whispered. &amp;ldquo;Because of what I’ve been
writing. They took my Luna and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where she is, what
they&amp;rsquo;ve done to her. But they might give her back to me if I&amp;mdash;if
I&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we learn later, Luna lost her wand when she got pulled off the
Hogwarts Express.  Presumably a Death Eater took it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and Luna&amp;rsquo;s and
his own wands, as well as Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_35&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 23&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get up, vermin.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknown hands dragged Harry roughly off the ground. Before he could
stop them, someone had rummaged through his pockets and removed the
blackthorn wand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get&amp;mdash;off&amp;mdash;her!&amp;rdquo; Ron shouted.  There was the unmistakable sound of
knuckles hitting flesh: Ron grunted in pain and Hermione screamed,
&amp;ldquo;No! Leave him alone, leave him alone!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your boyfriend&amp;rsquo;s going to have worse than that done to him if he&amp;rsquo;s
on my list,&amp;rdquo; said the horribly familiar, rasping voice.  &amp;ldquo;Delicious
girl &amp;hellip; what a treat &amp;hellip; I do enjoy the softness of the skin &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone still got a wand?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; said Ron and Hermione from either side of him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, crap.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got even less to go on here than in Umbridge&amp;rsquo;s
office.  Greyback is the head of this band of Snatchers, so it might
be reasonable to assume that he&amp;rsquo;s just giving orders and not actually
disarming anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn a few pages later that Harry was disarmed by Scabior:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know &amp;lsquo;e&amp;rsquo;s swollen, ma&amp;rsquo;am, but it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;im!&amp;rdquo; piped up Scabior.  &amp;ldquo;If
you look a bit closer, you&amp;rsquo;ll see &amp;lsquo;is scar.  And this &amp;lsquo;ere, see the
girl?  The Mudblood who&amp;rsquo;s been travelling around with &amp;lsquo;im,
ma&amp;rsquo;am.  There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;im, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got &amp;lsquo;is wand as well!
&amp;lsquo;Ere, ma&amp;rsquo;am&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Narcissa Malfoy scrutinising his swollen face.  Scabior
thrust the blackthorn wand at her.  She raised her eyebrows (&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt;
311).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think all we can say is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scabior&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand (hahaha holy shit if he only knew).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 1&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 2&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s, Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Fred&amp;rsquo;s, George&amp;rsquo;s,
Ginny&amp;rsquo;s, Sirius&amp;rsquo;, and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 3&lt;/strong&gt; has Dean&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands (Dean is picked by the
same group of Snatchers).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a bang and a flash of red light: Harry knew that the
Snatcher had been Stunned. There was a roar of anger from his
fellows: Scabior drew his wand.  &amp;ldquo;What d&amp;rsquo;you think you&amp;rsquo;re playing
at, woman?&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; she screamed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were no match for her, even though there were four of them
against one of her: she was a witch, as Harry knew, with prodigious
skill and no conscience. They fell where they stood, all except
Greyback, who had been forced into a kneeling position, his arms
outstretched. Out of the corners of his eyes, Harry saw Bellatrix
bearing down upon the werewolf, the sword of Gryffindor gripped
tightly in her hand, her face waxen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where did you get this sword?&amp;rdquo; she whispered to Greyback as she
pulled his wand out of his unresisting grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really too bad that Greyback didn&amp;rsquo;t disarm Harry et al., instead
of Scabior and the other shitheart Snatchers. Too bad Bellatrix didn&amp;rsquo;t
disarm instead of stun them. Then she would have &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. Oh
well; the truth is sacred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wand and her own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greyback&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And we&amp;rsquo;ll have that,&amp;rdquo; whispered Ron, tugging Wormtail&amp;rsquo;s wand from
his other hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ollivander says this should work, but Barty Crouch Jr. owns Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s
wand, so Ron&amp;rsquo;s out of luck. &lt;strong&gt;No changes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron had burst into the drawing room; Bellatrix looked round,
shocked; she turned her wand to face Ron instead&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he roared, pointing Wormtail&amp;rsquo;s wand at Bellatrix,
and hers flew into the air and was caught by Harry, who had sprinted
after Ron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ronnie the Bear shows his quality!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yeah, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking: Harry caught the wand, so are we
sure &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t own it? Pretty sure. If Filch had caught the Elder
wand as it fell from the tower when Dumbledore was disarmed, would he
have been the true owner of the Elder Wand?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s and Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chandelier crashed to the floor in an explosion of crystal and
chains, falling on top of Hermione and the goblin, who still
clutched the sword of Gryffindor.  Glittering shards of crystal flew
in all directions: Draco doubled over, his hands covering his bloody
face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ron ran to pull Hermione out of the wreckage, Harry took his
chance; he leapt over an armchair and wrested the three wands from
Draco&amp;rsquo;s grip, pointed all of them at Greyback and yelled:
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupefy!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; The werewolf was lifted off his feet by the triple
spell, flew up to the ceiling and then smashed to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, damn, it looks like J.K. Rowling&amp;rsquo;s wacky scheme might work!
Draco was holding his, Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s, and Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Draco&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, and Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kill him, Cissy!&amp;rdquo; shrieked Bellatrix, but there was another loud
&lt;em&gt;crack&lt;/em&gt;, and Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand, too, flew into the air and landed on the
other side of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You dirty little monkey!&amp;rdquo; bawled Bellatrix.  &amp;ldquo;How dare you take a
witch&amp;rsquo;s wand, how dare you defy your masters?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dobby&lt;/strong&gt; has Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NO MASTER&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narcissa&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_36&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 26&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Ollivander had sent Luna a new wand that morning. She was out on
the back lawn at that moment, testing its capabilities in the late
afternoon sun. Dean, who had lost his wand to the Snatchers, was
watching rather gloomily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has her new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands as well as Luna&amp;rsquo;s old wands, and Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_37&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 31&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s that Mudblood! &lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry saw Hermione dive aside and his fury that Crabbe had aimed to
kill wiped all else from his mind.  He shot a Stunning Spell at Crabbe,
who lurched out of the way, knocking Malfoy&amp;rsquo;s wand out of his hand; it
rolled out of sight beneath a mountain of broken furniture and boxes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t kill him!  DON&amp;rsquo;T KILL HIM!&amp;rdquo;  Malfoy yelled at Crabbe and
Goyle, who were both aiming at Harry: their split second&amp;rsquo;s
hesitation was all Harry needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyle&amp;rsquo;s wand flew out of his hand and disappeared into the bulwark
of objects beside him; Goyle leapt foolishly on the spot, trying to
retrieve it; Malfoy jumped out of range of Hermione&amp;rsquo;s second
Stunning Spell and Ron, appearing suddenly at the end of the aisle,
shot a full Body-Bind Curse at Crabbe, which narrowly missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draco didn&amp;rsquo;t really own his mother&amp;rsquo;s wand, and he certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t
own his own, so Crabbe doesn&amp;rsquo;t get anything out of disarming his
boss. But he&amp;rsquo;s about to die, so that&amp;rsquo;s really the least of his
worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goyle&lt;/strong&gt; has his health, which is more than we can say for
Crabbe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_38&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 32&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Kill&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a terrible scream. Harry saw Snape&amp;rsquo;s face losing the
little colour it had left, it whitened as his black eyes widened, as
the snake&amp;rsquo;s fangs pierced his neck, as he failed to push the
enchanted cage off himself, as his knees gave way, and he fell to
the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I regret it,&amp;rdquo; said Voldemort coldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned away; there was no sadness in him, no remorse.  It was
time to leave this shack and take charge, with a wand that would now
do his full bidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahahaha, Snape hasn&amp;rsquo;t owned a wand since the last time he was in the
Shrieking Shack, way back in the third book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a real disarming. But if we can trust Voldemort, the
ownership of the Wand of Destiny can be transferred through killing:
&amp;ldquo;The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard who killed its last owner&amp;rdquo;
(&lt;em&gt;DH&lt;/em&gt; 441). Perhaps this quality is exclusive to the Elder Wand. If
Snape had any non-Elder wands, Voldemort might not have won them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;no changes&lt;/strong&gt; occur, because neither of these jerks have wands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_39&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 36&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Voldemort broke off: Harry heard a scuffle and a shout, then
another bang, a flash of light and a grunt of pain; he opened his
eyes an infinitesimal amount. Someone had broken free of the crowd
and charged at Voldemort: Harry saw the figure hit the ground,
Disarmed, Voldemort throwing the challenger&amp;rsquo;s wand aside and laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And who is this?&amp;rdquo; he said, in his soft snake&amp;rsquo;s hiss. &amp;ldquo;Who has
volunteered to demonstrate what happens to those who continue to
fight when the battle is lost?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bellatrix gave a delighted laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is Neville Longbottom, my Lord! The boy who has been giving the
Carrows so much trouble! The son of the Aurors, remember?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t throw Neville&amp;rsquo;s wand away!  It&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;ve got!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A red-gold glow burst suddenly across the enchanted sky above them,
as an edge of dazzling sun appeared over the sill of the nearest
window.  The light hit both of their faces at the same time, so that
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s was suddenly a flaming blur.  Harry heard the high voice
shriek as he, too, yelled his best hope to the heavens, pointing
Draco&amp;rsquo;s wand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Avada Kedavra!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Expelliarmus!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bang was like a cannon-blast and the golden flames that erupted
between them, at the dead centre of the circle they had been
treading, marked the point where the spells collided. Harry saw
Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s green jet meet his own spell, saw the Elder Wand fly
high, dark against the sunrise, spinning across the enchanted ceiling
like the head of Nagini, spinning through the air towards the master
it would not kill, who had come to take full possession of it at
last. And Harry, with the unerring skill of the Seeker, caught the
wand in his free hand as Voldemort fell backwards, arms splayed, the
slit pupils of the scarlet eyes rolling upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like Harry is the master of the Elder Wand, after all. But this
whole thing still doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, and Harry really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
have thrown away the Elder Wand afterward since he doesn&amp;rsquo;t own his
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands, and Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing (and is dead).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_40&#34;&gt;The final tally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry&lt;/strong&gt; has Goyle&amp;rsquo;s, Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s, Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s and Draco&amp;rsquo;s
wands, and Neville&amp;rsquo;s new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voldemort&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neville&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goyle&lt;/strong&gt; has his health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luna&lt;/strong&gt; has her new wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Death Eater&lt;/strong&gt; has Justin&amp;rsquo;s and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s and his own
wands as well as Luna&amp;rsquo;s old wands, and Justin&amp;rsquo;s hair and clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dobby&lt;/strong&gt; has Narcissa&amp;rsquo;s wand and no master.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narcissa&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draco&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron&lt;/strong&gt; has Bellatrix&amp;rsquo;s and Greyback&amp;rsquo;s wands and the troll&amp;rsquo;s club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellatrix&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greyback&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scabior&lt;/strong&gt; has Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 1&lt;/strong&gt; has Mundungus&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 2&lt;/strong&gt; has Ron&amp;rsquo;s, Harry&amp;rsquo;s, Hermione&amp;rsquo;s, Sirius&amp;rsquo; and his own
wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snatcher 3&lt;/strong&gt; has Dean&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermione&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mundungus&lt;/strong&gt; has his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stan&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumbledore&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dolohov&lt;/strong&gt; has Crabbe&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Death Eater&amp;rsquo;s wand and his
own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginny&lt;/strong&gt; has Michael&amp;rsquo;s wand and some Slytherin&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warrington&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millicent&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crabbe&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin A&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slytherin B&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred or George&lt;/strong&gt; has Zacharias&amp;rsquo; wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Creeveys&lt;/strong&gt; have all the books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barty Crouch Jr&lt;/strong&gt; has Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Weasley&lt;/strong&gt; has Uncle Vernon&amp;rsquo;s ornaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncle Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; has an epic mustache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crookshanks&lt;/strong&gt; has Lockhart&amp;rsquo;s wand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snape&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sirius&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James&lt;/strong&gt; has Snape&amp;rsquo;s and his own wands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grindelwald&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregorovitch&lt;/strong&gt; has nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>