<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Shits on Santa Barbara Bullshit — sbshit.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Alex Dunn</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2014 Alex Dunn; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-03-18 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is It Possible To Be Other Than A Walking Stereotype?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/magic</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/magic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/is-there-a-glass-that-is-neither-half-full-nor-half-empty653636/&#34;&gt;It is an expression we have all heard&lt;/a&gt;,
someone is either &amp;ldquo;a glass half full … or glass half empty&amp;rdquo; kind of
person. It is a not question of perception, philosophy or sheer
determination to decide how you want to perceive the world.  This is
not an interesting concept either since it&amp;rsquo;s an expression and not a
concept at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I would like to introduce a perception,&lt;/strong&gt; which is different than
the expressions and concepts previously introduced on account of it
being a perception and not an expression or a concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling too negative, and the &amp;ldquo;glass&amp;rdquo; is always half empty
for you … pour it out. Literally stop being negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds unachievable perhaps, and you might think this article is published on &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Bullshit&lt;/em&gt; for a reason, but I have
a book for you that is way worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our local author, Rhonda Byrne (relation to
&lt;a href=&#34;/shit/liberal&#34;&gt;Sharon Byrne&lt;/a&gt; unknown) has written several books, The
Magic is one that shifted much of my perception on how to write
grammatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While reading The Magic, &lt;strong&gt;I discovered a simple directive.
Gratitude.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, it can be an actual verb, despite being a concept
and not a word at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do actual scientific experiments with this concept, like
discovering a causal relationship between
&lt;a href=&#34;http://megr.im/post/lucidity&#34;&gt;New Age nonsense and cultural appropriation&lt;/a&gt;.
There is even a science known as Spiritual Physics, assuming that
&amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean &lt;em&gt;science&lt;/em&gt; and &amp;ldquo;physics&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean &lt;em&gt;physics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could end with a quote from Einstein about human stupidity, but ugh
why bother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Don’t Need a Time Traveler to Stop the Culture War From Ever Having Happened</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/war</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/war</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaphors exert a powerful influence on our thought, by leading us
to draw connections that would have otherwise lain undiscovered.
Their power is great, and so they must be used wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Someone really wise and shit, maybe a centaur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One metaphor that&amp;rsquo;s everywhere these days, or at least close enough to
everywhere to justify a thinkpiece about it, is the metaphor of &lt;em&gt;war&lt;/em&gt;.
Everyone seems to be comparing war with things that are not war, but
which they are pretty sure are still a lot like war.  Some of these
comparisons are good, maybe, like the description of a widespread
effort to undermine access to life-saving reproductive health
resources as a &amp;ldquo;War on Women&amp;rdquo;; others are probably
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wonkette.com/490754/catch-1123-being-a-true-and-accurate-account-of-the-late-war-on-christmas&#34; title=&#34;Wonkette: Catch-11/23: Being A True and Accurate Account of the Late
War On Christmas&#34;&gt;bad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s got to be some truth in our favorite longest-running
metaphorical war, right?  If &lt;strong&gt;Culture War&lt;/strong&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t real then all the
weaponized irony we&amp;rsquo;ve deployed will have been for nothing and &lt;em&gt;SBBS&lt;/em&gt;
might as well shut down.  So we&amp;rsquo;re really mad about Jeffrey Moualim&amp;rsquo;s
new piece in the &lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt;, which
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2014/jan/19/cease-fire-anyone/&#34; title=&#34;Cease Fire, Anyone?&#34;&gt;shows some deep disanalogies&lt;/a&gt; between actual war and whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing
as a foot soldier in the &amp;ldquo;U.S. Right-Left Culture War&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with the incredibly fierce fighting that transpired for most of
[World War I&amp;rsquo;s] four years, on Christmas, both sides would observe a
cease fire. Men would put down their guns, the sound of canons would
go silent, and some would actually venture into no man&amp;rsquo;s land and
fraternize with the enemy. In the midst of sheer madness, there was
a glimpse, if for just for a moment, of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction was that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; identify with this, since I
sometimes have to stop making fun of bronies because they have Magic
cards I want to trade for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then Mr. Moualim describes the &amp;ldquo;Culture War&amp;rdquo; in similarly
militaristic terms and takes the comparison to its logical and absurd
conclusion, threatening our business for no better reason than to
establish an important truth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today there is a war waged every day, a culture war between the left
and the right. It is timeless and it appears endless. It uses media
of every kind to blitzkrieg the opposition, and those left standing
are entranced with the idea &amp;ldquo;we live to fight again.&amp;rdquo; The notion of
peace is nonnegotiable, and compromise is considered surrender. The
right and left of this country will do battle, and hostilities do
not stop even for the most important and significant day of the year
during which believers espouse peace on earth, good will toward
men. One need only turn on the television or access the Internet to
see polarizing figures like Miley Cyrus or Phil Robertson of &lt;em&gt;Duck
Dynasty&lt;/em&gt; lobbing shells of extremism at the other side, a shock and
awe strategy intended to evoke harsh and bitter feelings from the
&amp;ldquo;enemy&amp;rdquo; and provoke a response filled with hate and hysteria. And
while it may seem to some just harmless fencing, it has in point of
fact caused deep divisions in this country, where walls of
intolerance are fortified instead of torn down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as it pains me to admit this, I believe Mr. Moualim is correct
in the conclusions he draws from this juxtaposition, which are
definitely these conclusions and not other conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wars might be sometimes fought for reasons other than the immediate
interests of those actually fighting in them.  The soldiers who did
that illicit fraternizing in no-man&amp;rsquo;s-land on Christmas 1914 didn&amp;rsquo;t
really have reasons to hate those on the other side, except when
this one German guy cheated during a game of Magic.  But the
higher-level officers were pretty ticked off about this because
their interests were closer aligned with the state.  The foot
soldiers and their &amp;ldquo;recognition of each other&amp;rsquo;s humanity&amp;rdquo; were
fucking up the game-plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our good Mr. Moualim makes clear, though, the &amp;ldquo;issues&amp;rdquo; commonly
associated with the &amp;ldquo;Culture War&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;the rights of women, people of
color, and sexual, gender, and romantic minorities; gun control
and justice system reform; climate change and other aspects of
environmental justice&amp;mdash;are not abstract concerns that matter only
to guys like Hitler.  They directly concern the lives of our
friends and families (it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a hassle) and those who oppose
us&amp;mdash;who will actually work to prevent free reproductive care for
all, or the end of the drug war&amp;mdash;are threatening our interests
profoundly.  They&amp;rsquo;re trying to cheat at a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of games of Magic,
and they won&amp;rsquo;t recognize the humanity of all of us.  Effed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second point that Mr. Moualim definitely makes at some point in
his essay, I mean unless I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; misread it, is that the
&lt;em&gt;objectives&lt;/em&gt; of the &amp;ldquo;Culture War&amp;rdquo; aren&amp;rsquo;t that much like the objectives
of a real war at all.  If there are any overarching goals shared
between all the ongoing struggles on behalf of marginalized people,
one is probably to secure the universal recognition of their
humanity&amp;mdash;to make a Christmas Armistice &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; between more than
just white men from different European countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And an armistice was not probably the point of the Great War, or
of any war, and anyway if all you want is an armistice you
probably want fewer soldiers rather than more of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Jeffrey Moualim answers the rhetorical question in his article&amp;rsquo;s
title: it makes no sense to call for a cease-fire, for an armistice,
in the &amp;ldquo;Culture War&amp;rdquo;, not only because it&amp;rsquo;s not a real war but
because, when we do get a cease-fire, it means we&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;won&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts Are Good. Feelings Are Better.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/facts</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/facts</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Santa Barbara&amp;rsquo;s a small town, but there&amp;rsquo;s always room for another
pundit.  Indeed, we have quite an enviable concentration of writers
willing to bullshit (in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://philosophynow.org/issues/53/On_Bullshit_by_Harry_Frankfurt&#34; title=&#34;*On Bullshit* by Harry Frankfurt&#34;&gt;technical sense&lt;/a&gt;) in our local publications.  If
Sharon Byrne is our city&amp;rsquo;s Thomas Friedman, putting forth an
&lt;a href=&#34;liberal.html&#34; title=&#34;A New Argument for Moral
Relativism&#34;&gt;incoherent pragmatism&lt;/a&gt; divorced from truth or morality as a solution to our
political conflicts, then Cheri Rae is our very own David Brooks and
Craig Allen is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=site%3Adaringfireball.net+enderle&#34;&gt;Rob Enderle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rae and Allen both have written recent columns that are admirable in
their pursuit of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merriam-webster.com/info/06words.htm&#34;&gt;truthiness&lt;/a&gt;.  Rae&amp;rsquo;s
column is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/drive-they-say653663/&#34; title=&#34;Drive! They Say.&#34;&gt;a lovely wistful meditation&lt;/a&gt; on the necessity of cars.  She mocks the idea that
we should promote alternative modes of transportation with this chunk
of hard data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the 16th birthday dawns, it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to earn the Golden
Ticket to Freedom and Adulthood: the Driver&amp;rsquo;s License. Some, as my
own son did, make their appointments for the first moment of the
first day they can officially take the driving test.  Others, like
my own daughter wait a year or two, but the idea of not
driving&amp;mdash;ever, or rarely&amp;mdash;never enters their minds at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth is, driving is high up there on the list of teen essentials,
along with smartphones, texting and hanging out.  Just take a look
at the completely packed student parking lots at our local high
schools&amp;mdash;and the fine luxury cars so many kids are driving from
home to school and all over town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could counter with nostalgic anecdotes of my own, telling the unique
life histories of my several friends in their 20s who have yet to get
a license, but I&amp;rsquo;m bored and I found this by typing &amp;ldquo;decline in teen
driving&amp;rdquo; into Google and clicking the first result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/mt/assets/business/Drivers_Licenses_Sivak_Michigan.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;From a report by Michael Sivak and Brandon Schoettle of the University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute, cited by [The Atlantic](http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2012/07/the-dramatic-30-year-decline-of-young-drivers-in-1-chart/260126/)&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to Craig Allen, who wrote
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/craig_allen_apple_computers_20131027&#34; title=&#34;Craig Allen: Apple at Risk of Becoming an &#39;Also-Ran&#39;&#34;&gt;an equally ignorant and ahistorical thinkpiece&lt;/a&gt; on Apple&amp;rsquo;s
prospects.  He starts with a complaint so deep and important that it
has been uttered by every Wordpress blogger since late 2011: that &amp;ldquo;in
the time since Jobs died, Apple has released numerous evolutionary
products&amp;mdash;new versions of the iPhone and iPad, but has not released
any truly new, revolutionary products to rival its current lineup.&amp;rdquo;
This insight derives its force from the scientific principle that
since the three &amp;ldquo;revolutionary products&amp;rdquo; usually recognized by
pundits&amp;mdash;the iPod, iPhone and iPad&amp;mdash;debuted in 2001, 2007, and 2010,
the next revolution should surely have occurred sometime in 2011 or
2012, even though Jobs has only recently ceased to be the subject of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://maypalo.com/2011/10/09/top-5-best-steve-jobs-in-heaven-comics/&#34;&gt;shitty cartoons set in Heaven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allen can be forgiven for overlooking
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macworld.com/article/1151235/apple_rolls.html&#34; title=&#34;This is how Apple rolls&#34;&gt;the arcane scholastic doctrine of &amp;ldquo;incrementalism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that some Medieval theorists believed
better explains Apple&amp;rsquo;s history.  It is a much more complicated thesis
than the one Allen and most of his contemporaries rely on, which is
the single word &amp;ldquo;INNOVATION&amp;rdquo; written in 72pt Impact font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allen is correct, however, to bemoan the apparently
increasingly-desperate efforts to fool investors into valuing Apple
highly.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2013/10/28/5039154/apple-q4-2013-earnings&#34;&gt;Pitiful revenues last quarter&lt;/a&gt;
and increasingly dismal
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/09/30/business/media/apple-passes-coca-cola-as-most-valuable-brand.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;brand recognition&lt;/a&gt;
support his assertion that &amp;ldquo;Apple&amp;rsquo;s management team must produce real
revenue growth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is also correct to compare Apple to another dedicated cellphone
manufacturer that failed when its only product was made obsolete:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As great as Apple has been, its trajectory is similar to many other
companies that were once high-fliers and eventually
tanked. BlackBerry is probably the best example. Not too long ago,
Blackberry had a cult-like following, so much so that people
referred to the device as a &amp;ldquo;crackberry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy here is very good; neither Apple nor RIM are willing to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/2008/05/blackberry_vs_iphone&#34;&gt;cannibalize their own marketshare by coming out with better stuff&lt;/a&gt;
and then diligently improving it.  Allen&amp;rsquo;s closing statement is
therefore deeply troubling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is sending a clear signal that Apple is in its twilight
as a major market leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not for the reason he thinks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friends Don’t Let Friends Feel Good About Their Bodies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/boobs</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/boobs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Readers of &lt;em&gt;SBBS&lt;/em&gt; were introduced to Randi Rabin when we highlighted
her &lt;a href=&#34;friends.html&#34; title=&#34;The Case of
the Magical Magnetic Genitals&#34;&gt;provocative deconstruction of gender&lt;/a&gt; back in July.  Now, Noozhawk&amp;rsquo;s
J. Edgar Hoover Distinguished Visiting Professor of Feelings is back
in the news with a short but insightful meditation on self-image and
bodily autonomy.  She recounts a question put to her recently by a
female recipient of breast implants,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/randi_rabin_breasts_lead_way_husband_mail_order_bride_20131024&#34; title=&#34;Randi Rabin: Woman&#39;s New Breasts Lead the Way; Wife Worried Husband
Is Seeking Mail-Order Bride&#34;&gt;who finds that her female friends have become &amp;ldquo;standoffish&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went from a 34C to a DD, and they are beautiful.  I get lots of
attention&amp;mdash;usually from men, and most of them are my girlfriends&amp;rsquo;
husbands.  How can I keep my friendship with the women in my life
the way it used to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The superficial reply to these concerns would involve a discussion of
how women can uphold patriarchy by blaming other women for expressing
their sexuality and &amp;ldquo;tempting&amp;rdquo; men, and also how women are belittled
for pursuing breast augmentation while simultaneously being
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrdestructo.com/2013/05/lets-talk-about-angelina-jolies-breasts.html&#34; title=&#34;Let&#39;s Talk About Angelina Jolie&#39;s Breasts&#34;&gt;valued only &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; their breasts&lt;/a&gt;.  The superficial
recommendations to &amp;ldquo;Betsy Boob&amp;rdquo; might include that she refuse to be
ashamed of her body and demand that her &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; stop blaming her for
the behavior of their husbands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that would all be superficial.  It would, in short, be the
recommendation to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LEAN IN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  And we know by now that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dissentmagazine.org/online_articles/feminisms-tipping-point-who-wins-from-leaning-in&#34; title=&#34;Feminism&#39;s Tipping Point: Who Wins from Leaning in?&#34;&gt;leaning in is not the answer to our problems&lt;/a&gt;.  Professor
Rabin recognizes this, and accordingly recommends that Betsy Boob
instead &lt;em&gt;lean back&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try having an open discussion with your girlfriends about what is
going on, and if by chance you are overly friendly with &amp;ldquo;other
women&amp;rsquo;s men,&amp;rdquo; you may need to step back a bit&amp;mdash;literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randi Rabin understands that, aside from being a slogan for rich white
women that ignores the structural issues that create inequality, the
biggest problem with Sheryl Sandberg&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Lean In&amp;rdquo; movement was that it
encouraged assertiveness and self-confidence in women.  Rabin sagely
warns that &amp;ldquo;if you are wearing low cut, extremely revealing outfits
and leading with your &amp;lsquo;girls,&amp;rsquo; rethink what kind of picture you want
to paint here,&amp;rdquo; reminding us that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://m.entrepreneur.com/article/225972&#34; title=&#34;How
Today&#39;s Young Female Entrepreneurs Embrace Their Feminine Mystique&#34;&gt;feminism is dead&lt;/a&gt;
and that there are certain things that women &lt;em&gt;must not do&lt;/em&gt;, such as
love themselves unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Sarcasm And Other Sorts Of Humor Can Make It Easier To Talk About A Painful Subject Or Just Serve As An Introduction To Some Old-Fashioned Hatred</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/sarcasm</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/sarcasm</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Jed A. Hendrickson, CM, AICA: Thank you for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/saved-from-the-scourge-of-plastic-bags452524542/&#34; title=&#34;Saved from the Scourge of Plastic Bags&#34;&gt;saving us&lt;/a&gt; from the scourge of going
another week without something to make fun of in Santa Barbara (please
do not read with any sarcasm, we&amp;rsquo;re absolutely sincere and in fact
have never been sarcastic ever).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps now we can try to do something useful for the citizens and
businesses in Santa Barbara&amp;mdash;by laughing at your
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/saved-from-the-scourge-of-plastic-bags452524542/&#34; title=&#34;Saved from the Scourge of Plastic Bags&#34;&gt;letter to the editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have attached a photo of the &amp;ldquo;attached&amp;rdquo; photos that you included
with your letter.  The fact that a web-only publication can fail, in
2013, to correctly embed images in a blog post paints a sad picture of
what is allowed to happen when the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara View&lt;/em&gt; is allowed to
operate without regard to the impact on the community.  I realize that
using a PDF to display images is hardly a big deal except it seems to
happen every day (unlike the presence of homeless individuals around
Jed&amp;rsquo;s business, given the gaps in his photographic record).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/pdf.png&#34; alt=&#34;See pages 2--4, first page blank.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it were not for us at &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Bullshit&lt;/em&gt; I fear the City
would take the &lt;em&gt;View&lt;/em&gt; seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask the City Council to do more to marginalize the
&lt;a href=&#34;home.html&#34; title=&#34;Point-Counterpoint: Kill the
Homeless, or Just Treat Them Like Animals?&#34;&gt;privileged and hateful&lt;/a&gt; members of the local
community in the Milpas Street area.
&lt;a href=&#34;liberal.html&#34; title=&#34;A New Argument for Moral Relativism&#34;&gt;Sharon Byrne in particular&lt;/a&gt;
should be held to a strict standard (only one article or letter per
month); police budgets should be slashed to reduce the victimization
of the oppressed for the comfort of the rich; and finally the City
needs to recognize the burden it carries as a government complicit in
the continued production of conditions that create homelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/n3jzkYF.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Artist&#39;s rendition of Jed A. Hendrickson&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When In Rome Do As The Romans Do, Unless The Romans Are Ludicrously Privileged Americans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/foreign</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/foreign</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classes begin again next week at UCSB (you can be sure that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/dn&#34;&gt;The Daily Nonsense&lt;/a&gt; will too), and nothing
says &amp;ldquo;Back to School&amp;rdquo; like a local
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/letter_to_the_editor_foreign_students_should_learn_rules_of_the_road_201309&#34; title=&#34;Letter to the Editor: Foreign Students Should Learn Rules of the
Road&#34;&gt;screaming &amp;ldquo;Go Back Home!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at international students:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annually, we are flooded with enormous numbers of foreign students.
I feel it is the schools&amp;rsquo; responsibility to educate and quiz the
students on local rules that can save their lives&amp;mdash;and
ours&amp;mdash;making sure they fully comprehend laws, rules and common
courtesies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Korean girl was angry she could not get a pink car.  She ended up
buying a white, fancy, convertible for cash in L.A.  She pulled into
my driveway and took out the entire side of my car.  She had never
parked a car before.  She moved out the next day.  Her one-day
insurance did not cover the car damage, and she had to call her
father to pay for the damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American children never use their parents&amp;rsquo; money to buy expensive
things and wreck them.  Granted, that may be only due to Obama&amp;rsquo;s war
on the rich (against which only a few brave souls are
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/harrybinswanger/2013/09/17/give-back-yes-its-time-for-the-99-to-give-back-to-the-1/&#34; title=&#34;Harry Binswanger: Give Back? Yes, It&#39;s Time For The 99% To Give Back
To The 1%&#34;&gt;standing strong&lt;/a&gt;), but the point stands.  Believing oneself to be above the
law due to a childhood marinated in wealth is a condition exclusive to
foreigners, particularly young Asian students.  The PC police don&amp;rsquo;t
want you to hear this, but Deborah Barnes has exemplified a
characteristic American bravery by telling the truth nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to Bad Odes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/poem</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/poem</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to another installment of&lt;/em&gt; Art Critic,
&lt;em&gt;in which we attempt a negative definition of art by excluding
everything in Santa Barbara.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt; has a proud tradition of publishing
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/clickety-clack/&#34; title=&#34;Clickety-Clack, We Talk Back&#34;&gt;unusual poetry&lt;/a&gt;, and today saw the continuation of
that saga with a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/sep/09/electronic-devices/&#34; title=&#34;Electronic Devices&#34;&gt;rhythmic meditation on &amp;ldquo;Electronic Devices&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  To attempt to perform a close reading of such
a work would be folly, as Gandalf reminds us: &amp;ldquo;he that breaks a thing
to find out what it is has left the path of wisdom.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead we will respond with verses of our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad poetry&amp;rsquo;s a crying shame &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But who&amp;rsquo;s at fault &amp;mdash; what to blame?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at all these awful verses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of them with any purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate all this tech and I won&amp;rsquo;t tell you why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It gives me a chance to be published online).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my rhythm gets bad, and I leave out a comma,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The editor&amp;rsquo;s sad;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading my poem, line by line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drowning her horror and sorrow in wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t do this with print media, my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so pleased with this new drivel-publishing trend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Class Analysis of Santa Barbara</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/class</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/class</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Mazza, Editor-in-Chief of the radical zine
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbarasentinel.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has
produced a trenchant essay on the class disparities in our city.
Taking the form of a first-person narrative, the piece brilliantly
parodies the tone-deafness of the wealthy and their ignorance of their
own privilege, as well as touching on the problematic tendency of our
media to serve as mouthpieces for local businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excerpt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family trips and incessant summer barbecues and parties are the norm
for our family in these wonderful warm months, and we always indulge
and generally have a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But come Labor Day, man, I&amp;rsquo;m straight burnt.  Worn out.  Beat down.
Bushed.  Bonked.  Bagged.  Zonked.  Tuckered.  Fried.  Whipped.  (I
love my thesaurus.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m typically looking forward to re-focusing on the office (gasp!)
and putting some damned structure back into things.  And the
partying and vacationing and merrymaking is fun, very fun, but it&amp;rsquo;s
also grueling.  (Punishing.  Debilitating.  Told you I love my
thesaurus.)  And this year was no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact this year was particularly egregious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, though.  Despite an absolutely crippling last
couple of weeks that left me emotionally, mentally, and physically
drained, I recently discovered a wonderful remedy that, when coupled
with the aforementioned structure and focus, already has me
reenergized and reinvigorated for the impending school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the cure, you ask expectantly?  What doctor is most likely to
prescribe it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert, folks: It&amp;rsquo;s not something you &lt;em&gt;take&lt;/em&gt;, and there ain&amp;rsquo;t
no doctor who an give it to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cure is somewhere you &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt;.  Just for a night or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple, and it&amp;rsquo;s right here in our collective backyard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three(ish) words: &lt;strong&gt;Bacara Resort &amp;amp; Spa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the rest at &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Sentinel&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; Issuu page
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.issuu.com/130830184014-057e3c6c253af0ab39fff9f252607560/jpg/page_1.jpg&#34;&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.issuu.com/130830184014-057e3c6c253af0ab39fff9f252607560/jpg/page_2.jpg&#34;&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.issuu.com/130830184014-057e3c6c253af0ab39fff9f252607560/jpg/page_11.jpg&#34;&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.issuu.com/130830184014-057e3c6c253af0ab39fff9f252607560/jpg/page_28.jpg&#34;&gt;page 4&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.issuu.com/130830184014-057e3c6c253af0ab39fff9f252607560/jpg/page_30.jpg&#34;&gt;page 5&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art Critic: How Is This House Floating?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/bubble</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/bubble</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first (and, hopefully, last) installment of&lt;/em&gt; Art Critic,
&lt;em&gt;in which we attempt a negative definition of art by excluding
everything in Santa Barbara.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Greenberg is widely thought to be a cartoonist, but there has
historically been little evidence supporting that claim.  This week,
however, the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara View&lt;/em&gt; threw their weight behind the
credibility of rumors that Greenberg in fact draws pictures,
accompanied with text, that aim to provide humorous commentary on
current political affairs.  By reprinting his piece
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/toon-op-housing-bubble-ii6536356/&#34;&gt;Housing Bubble 2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;,
which first appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Ventura Star&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greenberg-art.com/.Toons/.Toons%20recent/HousingBubble.html&#34;&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt;,
the suggestion is that the work meets enough of the criteria listed
above to be considered a &amp;ldquo;political cartoon&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/speculator.png&#34; alt=&#34;His bubble wand is colored gold in order to symbolize his wealth (this is because gold is associated with wealth because it is valuable)&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What first captures the viewer&amp;rsquo;s attention is this man in the bottom
left.  He is labeled &amp;ldquo;SPECULATORS&amp;rdquo;, implying that he represents multiple
speculators.  But which speculators?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/house.png&#34; alt=&#34;The house has curved walls because it is inside a bubble, which distorts light and creates that sort of illusion&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second large element of &amp;ldquo;Housing Bubble 2&amp;rdquo; makes it clear that our
topic is &lt;em&gt;housing&lt;/em&gt; speculators, who attempt to leverage fluctuations
in real estate prices in order to make money quickly.  This practice
can artificially &amp;ldquo;inflate&amp;rdquo; house prices and create a housing
&amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;represented above by the house inside a bubble.  The house,
inside the bubble, rising up in the air, represents the rising house
prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/homebuyer.png&#34; alt=&#34;The man on the roof represents the would-be-homebuyer whose dream house is &amp;quot;slipping away&amp;quot; (it would be visually uninteresting to show the worth of the house in contrast to the would-be-homebuyer&#39;s means, so the cartoonist shows him *on* the house, but slipping off it)&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo;, lower- and middle-class individuals may
find themselves no longer able to afford to purchase a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/words.png&#34; alt=&#34;Don&#39;t imagine that these words are actually painted on the house, because it&#39;s supposed to be a good-looking house that the would-be-homebuyer wants to buy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; at the end of &amp;ldquo;Housing Bubble 2&amp;rdquo; (which is also the title of
the drawing) is supposed to inform us that this is the second housing
bubble that has occurred.  Another housing bubble happened a while
ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara View&lt;/em&gt; is correct.  This is a
cartoon, it&amp;rsquo;s a good cartoon, and it is funny.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny because
it&amp;rsquo;s funny to imagine a grown man blowing a bubble wand, and a house
floating in the air.  Considered alongside his
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/toon-op-school-funding654363/&#34;&gt;last drawing&lt;/a&gt;,
which was funny because some places have a larger property tax base
than others, there is little doubt that Steve Greenberg is a very
funny political cartoonist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.greenberg-art.com/Caricature%202008%20Color%20Small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This isn&#39;t actually Steve Greenberg, he&#39;s a real person and not a drawing, but this is a drawing he did of himself to symbolize the fact that he draws things (he draws cartoons, not just himself)&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haven’t We Done Enough For (To) Those Foreigners?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/charity</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/charity</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Harris Sherline continues to provide living proof that we must not
mean what we say.  Having previously issued a
&lt;a href=&#34;wage.html&#34; title=&#34;What Is The
Point Of A Living Wage If We Are Not Truly Alive&#34;&gt;revolutionary call to bring down capitalism&lt;/a&gt; under the guise of
a neoliberal propaganda piece, the weekend found him penning a
thoughtful essay&amp;mdash;pretending to be a bit of bland parochialism&amp;mdash;on
the damage done to the world by American good intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherline begins charitably by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/harris_sherline_charity_begins_at_home_20130824&#34; title=&#34;With So Many in Need Here, Charity Should Begin at Home&#34;&gt;noting the &lt;em&gt;desire to do good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that can be
found in his fellow nationals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the vantage point of my own background, which includes about 15
years of active involvement with nonprofits, my perception is that
very few communities have the extent of participation in charitable
activities as our valley.  Coming from Los Angeles via Santa
Barbara, where my wife and I lived for seven years, I have never
seen a community where so many of its residents are involved in some
type of charitable work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an impulse to kindness is itself praiseworthy, of course, but
Sherline recognizes that much depends on how it is acted upon.  He is
therefore troubled by the fact that &amp;ldquo;various people and organizations
feel it necessary to go outside the local area to help others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reader unaware of Sherline&amp;rsquo;s politics might be alarmed and think
that he is promoting some sort of tight-fisted nationalism in which
those across borders are less deserving of aid.  But of course, that
is not the point he is driving at.  That point is brought out in a
brilliant bit of dark humor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are the most generous people on Earth and have done more for
others around the world than any other society in history&amp;mdash;ever.
Yet we seem to be frequently castigated, both at home and abroad,
for our failure to cure the world of all of its ills or for not
preventing the starvation and privation that exist almost everywhere
on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By reminding us of the incalculable death and destruction caused
worldwide by the United States, and quietly reminding us that our good
intentions with regard to the rest of the world are often misguided
and sometimes
&lt;a href=&#34;http://seetheworldanew.tumblr.com/post/54606200629/theres-a-mosquito-net-maker-in-africa-he&#34;&gt;do more harm than good&lt;/a&gt;,
Sherline is making a point similar to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kafila.org/2013/02/20/dear-sisters-and-brothers-at-harvard/&#34; title=&#34;Kafila: Dear Brothers and Sisters at Harvard&#34;&gt;that made by feminists in India&lt;/a&gt; when Harvard decided
to tell them how to end gender violence in their country:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your colonialist good intentions to yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Terrifying Person In Santa Barbara</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/hand</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/hand</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/john_daly_a_virtual_introduction_20130815&#34; title=&#34;John Daly: A Virtual Introduction Will Go Hand in Hand with Success&#34;&gt;Is John Daly:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t see it right now, but my arm is outstretched to shake your
hand.  Close your eyes and go with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Beast: Women’s Health and Social Noise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/pms</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/pms</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea of PMS as a great hormonal tide that washes away women&amp;rsquo;s
rationality does not, of course, correspond to reality.  Many were
probably nonetheless shocked last year when University of Toronto
researchers published a literature review suggesting that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/10/pms-and-the-wandering-womb/263398/&#34; title=&#34;James Hamblin: PMS and the Wandering Womb&#34;&gt;many of the phenomena attributed to PMS may have their source elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.  (Among those
unsurprised by their findings was surely Emile Nelson, who has long
insisted that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/dn/hump.html&#34; title=&#34;How To Have Sex While Hating Yourself And Others&#34;&gt;women never had any rationality to begin with&lt;/a&gt;.)  Dr. Sarah
Romans even suggested that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the whole PMS notion serves to keep women non-irritable, sweet, and
compliant the rest of the time.  There is a range of
paradoxes&amp;mdash;world-turned-upside-down events&amp;mdash;like festivals, Mardi
Gras, where people are socially prescribed to behave out of role.
In Europe in medieval times there&amp;rsquo;d be one day a year where the lord
would serve his own servants and workers, and then the rest of the
time it&amp;rsquo;s the other way, servant obeying the master.  And these
kinds of rituals serve to embed the normal behavior.  I think PMS is
a bit like that.  &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll let you be cranky and bad-tempered now, but
just for one or two days. The rest of the time you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be like
a true woman.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since Romans et
al. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1550857912001349&#34; title=&#34;ScienceDirect: Mood and the Menstrual Cycle: A Review of Prospective
Data Studies&#34;&gt;published their results&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Gender Medicine&lt;/em&gt;.  Did this finally change our
narratives about women&amp;rsquo;s emotionality?  Starshine Roshell took to the
&lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt; today to issue a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/aug/14/pms-safety-guide-men/&#34; title=&#34;PMS: A Safety Guide for Men&#34;&gt;pessimistic progress report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roshell&amp;rsquo;s column contains two distinct threads.  One is a
straightforward exposition of what should, by now, be obvious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;d love to be able to dismiss our emotional extremes as
the hormone-fueled flare-ups of an estrogen-addled lunatic rather
than have to consider whether you&amp;rsquo;ve actually done something wrong
(HOW HARD IS IT TO PICK A DIFFERENT FORK?). But it&amp;rsquo;s not like we&amp;rsquo;re
schizophrenic, possessed by the devil, or on a bender; we&amp;rsquo;re still
us, reacting to genuine feelings about real things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth reminding you that men behave unpredictably and
unpleasantly from time to time: The teenaged boy who roars from
sulking to rage in 60 seconds flat, the grown man who grows
despondent when we&amp;rsquo;re out of coffee or snippy when he misses his
morning workout &amp;hellip; Those chemical surges&amp;rsquo;ll mess with your mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if empathy alone won&amp;rsquo;t keep you from playing the condescending
&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got PMS&amp;rdquo; card, then do it for your own safety. Because when
you dismiss our concerns&amp;mdash;deranged as they may seem&amp;mdash;as the bogus
byproducts of a biological function, it belittles our distress and
defines us as poorly engineered, malfunctioning freaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we&amp;rsquo;ve been labeled with the scarlet P, we can no longer be
heard; even legitimate worries and reasonable frustrations are
ignored as involuntary theatrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But woven between these paragraphs is another thread that disrupts and
confuses the points being made.  It is the trope of PMS-induced
hysteria, which Roshell introduces to show that the old story is still
the one being told:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have arrived, yet again, at that odious interlude of each lunar
cycle when there is a small chance that I will throw something heavy
at your head.  There&amp;rsquo;s also a chance that during the next three days
I will snatch something out of your hands because you are doing it
wrong, shriek &amp;ldquo;WHO ATE THE LAST BROWNIE?&amp;rdquo; at a pterodactyl pitch,
and begin weeping inconsolably because you set the table and gave me
that fork I don&amp;rsquo;t like&amp;mdash;that one freaking fork that is so easy to
avoid in the utensils drawer and that you know very well I dislike,
but you just had to put it at my place, didn&amp;rsquo;t you? You never have
respected me, not for one minute of our lives, and this is how you
choose to show me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to hell, fellas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your wife/mother/girlfriend/sister is a porcupine who has swallowed
a hand grenade and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to die alone. But with a steady
supply of wine and simple carbohydrates, she might&amp;mdash;might&amp;mdash;be able
to keep The Beast shackled in the basement of her soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roshell&amp;rsquo;s intention is clearly to illustrate how even the most
sensible conversation about menstruation takes place against the
backdrop the bad old narrative.  Not only is this sort of conversation
constantly at risk of being actively derailed by the invocation of
that backdrop, but decades of sexism and misinformation have lead
listeners to immediately associate such conversations with problematic
myths.  The second thread of Roshell&amp;rsquo;s column can therefore be thought
of as the social noise in the background of any discussion of women&amp;rsquo;s
emotions, perpetually distracting us from what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this strategy is actually too effective because all
we&amp;rsquo;re going to get out of this column is that women&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have no option but to cash in that free pass, stop trying to tame
our tempers, and erupt in a delirious streak of long-overdue,
blame-my-uterus, full-volume flipping freak-outs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gentlemen &amp;hellip; meet The Beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Reven Steynalds’ Write-In Candidacy for Mayor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/mayor</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/mayor</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/letter_to_the_editor_announcing_write-in_candidacy_for_mayor_20130809&#34;&gt;Dear Santa Barbara,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to enter the race for mayor as a write-in candidate.  As
our newly elected mayor, my first order of business will enure that
all official correspondence takes the form of rhetorical questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s brush aside my qualifications and everything else that&amp;rsquo;s
relevant and discuss an issue the surface of which was barely
scratched&amp;mdash;the police chief&amp;rsquo;s idea for a door-to-door campaign to
discuss the &amp;ldquo;homeless problem&amp;rdquo;.  If I am so adept at this art of
misdirection already, will I not be an admirable politician?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve hitched my announcement of candidacy to a topic that
will only interest the people who comment at the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara
View&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;how about we dishonestly suppose that such a campaign is
motivated by some abstract principle, and then generalize that
principle in the hopes of deriving some absurd conclusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it say something about my priorities that this is the most
important thing I can think to write about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, have you learned anything about me and my political
views in this letter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.  I hope to see you at the next City Council
meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Reven C. Steynalds, &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comedy of Errors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/porn</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/porn</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All publications are prone to mistakes, and the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara View&lt;/em&gt;
is no exception.  But the &lt;em&gt;View&lt;/em&gt; has made some major slips recently.
Two weeks ago they transposed some key words in Sharon Byrne&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;liberal.html&#34; title=&#34;A New Argument for Moral
Relativism&#34;&gt;essay on moral philosophy&lt;/a&gt;, and today they have committed a much graver error,
accidentally publishing
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/rewarding-bad-behavior56536/&#34; title=&#34;Rewarding Bad Behavior&#34;&gt;draft notes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;made by Loretta Redd, PhD on a variety of
topics&amp;mdash;as a single essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Redd apparently created a draft post to collect her thoughts
on a number of different topics&amp;mdash;manipulation of the media, rape
culture, technology and pornography, teaching healthy sexuality&amp;mdash;but
someone accidentally hit &amp;ldquo;Publish&amp;rdquo; on the lot.  The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/rewarding-bad-behavior56536/&#34; title=&#34;Rewarding Bad Behavior&#34;&gt;result&lt;/a&gt; unfortunately (and most assuredly
unintentionally) conflates healthy and unhealthy sexuality,
pathologizes women&amp;rsquo;s agency, places Paula Deen alongside sexual
predators, and gives the impression that Loretta Redd has no
understanding of either technology or pornography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Redd&amp;rsquo;s essays was apparently intended to juxtapose
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtoncitypaper.com/blogs/sexist/2009/09/11/the-rapiest-quotes-from-i-hope-they-serve-beer-in-hell/&#34; title=&#34;The Rapiest Quotes From \&amp;quot;I Hope They Serve Beer In Hell\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;rape apologist&lt;/a&gt; Tucker
Max with Anthony Weiner, Bob Filner, and Herman Cain, who have used
their positions of power to (so far) avoid prosecution for repeated
sexual harassment.  No doubt the point was to illustrate how our
willingness to excuse &amp;ldquo;bad boys&amp;rdquo; like Max and politicians like Weiner,
Filner and Cain are equally dangerous aspects of rape culture.  But
somehow a short rant about Paula Deen was inserted into the middle of
that piece, seriously disrupting the flow.  Readers are likely to
lose the thread, and wonder whether she&amp;rsquo;s writing about specifically
male privilege or the entitlement of the powerful in general (or even
that Paula Deen is also a sexual predator!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately things quickly get even worse for the unwitting reader,
as another random bit of text has been tacked onto the end of that
section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid decline of what once passed as morality seems to go
hand-in-hand with the rise of access to our impersonal digital
connections.  &lt;strong&gt;Men aren&amp;rsquo;t alone in the decline&lt;/strong&gt;; women who show
their bodies on social media, who drink like fish, and behave like
frat boys aren&amp;rsquo;t helping to chart a map for morality or do much to
hold men accountable for acting out their fantasies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presumably this is a quote from Ross Douthat or some other benevolent
sexist who Loretta Redd (PhD) was planning on critiquing.  She may
have meant to expand her article on rape culture to cover how the
sentiments expressed in this quote&amp;mdash;that women being able to choose
how to present their bodies is dangerous, that women behaving in
stereotypically masculine ways is wrong, and that women are
responsible for controlling inherently irresponsible men&amp;mdash;subtly
reinforces the idea that women who &amp;ldquo;act out&amp;rdquo; are asking for trouble.
But instead, the effect of this quote, coming right after Redd&amp;rsquo;s
remarks about the moral depravity of Weiner et al., may lead the
incautious reader to think that Loretta Redd, PhD is suggesting that
Weiner&amp;rsquo;s behavior and the increasing autonomy of women are both
aspects of the same (imaginary) moral decline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then make another jump.  Redd was apparently planning on later
publishing a piece about the impact of technology on pornography.
It&amp;rsquo;s obvious that this was intended to be a subsequent article because
she makes a cute reference to her article about Weiner and Filner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if Mr. Weiner or Mayor Filner in San Diego spend hours
engaged in on-line pornography, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her notes contain some statistics about pornography consumption by
young people today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Jennings Bryant, in a review of 600 third-year high school
students discovered that 91% of males and 82% of females had been
exposed to explicit on-line pornography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of search engines, M. Ybarra and K. Mitchell of
&lt;strong&gt;Internet Solutions for Kids, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;, declare in their study on
this subject that deliberate exposure to pornographic sites is now
surpassing that of accidental exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to say what the objective of this column was to be, because
these notes are mixed up with some quotes pulled from&amp;mdash;I can only
guess&amp;mdash;the American Family Association:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our children under the age of 12 are being exposed to pornography
with devastating impact on healthy age-appropriate sexual
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imagery is far beyond their years and can permanently distort
beliefs about sexual aggression or the treatment of women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In decades past, teenage sexual curiosities were satisfied by
peering at the nubile breasts or male nudity of some Old Master&amp;rsquo;s
paintings or sneaking a peek at a big brother&amp;rsquo;s copy of Playboy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s world is far more graphic, emotionally more jarring, and
physically more dangerous because limits to access are becoming more
difficult to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t anything healthy for anyone about internet pornography
&amp;hellip; There isn&amp;rsquo;t anything appropriate about pre-pubescent children
gaining access to images that can distort their concept of human
relations forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of this mistake, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure nobody regrets more than
Loretta Redd, PhD, is to suggest that the fact that relatively fewer
young people are accidentally stumbling across porn is itself a
crisis, and that teens were &lt;em&gt;healthier&lt;/em&gt; when their sexual desires were
more stigmatized than they are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt the former notes were the beginnings of Redd&amp;rsquo;s article on the
need for more comprehensive sex education that encourages safety and
consent instead of ignorance and fear, and the need not for internet
filters but
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stavvers.wordpress.com/2013/07/22/not-that-porn-blocking-bollocks-again/&#34; title=&#34;Stavvers: Not that porn-blocking bollocks again&#34;&gt;better porn&lt;/a&gt; that itself teaches
healthy sexuality.  And surely the latter quotes were to be gleefully
torn apart as the moral panic of those with reactionary views of
sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too bad that these sketchy but promising ideas were published
prematurely.  And the second half of the essay is also peppered with
some unrelated psychological musings on the possibility of sexual
pathology as an explanation for why Anthony Weiner was compelled to
ruin his career for a few dick pics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trust, however, that this error will be addressed, and that
eventually we will see the full flowering of Loretta Redd&amp;rsquo;s intellect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born Into Trouble</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/sterile</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/sterile</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have long been awaiting new work from Sue Ahlgren, who rose to fame
in January after publishing an exhaustively-researched article in the
&lt;em&gt;Montecito Journal&lt;/em&gt; arguing for the unintuitive but apparently true
claim that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/120570735/LEGALLY-BLONDE&#34; title=&#34;Food For Too Many, page 9&#34;&gt;poor people are lazy&lt;/a&gt;.  And she has at last delivered.  In the
&lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Independent&lt;/em&gt; today, Ahlgren carefully sifts through the
history of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ijfab.org/blog/they-all-wanted-it-done-eugenics-now-showing-in-a-state-prison-near-you/&#34; title=&#34;IJFAB: \&amp;quot;They all wanted it done\&amp;quot;: Eugenics---Now Showing In A State
Prison Near You!&#34;&gt;eugenics in California&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;in light of revelations that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cironline.org/reports/female-inmates-sterilized-california-prisons-without-approval-4917&#34; title=&#34;Center for Investigative Reporting: Female inmates sterilized in
California prisons without approval&#34;&gt;forced sterilizations have continued to be performed in prisons&lt;/a&gt; until as recently as 2010&amp;mdash;and
concludes that somewhere around 2006 this practice ceased being a form
of state-sponsored genocide against women of color and those with
disabilities and instead became a responsible choice by those who
finally realized that their decision to be a minority was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/jul/27/issues-not-inmates/&#34; title=&#34;Issues, Not Inmates&#34;&gt;reckless and unwise&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are woman in federal prison, some with mental instability, who
have accepted the counsel of health professionals in prison and
decided that maybe, given their lifestyle, it would be prudent for
them not to have more children.  No doubt they came to the
conclusion that repeated lawbreaking and incarceration is no way to
raise a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahlgren accordingly takes State Senator Hannah-Beth Jackson to task
for trying to position herself as an &amp;ldquo;advocate&amp;rdquo; for these women.
Jackson, blinded by her privilege, presumes to speak for these women
and erase their agency when they can speak perfectly well for
themselves and have freely and happily placed themselves in the care
of a prison system that has been entirely open about its mission of
absolutely destroying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only weakness of Ahlgren&amp;rsquo;s article is its terseness: her argument,
against the historical consensus that forced sterilization is forced,
is concise to a fault.  Here it is in its entirety:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument just quoted obviously requires some elaboration, so I
will attempt to flesh out Ahlgren&amp;rsquo;s thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would any person of color, or disabled person, who has a uterus,
and is in a racist, sexist, and ableist prison system, allow that
system to further marginalize them by removing their capacity for
reproduction?  Perhaps Sue Ahlgren&amp;rsquo;s suggestion is that they have been
so victimized by society, and have endured such pain, that do not wish
to have more children who will inherit that agony.  Perhaps, through
some morbid rationality, they have decided that it would be a cruelty
to bring a child into a world that still contains people like Sue
Ahlgren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s also possible that I&amp;rsquo;ve misinterpreted her argument.  And so
I continue to look forward to hearing what Sue Ahlgren has to tell us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randy Alcorn Can’t Be *This* Racist, So What’s Going On?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/race</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/race</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;wage.html&#34; title=&#34;What Is The Point Of A Living Wage If We
Are Not Truly Alive&#34;&gt;last piece&lt;/a&gt; examined the way local writers cleverly hide
their progressive politics behind superficially reactionary claims.
Harris Sherline in particular showed himself to be a master of hiding
his revolutionary anti-capitalism behind boilerplate corporate
rhetoric.  An uncritical reader might misunderstand him, but his
radical meaning was clear to those to were ready to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, however, &lt;em&gt;Noozhawk&lt;/em&gt; has printed a real puzzler.  Randy Alcorn has
used his column to pose a curious question: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/randy_alcorn_trayvon_martin_case_racism_or_reality&#34; title=&#34;Randy Alcorn: Trayvon Martin Case---Racism or Reality?&#34;&gt;[The] Trayvon Martin
Case&amp;mdash;Racism or
Reality?&lt;/a&gt;  Such a
question &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; to imply that racism doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually exist, and that
Serious People who are grounded in reality ignore the centuries-old
system of oppression that continues to position Black people as
second-class citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that can&amp;rsquo;t be what Randy is &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; saying.  There&amp;rsquo;s no way
he&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; willfully ignorant of racism in the United States today,
and of his own complicity in its perpetuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No way.  So let&amp;rsquo;s dig a little deeper and see if we can figure out
what he&amp;rsquo;s really getting at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, racial profiling of black men, especially young black men, is
common in America, but is it a manifestation of persistent,
widespread racism?  While racism certainly still exists in America,
its pervasiveness is questionable.  The vast majority of nonblack
Americans are not racist, especially the younger generation, as
Obama mentioned, for whom race is virtually a nonfactor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randy must be trying to imply something else here, because there&amp;rsquo;s no
other reason why he would utter such a blatant falsehood.  Everyone
raised in a racist society will more or less frequently perpetuate
that racism, and because the US is still &lt;em&gt;profoundly&lt;/em&gt; racist, young
people are no exception.  Indeed, those born after 1980 may be even
&lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; prone to actions that prop up racist oppression, given that
they have been taught to think only of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thegrio.com/2011/08/10/milennials-attiudes-prove-america-isnt-post-racial/&#34; title=&#34;The Grio: Millennial attitudes prove America isn&#39;t post-racial&#34;&gt;interpersonal &lt;em&gt;prejudice&lt;/em&gt; as opposed to &lt;em&gt;systemic racism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tendency of the millennial generation to talk about racism as
interpersonal rather than institutional reflects a generational
divide.  Completely divorced from the experiences of the Civil
Rights movement, a new generation of Americans has reached adulthood
without any frame of reference to provide them with a proper
context, save their own limited and often lacking personal
experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is the legacy of the right&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;reverse racism&amp;rdquo; talking point.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps Randy&amp;rsquo;s point here about race being a &amp;ldquo;nonfactor&amp;rdquo; is that many
white people have convinced themselves that we live in a &amp;ldquo;post-racial&amp;rdquo;
society where they don&amp;rsquo;t need to confront their own privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving along:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racial integration throughout society is now more the norm than the
exception.  And mixed-race marriages only turn the disapproving
heads of the nation&amp;rsquo;s most primitive cultural Neanderthals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blatant racism may explain some of the profiling and
harassment of black males, especially by police, most of it stems
from instinctual prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very strange, given that the country is still
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.propublica.org/article/reading-guide-segregation-in-america&#34; title=&#34;ProPublica reading guide: Segregation in America&#34;&gt;deeply segregated&lt;/a&gt;, with schools
possibly &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; integrated than in the 1960s.  But I suppose it is
indeed comforting to know that in 2010 only
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pewsocialtrends.org/2012/02/16/the-rise-of-intermarriage/5/#chapter-4-public-attitudes-on-intermarriage&#34; title=&#34;The Rise of Intermarriage: Public Attitudes on Intermarriage&#34;&gt;17 percent&lt;/a&gt; of
those responding to a Pew Survey were willing to openly voice their
disapproval of Blacks and whites dating, while a mere 11 percent
claimed that increasing rates of intermarriage were a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guess is that Randy Alcorn here is &lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to be one of those
commenters who points out unapologetic racist behavior as the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;
racism in order to deflect attention from their brand of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gawker.com/5899322/the-dog-whistle-has-sounded-how-the-right-talks-about-thugs-like-trayvon-martin&#34; title=&#34;The Dog Whistle Has Sounded: How the Right Talks About &#39;Thugs&#39; Like
Trayvon Martin&#34;&gt;dog-whistle
racism that is more easily denied&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure what Randy&amp;rsquo;s ultimate purpose is.  Maybe
reading further will clear things up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The stark reality is that crime happens in communities of color,&amp;rdquo;
New York City Police Commissioner Raymond Kelly said in a recent ABC
Nightline broadcast. He went on to say, &amp;ldquo;About 70 percent to 75
percent of the people described as committing violent crimes&amp;mdash;
assault, robbery, shootings, grand larceny&amp;mdash;are described as being
African-American.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most likely Randy is citing
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2013/07/23/kelly_stop_and_frisk_and_muslim_surveillance_are_wonderful/&#34; title=&#34;Kelly&#39;s creative writing: Stop-and-frisk and Muslim surveillance are
wonderful!&#34;&gt;compulsive liar Ray Kelly&lt;/a&gt; in order to remind us both that statistics given to us
by the police may exaggerate Black criminality, and that that racist
police state that Ray Kelly champions may well be a major &lt;em&gt;cause&lt;/em&gt; of
crime in poor Black communities, by robbing young people of
opportunity and hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very good points, but I&amp;rsquo;m still not finding the thread tying this all
together.  Here&amp;rsquo;s Randy again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Martin profiled by Zimmerman?  Most probably.  Did Zimmerman
have reason to be cautiously suspicious of Martin?  Given the
realities of who commits crime in America, yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to pinpoint why Randy feels the need to repeat the lie
that Black communities should be willing to take on a &amp;ldquo;racist
public-safety tax&amp;rdquo; after it has been so well
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2013/07/the-banality-of-richard-cohen-and-racist-profiling/277871/&#34; title=&#34;The Banality of Richard Cohen and Racist Profiling&#34;&gt;refuted by Ta-Nehisi Coates&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York City&amp;rsquo;s murder rate is as low as it has been in 50 years.
How long should a racist public-safety tax last?  Until black people
no longer constitute a disproportionate share of our violent
criminals, one assumes.  But black people do not constitute such a
group&amp;mdash;victims of hundreds of years of racist state policy
constitute that group.  &amp;ldquo;Black on Black&amp;rdquo; crime is the racecraft by
which the fact of what was done to us disappears, and the fact of
our DNA becomes criminalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In other words, &amp;ldquo;Black-on-Black&amp;rdquo; crime is the rhetorical device by
which the fact that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/07/15/the-trayvon-martin-killing-and-the-myth-of-black-on-black-crime.html&#34; title=&#34;The Trayvon Martin Killing and the Myth of Black-on-Black Crime&#34;&gt;violence occurs between neighbors in our segregated society&lt;/a&gt; is
transformed into an indictment of Blackness itself.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m becoming increasingly confused, and there&amp;rsquo;s not much left of
Randy&amp;rsquo;s column:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had Zimmerman not been armed and Martin had severely beaten him,
maybe killing him or leaving him disabled, would this case have
commanded such ongoing national attention?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I must admit to being rather nonplussed by Randy&amp;rsquo;s (surely
tongue-in-cheek) invocation of a racist trope.  If Martin had been the
aggressor rather than Zimmerman, he would have been immediately
arrested and jailed, rather than allowed to walk free and only
apprehended six weeks later after sustained protests.  You can&amp;rsquo;t just
flip the races of the attacker and victim and pretend that the
sequence of events would have remained the same.  To so pretend is
just another method by which the effects of racism are minimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thoroughly bewildered.  And the last paragraph doesn&amp;rsquo;t help
things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The racism industry and the media vultures cannot bank on old white
guilt forever.  White America is not responsible for black behavior,
black America is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only assume that Randy is trying to write a clever parody of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/richard-cohen-racism-vs-reality/2013/07/15/4f419eb6-ed7a-11e2-a1f9-ea873b7e0424_story.html&#34; title=&#34;Racism vs. reality&#34;&gt;Richard Cohen&amp;rsquo;s appalling piece for the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which he titled &amp;ldquo;Racism vs. reality&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s really not very funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Point Of A Living Wage If We Are Not Truly Alive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/wage</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/wage</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our local writers are masters of dissimulation and double meaning.
They brilliantly hide a progressive message behind overblown,
reactionary rhetoric.  Harry Schutle
&lt;a href=&#34;fallacy.html&#34; title=&#34;Critical Thinking
for Racists&#34;&gt;pretended to be an ignorant racist&lt;/a&gt; while in fact spotlighting the fallacies in racist
thought.  Randi Rabin
&lt;a href=&#34;friends.html&#34; title=&#34;The Case of the
Magical Magnetic Genitals&#34;&gt;feigned interest in idiotic questions&lt;/a&gt; so as to undermine cis- and
heteronormativity.  And most recently, Sharon Byrne pretended to write
&lt;a href=&#34;liberal.html&#34; title=&#34;A
New Argument for Moral Relativism&#34;&gt;a high-school-level paper on political philosophy&lt;/a&gt; while actually making a novel
argument for moral relativism.  (Byrne goes so far as to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/SantaBarbaraBullshit/posts/10201690114437674?notif_t=share_wall_create&#34; title=&#34;Lucy Sharon Byrne&#39;s post on Santa Barbara Bullshit on 20 July
2013&#34;&gt;stay in character on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Harris Sherline has written the most subtle piece yet, an essay
ostensibly concerning the living wage that is really a profound
meditation on the problems at the heart of capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherline uses another article as his jumping-off point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent article in the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; reporting that Washington,
D.C., is considering mandating a &amp;ldquo;living wage&amp;rdquo; caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then spends over one quarter of his column quoting nearly five full
paragraphs of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/dc-politics/wal-mart-says-it-will-pull-out-of-dc-plans-should-city-mandate-living-wage/2013/07/09/4fa7e710-e8d0-11e2-a301-ea5a8116d211_story.html&#34; title=&#34;Wal-Mart says it will pull out of D.C. plans should city mandate
&#39;living wage&#39;&#34;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; story&lt;/a&gt;, without actually linking to the story itself.
Sherline is clearly trying to make the point that &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; is not being
paid enough by &lt;em&gt;Noozhawk&lt;/em&gt; to write his column.  And by failing to link
back to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; he draws attention to fact that there are no
editors at &lt;em&gt;Noozhawk&lt;/em&gt; who are able to catch such basic mistakes (or
use block quotes where necessary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing his copy-and-paste protest, Sherline becomes rather
pensive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a fan of the &amp;ldquo;living wage&amp;rdquo; policy, which I believe
causes more problems than it solves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, does anyone know how much a &amp;ldquo;living wage&amp;rdquo; should be?
After all, one man&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;living wage&amp;rdquo; may well be another&amp;rsquo;s poverty
wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is immediately clear that Sherline is not actually asking this
question in earnest, because doing so would violate the conversational
maxim of &amp;ldquo;Do Not Solemnly Ask Questions That Can Be
&lt;a href=&#34;http://livingwage.mit.edu/counties/06083&#34; title=&#34;Living Wage Calculation for Santa Barbara County, California&#34;&gt;Answered In Ten Seconds With Google&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
Rather, he is trying to make a larger point, as we can see with his
next question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, just what amount of compensation is necessary to provide an
adequate living, and who should make that decision?  It appears that
many city and county governing boards have become the
decision-makers in such matters&amp;mdash;rather than the free market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the concept [of a living wage] has been around for a while
and was adopted by the City of Santa Barbara in 2005, I have yet to
see a clear statement of what it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, Sherline must be tending towards something of a philosophic
nature, because one is not licensed to say something like &amp;ldquo;I have yet
to see such-and-such&amp;rdquo; unless such-and-such is not
&lt;a href=&#34;http://povertyinamerica.mit.edu/projects/living_wage/&#34; title=&#34;Living Wage Project&#34;&gt;easily accessible on the internet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherline begins to reveal his ultimate purpose when he mentions the
work of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.propublica.org/article/rotten-acorn-ad-funded-by-anti-minimum-wage-group&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;Rotten\&amp;quot; ACORN Ad Funded by Anti-Minimum Wage Group&#34;&gt;Employment Policies Institute&lt;/a&gt;, a group
funded by businesses for the sole purpose of lowering the minimum wage
(and who, to that end, spearheaded the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epionline.org/study/r113/&#34; title=&#34;Rotten ACORN:
America&#39;s Bad Seed&#34;&gt;smear campaign&lt;/a&gt; that helped destroy ACORN).  Sherline&amp;rsquo;s purpose
in citing this indefensible organization might seem puzzling at first,
but it must be taken in conjunction with his earlier claim that the
living wage &amp;ldquo;is nothing more than a minimum wage packaged under
another label and justified as &amp;lsquo;economic justice&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we are.  The living wage is a &amp;ldquo;bad idea&amp;rdquo; because it is simply
another version of the minimum wage, something that has been combated
so effectively by the Employment Policies Institute along with the
rest of the right.  Living wage laws will not ensure economic justice
because there &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; be economic justice under a capitalist system
that allows laws to be covertly influenced by corporate interests.
Living wage laws are reformist approaches that merely slow the
impoverishment of the lower classes while promoting a false sense of
security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harris Sherline demands more than reform.  He demands revolution.
Join Comrade Sherline in bringing down capitalism, for only then will
we have true economic justice!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Slice of Journalistic Life in the Facebook Age</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/slice</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/slice</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/murillo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Local website *Santa Barbara View* posting screenshots of Santa
Barbara City Councilwoman Cathy Murillo Facebooking photos from a
closed-session of Council on Tuesday.&#34; title=&#34;We are all
BuzzFeed now&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Argument for Moral Relativism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/liberal</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/liberal</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contemporary moral philosophy has hit a dead end, at least in the
academy.  Increasingly many students of ethics have become too willing
to defer to findings in neuroscience and to experimental methods in
general, often thereby confusing how we think about right and wrong
with how we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; think about right and wrong.  Scanning my brain
with an fMRI machine to see how I in fact react to a moral dilemma
tells us nothing about how I &lt;em&gt;ought&lt;/em&gt; to react.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this lamentable state of affairs, where is one to turn for new
insights about morality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara View&lt;/em&gt;, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Sharon Byrne has shaken up the field with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/defining-some-points-on-the-political-spectrum536366/&#34; title=&#34;Defining Some Points on the Political Spectrum: Street vs Parlor
Liberal vs Libertarian&#34;&gt;a novel argument for moral relativism&lt;/a&gt;: the view that what is morally right or wrong
can vary depending on the time, place, or other aspect of the
situation.  Byrne&amp;mdash;who, you will recall,
&lt;a href=&#34;home.html&#34; title=&#34;Point-Counterpoint: Kill the
Homeless, or Just Treat Them Like Animals?&#34;&gt;does not have a PhD&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;circumvents the insular
realm of peer-reviewed journals and brings her findings direct to the
people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She first contrasts &lt;em&gt;street liberals&lt;/em&gt;, who are often activists and are
genuinely committed to eradicating oppression, with &lt;em&gt;parlor
liberals&lt;/em&gt;, who support leftist causes as long as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require
them to examine their own privilege and complicity in systems of
inequality.  She illustrates the ideological gap between these two
groups with an example (unfortunately the editor of the &lt;em&gt;Santa
Barbara View&lt;/em&gt; accidentally exchanged instances of &amp;ldquo;parlor&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;street&amp;rdquo;; I have corrected the error):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypothetical example: Normally tolerant [parlor] liberals get
annoyed with their public spaces being taken over by homeless
&amp;hellip; They take this stance with great angst.  Liberals are supposed
to support the homeless, right?  &amp;hellip;  So how does this play against
[street] liberals&amp;rsquo; agenda of funding homeless shelters in the
[parlor] liberals&amp;rsquo; community, and expansion of civil rights for the
homeless &amp;hellip; ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &amp;ldquo;street liberals&amp;rdquo; recognize that the homeless deserve the same
protections that the rest of us enjoy, the acknowledgment by &amp;ldquo;parlor
liberals&amp;rdquo; of the humanity of others depends on whether or not the
goings-on of the parlor is disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byrne&amp;rsquo;s second distinction is between liberals in general and
&lt;em&gt;libertarians&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libertarians and liberals look alike on the surface.  They both
support reducing penalties [for] illegal drug use, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Both also support universal healthcare, affirmative action, stronger
hate-crimes legislation, and a better social safety net.  They only
really disagree about whether &lt;a href=&#34;cars.html&#34; title=&#34;The Freedom
to Choose \(A New or Used Automobile\)&#34;&gt;cars are basic&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where they part company, as pointed out by Matt Mazza in a recent
letter to the editor, is on the solution.  Liberals believe
government is the best regulator of human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libertarians believe the opposite.  The government should not be in
the business of telling us what to do &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/f21ZY.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;I see, yes&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both arguments break down at various points.  Liberal arguments for
increased government involvement create a society in which
ultimately, liberty is lost.  That&amp;rsquo;s a strange outcome for a group
with the Latin root &lt;em&gt;liberalis&lt;/em&gt; (freedom) in its name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libertarian arguments work until you check in with, say, a cartel
head.  It seems we&amp;rsquo;re actually &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; all rational adults that
should be trusted to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here Byrne sets forth the dilemma that motivates her thesis.  The
libertarian&amp;rsquo;s worship of individualism would restrict regulation and
allow drug cartels to persist even if drugs were legalized.  That is
unacceptable.  But the liberal&amp;rsquo;s solution, to regulate the drug trade
and prevent violent cartels from flourishing, would result in an equally
unacceptable loss of liberty, particularly to the cartel head.  What
is to be done?  What is the correct solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read your
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eschatonblog.com/2012/04/one-true-wanker-of-decade.html&#34; title=&#34;THE ONE TRUE WANKER OF THE DECADE&#34;&gt;Tom Friedman&lt;/a&gt;, you know that the answer is
somewhere in the middle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whichever paradigm you&amp;rsquo;re holding onto (and we haven&amp;rsquo;t discussed
conservatives), you can safely assume that at some point it&amp;rsquo;s going
to fail to provide the right answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s worth checking in with other circles to see if
they&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled onto something that posits a better answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharon Byrne&amp;rsquo;s relativist thesis can be expressed thus: &lt;em&gt;for every
pair of moral theories, there is a third theory that is better and is
a compromise between the two.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of illustration, there is, according to Byrne, a compromise
between liberalism and libertarianism (liberaltarianism?) that is
therefore better than either.  But&amp;mdash;and this is what makes the view
relativist&amp;mdash;there is then a view that is a compromise between
&lt;em&gt;liberaltarianism&lt;/em&gt; and liberalism, which is better than either.  There
is &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a compromise between liberaltarianism and libertarianism.
And there are compromises between those compromises, and so on &lt;em&gt;ad
infinitum&lt;/em&gt;.  No compromise is actually &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt;, or even better than all
others, because there are compromises of that compromise, but each is
better than the views it is a compromise of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all pretty abstract, but it&amp;rsquo;s the most explicit formulation
yet of the centrist view that principles are weakness and there is
always a Third Way.  With Byrne&amp;rsquo;s philosophical acuity and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://baruffio.com/dn/moral.html&#34; title=&#34;If
Thomas Friedman and Matthew Yglesias Had a Child, That Child Would Be
Mark Strong&#34;&gt;Mark Strong&amp;rsquo;s youthful energy&lt;/a&gt;, the future looks bright for bold pragmatists willing to
say what everyone has already said a thousand times before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Paul Burri Allowed Near A Keyboard?  And Other Smart Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/dumb</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/dumb</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Local entrepreneur, inventor, columnist, engineer, guerrilla marketer
and iconoclast Paul Burri is running out of ideas
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/112512_paul_burri_have_nothing_to_say&#34; title=&#34;When You Have Nothing to Say&#34;&gt;this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time&lt;/a&gt;).  In his &lt;em&gt;Noozhawk&lt;/em&gt; column, which he
has apparently mistaken for a Tumblr, he&amp;rsquo;s already written about that
time he
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/021013_paul_burri_the_great_frying_pan_mystery&#34; title=&#34;Cracking the Case of the Great Frying Pan Mystery&#34;&gt;poached an egg&lt;/a&gt;, that time he
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/012013_paul_burri_the_electric_blanket_mix-up&#34; title=&#34;The Electric Blanket Mix-Up Unfolds&#34;&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t make the bed correctly&lt;/a&gt;, that time he went to Israel
and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/123012_paul_burri_recent_trip_to_israel&#34; title=&#34;Observations After Our Recent Trip to Israel&#34;&gt;decided that the Palestinians could learn a lot from the Israelis&lt;/a&gt;, that time he got
annoyed when
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/101412_paul_burri_why_didi_he_do_that&#34; title=&#34;Questioning Why People Do the Things They Do&#34;&gt;someone talked about him&lt;/a&gt;, that time he
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/081912_paul_burri_words_i_think_need_to_be_invented&#34; title=&#34;Words I Think Need to Be Invented&#34;&gt;made up words&lt;/a&gt;, and that time when
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/042113_paul_burri_santa_barbara_homeless&#34; title=&#34;An Unconventional Solution to Santa Barbara’s Transient Problem&#34;&gt;he suggested that Santa Barbara conscript people into performing manual labor and then forcibly remove them from town&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There really isn&amp;rsquo;t much more to talk about, but
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/090212_paul_burri_man_killed_defective_toilet_seat&#34; title=&#34;Man Killed by Defective Toilet Seat&#34;&gt;that hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped dear Paul before&lt;/a&gt;.  This week Paul titled his
piece
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/paul_burri_dumb_questions&#34; title=&#34;Actually, There Are Such Things as Dumb Questions&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Actually, There Are Such Things as Dumb Questions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, playing on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitchmagazine.org/post/the-transcontinental-disability-choir-what-is-ableist-language-and-why-should-you-care&#34; title=&#34;The Transcontinental Disability Choir: What is Ableist Language and
Why Should You Care?&#34;&gt;an ableist slur&lt;/a&gt; to make the point that he has nothing
interesting left to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I am in a lecture or an adult-ed class, my hand is always
one of the first to go up when we get to the Q&amp;amp;A part of the
program. And often, afterward, people frequently come up to me and
thank me for asking a question they were too timid to ask. I am sure
that whatever question you have on your mind, there are several
others in the audience who have the same question but hesitate
because it might be a &amp;ldquo;dumb question.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the risk of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/paul_burri_whats_so_funny&#34; title=&#34;What&#39;s So Funny?&#34;&gt;explaining the joke&lt;/a&gt;, this works on two levels.  After having railed
against the plague of &amp;ldquo;dumb&amp;rdquo; questions, it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly revealed that
Paul Burri asks a lot of them himself.  And the people who have to
answer his questions probably can&amp;rsquo;t stop themselves from wishing he
was dumb in the literal sense.  But that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stop him from typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have nothing more to say about Paul Burri.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case of the Magical Magnetic Genitals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/friends</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/friends</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Randi Rabin, J. Edgar Hoover Distinguished Visiting Professor of
Feelings at the Noozhawk College of Bullshit, today attempts to tackle
a new version of the age old Problem of Friendship.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/randi_rabin_help_what_happened_to_my_15_year_old_angel&#34; title=&#34;Randi Rabin: Help! What Happened to my 15-Year-Old \&#39;Angel\&#39;?&#34;&gt;This iteration, due to noted scholar &lt;strong&gt;Craig in Santa Barbara&lt;/strong&gt;, runs thus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Feelings Doctor:&lt;/strong&gt; Please answer this &amp;ldquo;age old&amp;rdquo; question: Can
men and women really be &amp;ldquo;just friends&amp;rdquo;?  Thanks very much.  I just
need to know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craig in Santa Barbara has spent many years in the field, accosting
pairs of men and women in Chaucer&amp;rsquo;s and asking them &amp;ldquo;but are you
really &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; friends?&amp;rdquo;  But his results have been entirely
inconclusive, and he appealed to our Distinguished Professor to
attempt to open up new avenues of research.  (His desperate search for
an answer to the question that has defined his career is evident: &amp;ldquo;I
just need to know!&amp;rdquo; he says.  But do you really &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; need to know,
Craig?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Rabin&amp;rsquo;s analysis is rich and insightful.  She deserves a
good deal of praise for identifying &amp;ldquo;the bumpy stage of &amp;lsquo;should we
sleep together to see if it&amp;rsquo;s great or just be friends?&amp;lsquo;&amp;rdquo; that
inevitably precedes any &amp;ldquo;friendship attraction&amp;rdquo; between &amp;ldquo;women&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;guys&amp;rdquo;.  She also makes the keen observation that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;society has a difficult time figuring out this whole male/female
friendship thing.  People seem to feel more comfortable when they
know what column you go into.  It makes everyone feel safer to know
that you go into this box or that box.  Well, guess what?  Fit into
a box if you like, but actually, shhh&amp;mdash;there really is no box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a dense bit of argumentation.  For most readers, a visual aid
may be necessary to clarify what&amp;rsquo;s going on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+
|&lt;strong&gt;Woman&lt;/strong&gt;   |&lt;strong&gt;Man&lt;/strong&gt;     |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+
|interacts   |interacts   |
|amicably    |amicably    |
|with women  |with men    |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rabin&amp;rsquo;s thesis is that these are the societal criteria by which we
assign gender to individuals.  If they interact amicably with women,
they are a woman, and amicable interaction with men is a necessary and
sufficient condition for being a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These criteria are clearly problematic, but Rabin&amp;rsquo;s criticism of them
is difficult to understand at first.  What are we to make of her claim
that &amp;ldquo;there really is no box&amp;rdquo;?  She cannot be saying merely that
gender is socially constructed, for that does not make it any less
real.  By saying there is no box, or are no boxes, she appears to be
denying the reality of gender in any sense at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her final paragraph will only confuse the casual reader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, being best friends with the opposite sex can be an
illuminating, fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those not simply bewildered by the progression of her thoughts may
accuse her of lazily conflating sex and gender, but I believe that in
fact she&amp;rsquo;s making a very subtle and clever point about our society&amp;rsquo;s
view of gender relations.  By taking Craig from Santa Barbara&amp;rsquo;s
question about the &lt;em&gt;gendered&lt;/em&gt; categories of &lt;em&gt;woman&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;man&lt;/em&gt; and
gradually moving to a discussion of the &lt;em&gt;sexual&lt;/em&gt; categories of
&lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;male&lt;/em&gt;, our J. Edgar Hoover Distinguished Visiting
Professor of Feelings is demonstrating how this most idiotic of
questions&amp;mdash;can men and women be friends?&amp;mdash;can only emerge from a
simplistic view of men and women as necessarily both heterosexual and
cissexual.  Only by (1) ignoring the existence of gay, lesbian and
transgender individuals, (2) seeing sex and gender as synonymous, and
(3) probably being pretty emotionally immature could anyone take that
to be an open question worthy of serious discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rabin&amp;rsquo;s scathing piece undeniably means the end of Craig from Santa
Barbara&amp;rsquo;s research program.  When reached for comment, he was
surprisingly upbeat, however, saying that he now has time to study
where babies come from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Be Racist After Paula Deen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/roma</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/roma</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latimes.com/features/books/jacketcopy/la-et-jc-anne-rice-defends-paula-deen-against-lynch-mob-20130625,0,7208709.story&#34; title=&#34;Anne Rice defends Paula Deen against \&#39;lynch mob\&#39;&#34;&gt;lynching&lt;/a&gt; of gentle soul
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gawker.com/i-is-what-i-is-paula-deen-sobs-in-tense-today-interv-583684774&#34; title=&#34;\&amp;quot;I Is What I Is,\&amp;quot; Paula Deen Sobs in Tense *Today* Interview&#34;&gt;Paula Deen&lt;/a&gt; has
had a chilling effect on other American racists.  How are they to
exercise their right to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/squeenlatifah/status/350024436939898881&#34; title=&#34;Tweet by @squeenlatifa on 26 June 2013&#34;&gt;free speech&lt;/a&gt; when there are such
consequences?  Your average racist could not be blamed for simply
packing it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Julia Chaplin is not your average racist.  Her bigotry is
sophisticated and subtle, as demonstrated by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sbmag.com/2013/06/bohemian-rhapsody/&#34; title=&#34;Bohemian Rhapsody&#34;&gt;a recent feature in &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  The &amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo; she promotes involves some
egregious cultural appropriation, particularly against Indigenous
American peoples, and her books are boldly titled with the portmanteau
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gypset.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;gypset&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the combination of &amp;ldquo;jet-set&amp;rdquo; and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rsdb.org/race/gypsy&#34; title=&#34;The Racial Slur Database entry for \&amp;quot;gypsy\&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;racial slur used against the Romani people&lt;/a&gt;.  But none of this is
mentioned in the interview; Chaplin and &amp;ldquo;her band of friends, artists,
musicians, and otherworldly vivants&amp;rdquo; are described as &amp;ldquo;a disheveled,
chic, colorfully elegant tribe that turns heads&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did Julia Chaplin get away with this sort of behavior in our
politically-correct dystopia?  We sat down with her (&lt;em&gt;we did not&lt;/em&gt;) and
asked her how to be racist after Paula Deen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn&#34; title=&#34;Twitter for @dunndunndunn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; First off, congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JC:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you!  In a time when you can get in trouble for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thisweekinblackness.com/2013/07/01/white-feminists-netroots/&#34; title=&#34;This Week in Blackness: White Feminists: Step Your Game Up&#34;&gt;using stock photography instead of finding a single image of a feminist of color&lt;/a&gt;, I feel
like I&amp;rsquo;ve really beat the odds here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAT:&lt;/strong&gt; How do you think you got away with perpetuating racist
stereotypes against &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; groups with very little protest?  During my
exhaustive research I found only one
&lt;a href=&#34;http://madamethursday.tumblr.com/post/26627290176/image-a-very-racist-appropriative-photo-of-a&#34;&gt;Tumblr chain letter&lt;/a&gt;
and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/review/R2HYW6F8COMLH/ref=cm_cr_pr_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=2759403963&amp;amp;linkCode=&amp;amp;nodeID=&amp;amp;tag=&#34;&gt;one-star review on Amazon of your book &lt;em&gt;Gypset Style&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JC:&lt;/strong&gt; There are a few things I did that Paula Deen failed to do.
First, the groups I went after are even more marginalized than the
Black community is.  Racism directed at Indigenous and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gypsyappropriations.blogspot.com/2010/07/truth-about-gypsy-life.html&#34; title=&#34;The Truth About \&#39;Gypsy Life\&#39;&#34;&gt;Romani&lt;/a&gt; peoples remains acceptable in a way
anti-Black racism isn&amp;rsquo;t.  Remember that just recently
&lt;a href=&#34;../docs/lucidity.html&#34; title=&#34;When You\&#39;re Lucid Dreaming You Can Do Anything But That Includes
Being Racist&#34;&gt;a music festival was hosted in your own backyard&lt;/a&gt; that engaged in blatant appropriation of various
Indigenous cultures, and another local magazine devoted
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ventanamonthly.com/issue.php?IssueNum=79&#34; title=&#34;Ventana Magazine: On the Gypsy Trail&#34;&gt;half an issue&lt;/a&gt; to playing on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://staticnonsense.wordpress.com/2011/04/23/tw-the-bullshit-of-gypsy-magic-in-the-pagan-community/&#34; title=&#34;[tw] the bullshit of \&#39;gypsy magic\&#39; in the pagan community&#34;&gt;the racist trope of &amp;ldquo;gypsy magic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAT:&lt;/strong&gt; Good points.  And there&amp;rsquo;s probably something to be said for
committing some appropriation against different groups, rather than
going all-in on one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JC:&lt;/strong&gt; Exactly, you want to diffuse the response.  There&amp;rsquo;s no one group
that I&amp;rsquo;ve single-mindedly victimized; that was the mistake of Lucidity
Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAT:&lt;/strong&gt; So the lessons are to choose multiple groups that remain
incredibly vulnerable and spread the damage around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JC:&lt;/strong&gt; Correct!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAT:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, this has been very enlightening.  Thank you so much for
your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JC:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gypset.com/uploads/300003/1372704426357/calvi-on-the-rock-maillot06-366-xxx.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From [Gypset.com](http://www.gypset.com/news &amp;quot;No permalink available&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;Holy Fucking Shit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craig Smith Is A Zombie And Should Not Be Allowed On Airplanes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/faa</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/faa</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/jun/26/world-war-z/&#34; title=&#34;SB Independent: World War Z&#34;&gt;bad movie&lt;/a&gt; with some curious
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mattcornell.org/blog/2013/06/where-the-z-stands-for-zionism/&#34; title=&#34;Matt Cornell: Where the Z Stands for Zionism&#34;&gt;political undertones&lt;/a&gt; has the the thinking
public thinking again about that most
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adeerable/status/347688205337911296&#34; title=&#34;Tweet from @adeerable on 20 June 2013&#34;&gt;Serious&lt;/a&gt; of problems: the zombie
menace.  As any student of anti-zombie strategy knows, the most
important thing is to quickly identify and eliminate infected members
of your community.  Therefore I feel compelled to warn Santa Barbara
residents that our own Craig Smith may be a zombie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evidence comes in the form of today&amp;rsquo;s blog post, in which &lt;a href=&#34;http://craigsmithsblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/the-mile-high-club-needs-to-stay.html&#34; title=&#34;The Mile High Club Needs to Stay Powered Down&#34;&gt;he
appears to admit to having &amp;ldquo;died&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to electronic gadgets and devices, I&amp;rsquo;m a little like
Charlton Heston was when it came to his gun.  The only way you are
going to take my iPhone away from me is to, &amp;ldquo;pry it from my cold,
dead hand.&amp;rdquo;  The same goes for my iPad and my Nexus 7 tablet.
However, despite my attachment to these gadgets, I think the time
and energy spent by the FAA on repealing the rule that electronic
devices need to be powered off and put away during take-off and
landing is a bad idea.  The rule as it stands (&amp;ldquo;if it has an on/off
switch it needs to be off) is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craig Smith will only stop using his iPhone when he is &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo;, but he
&lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; stopped using his phone when flying!  The only possibility is
that he goes into some sort of zombie fugue when boarding an
airplane.  What is most shocking about this revelation is the fact
that he apparently recovers upon landing.  Traditionally, zombies have
been thought to be permanently undead.  This is a disturbing
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Many of you will point out that Smith says he only dies when his
phone is taken from his hands, not when it is turned off.  True
enough, but the implication is clear.  It would be a gross non
sequitur to make such a claim in the context of a discussion of the
FAA&amp;rsquo;s rules for the use of electronics.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A zombie on an airplane is a terrifying idea, for it allows the rapid
spread of contagion.  Warnings about public safety, therefore, sound
pretty hollow coming from Smith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If indeed, the most critical time on an airplane is during take-off
and landing shouldn&amp;rsquo;t passengers be ready to be alerted to the
possibility that an emergency is imminent?  You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be playing
Angry Birds and be oblivious to the fact that everyone else is
panicked because the bird you are flying on is going down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this clumsy attempt to deflect attention from his own disease only
further highlights Smith&amp;rsquo;s affliction.  No passenger could be so
engrossed in a game to fail to notice that their plane is crashing;
but Smith, being always zombified during flight, is not aware of this.
Likewise he does not realize that electronic devices are allowed to be
on during the majority of the flight, proclaiming that &amp;ldquo;if they ever
allow passengers to talk on cell phones during the flight, I&amp;rsquo;ll be
done with flying.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope Craig Smith does stop flying, for the good of us all.  In
particular, though, it may make the flight attendants more
comfortable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a few years ago I was on a plane about to depart from JFK
when a passenger was still gabbing on her cell phone even though the
flight attendants were giving the safety instructions and the plane
was taxiing down the runway.  Apparently this passenger didn&amp;rsquo;t find
the &amp;ldquo;Delta Girl&amp;rdquo; anywhere near as captivating as I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point-Counterpoint: Kill the Homeless, or Just Treat Them Like Animals?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/home</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/home</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most pressing question for residents of our fair city is &lt;em&gt;how do
we get rid of the sorts of people we don&amp;rsquo;t like?&lt;/em&gt; Finding an answer to
this question is urgent due to the very large number of people we find
objectionable:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/may/16/heated-debate-over-gang-injunction/&#34; title=&#34;SB Independent: Heated Debate Over Gang Injunction&#34;&gt;young men of color&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thebottomline.as.ucsb.edu/2013/05/violent-altercation-breaks-out-in-iv-provoked-by-homophobic-remarks&#34; title=&#34;Violent Altercation Breaks Out in IV, Provoked By Homophobic
Remarks&#34;&gt;gender, sexual, and romantic minorities (GSRMs)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; the homeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as we dislike people who look and love other than we do, our
most righteous fury is reserved for those who&amp;mdash;outrageously&amp;mdash;find
themselves living on the street.  We therefore owe the &lt;em&gt;Santa Barbara
View&lt;/em&gt; our gratitude for hosting a debate on what to do with these
filthy individuals who remind us, unfairly and distressingly, of the
grave inequality in our society.  Those who have recently taken to
existing on State Street are particularly galling, given that the
&lt;em&gt;point&lt;/em&gt; of going to State Street is to forget about all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So something has to be done.  But what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Loretta Redd, PhD (she has a PhD, everyone), asks us to see the
homeless population as a band of stray animals.  One should not
necessarily feed the strays, but rather support the shelters that are
equipped to care for them.  The analogy is apt:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/more-givingless-helping-santa-barbara6535387/&#34; title=&#34;More Giving=Less Helping&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is time to face the harm we are doing by giving money to those unable to use it wisely,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, writes Redd (who has a PhD), making the
obvious but often-overlooked point that a house or apartment is a
precondition of rationality.  She suggests that instead of feeding
these anthropomorphized seagulls, we&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;follow the Atlanta model, and &lt;strong&gt;install &amp;ldquo;giving meters&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; on
sidewalks, or on private property if owners are willing, where the
money could be collected and transferred to programs of transitional
housing or intensive professional service to assist those addicted
to substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting proposal, but not one that is to the liking of
Dr. Redd&amp;rsquo;s sparring partner in this online debate.  Sharon Byrne (who
does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;, apparently, have a PhD), argues that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/the-business-of-homelessness-in-santa-barbara/&#34; title=&#34;The Business of Homelessness in Santa Barbara, California&#34;&gt;shelters like Casa Esperanza have existed for a number of years and continue to pay their employees&lt;/a&gt;, proof of
their profound corruption.  Moreover,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the money that has been spent, is still being spent, and
what it&amp;rsquo;s being spent on &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How well is the city really tackling this issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could it be done better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are, of course, rhetorical questions, since we know that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/whose-city-is-it-anyway2542252/&#34; title=&#34;Whose City Is It, Anyway?&#34;&gt;truly helping other people is tree-hugger bullshit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Some suggest that we] &lt;strong&gt;stop Wall St Greed, and end the disparity
between rich and poor to solve homelessness.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure, we&amp;rsquo;ll get right
on that. No one&amp;rsquo;s solved it in decades, but let Santa Barbara lead
the charge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in any case, Sharon Byrne has done extensive research and
discovered that &amp;ldquo;the bench occupiers [on State Street] aren&amp;rsquo;t
homeless.&amp;rdquo; (She has not released the data supporting this claim,
presumably because she plans on publishing her findings and is afraid
of academic plagiarism.  Understandable.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What, then, is Byrne&amp;rsquo;s suggestion?  How are we do deal with this
plague of undesirables?  She, unfortunately, has no answers, but
recognizes that this question is of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.santabarbaraview.com/whose-city-is-it-anyway2542252/&#34; title=&#34;Whose City Is It, Anyway?&#34;&gt;existential import&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whose city is it, anyway???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If homeless youths are allowed to remain in Santa Barbara, Sharon
Byrne is gone.  Much as in the pitiful case of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.com/news/2013/jun/14/sidewalk-weapons/&#34; title=&#34;Terrorists on Wheels&#34;&gt;a woman driven out of town by terrorists&lt;/a&gt;, it is perfectly clear who we would rather
have living in our city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Thinking for Racists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/fallacy</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/fallacy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most important aspects of teaching is the use of apt
examples to illustrate key points.  If an educator fails to show how a
subject is applicable to real problems, students may find it abstract,
pointless, and unworthy of their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is particularly crucial to remember this when discussing
&lt;em&gt;fallacies&lt;/em&gt;.  We commit fallacies&amp;mdash;errors in reasoning&amp;mdash;on a daily
basis, but studying them in the context of &lt;em&gt;logic&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;critical
thinking&lt;/em&gt; can lead to one&amp;rsquo;s pupils treating them as academic issues,
rather than faults which can negatively affect many aspects of our
lives.  It is very fortunate, therefore, that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/061713_henry_schulte_immigration_reform/&#34; title=&#34;Noozhawk: If We Would Use the Process Already in Place, We Wouldn\&#39;t
Need Immigration \&#39;Reform\&#39;&#34;&gt;Henry Schulte has taken to the pages of today&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Noozhawk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to demonstrate vividly how we frequently
commit fallacies in our ordinary thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schulte draws his examples from a fictional polemic against
immigration reform.  His fictional author, railing against the
imagined evils brought about by undocumented immigration, makes an
series of fallacies that are highly instructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Schulte addresses the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nizkor.org/features/fallacies/appeal-to-ridicule.html&#34; title=&#34;The Nizkor Project: Appeal to Ridicule&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;appeal to ridicule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  His op-ed writer tells a
story about moving to China on a visa and remaining there for 20
years, presumably against Chinese law.  When his undocumented status
is discovered, he is arrested.  He sarcastically
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/061713_henry_schulte_immigration_reform/&#34; title=&#34;Noozhawk: If We Would Use the Process Already in Place, We Wouldn\&#39;t
Need Immigration \&#39;Reform\&#39;&#34;&gt;laments his plight&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I don&amp;rsquo;t get is after all these years of living and working
there, how come I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a bunch of free stuff and become a
Chinese citizen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound ridiculous? It is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By treating healthcare, security, voting rights, and other benefits of
citizenship as &amp;ldquo;free stuff&amp;rdquo;, the (invented) opinion writer trivializes
the often life-saving rights conferred to citizens and denied to
others in a cynical attempt to convince readers to ignore their
importance and instead think of the less-privileged as
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thecaucus.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/11/14/romney-blames-loss-on-obamas-gifts-to-minorities-and-young-voters/&#34; title=&#34;Romney Blames Loss on Obama\&#39;s \&#39;Gifts\&#39; to Minorities and Young
Voters&#34;&gt;moochers looking for gifts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s of course &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; ridiculous to think that a person who has lived
somewhere for two decades and become part of that society has some
claim to stay, but Schulte shows here how the impression that it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;
can be easily produced in an incautious mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next example is not of a fallacy, strictly speaking, but it is
noteworthy all the same:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have a process [for immigration] in place that has been
working just fine for those who follow the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_Bullshit&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia: On Bullshit&#34;&gt;bullshit&lt;/a&gt;.  The claim that the existing immigration
system is perfectly functional is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/04/12/17709883-waiting-half-a-life-for-a-green-card-families-languish-in-immigration-line?lite&#34; title=&#34;Waiting half a life for a green card: Families languish in
immigration line&#34;&gt;obviously false&lt;/a&gt;, but our devious (and thankfully nonexistent)
author presents this claim with such confidence that some readers may
take it as fact.  Those who see through it will likely treat the rest
of the article with skepticism, so this sort of flagrant bullshitting
is a risky strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schulte next provides two passages that exemplify the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nizkor.org/features/fallacies/straw-man.html&#34; title=&#34;Nizkor Project: Straw Man&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;straw man fallacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left has hammered us for so long with the need for immigration
reform that it&amp;rsquo;s made many believe it&amp;rsquo;s now a requirement.  And they
try to guilt those who are opposed as racist and cold-hearted who
don&amp;rsquo;t care about the lives of other people.  What about the lives
and welfare of American citizens?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debate isn&amp;rsquo;t over whether immigrants work hard or contribute
something to the American society; it&amp;rsquo;s how come we&amp;rsquo;re being forced
to change our policy to accommodate one group over another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here our delusional author (the product of a truly creative mind)
combines another bit of bullshit&amp;mdash;the outrageous claim that &lt;em&gt;white
Americans are being oppressed&lt;/em&gt; by undocumented immigrants&amp;mdash;with a
gross distortion of the position held by those who advocate
immigration reform.  Comprehensive reform&amp;mdash;even the sort of
idealistic reform that would allow free movement across borders&amp;mdash;is
not an attempt to &amp;ldquo;accommodate&amp;rdquo; one group over another.  Nor do those
who seek such reform care more about immigrants than citizens.  Reform
activists care about the welfare of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; people, and loathe
discriminatory policies (such as ours) that treat immigrants and
non-citizens as second-class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we get what I&amp;rsquo;ll call the &lt;em&gt;fallacy of ambiguity&lt;/em&gt;.  Our imaginary
writer has turned to the invented problem known as &amp;ldquo;Who Will Pay For
All These Lazy Immigrants?&amp;rdquo;  He claims that they will not themselves
contribute via taxes, because
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/061713_henry_schulte_immigration_reform/&#34; title=&#34;Noozhawk: If We Would Use the Process Already in Place, We Wouldn\&#39;t
Need Immigration \&#39;Reform\&#39;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;already half the country doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay a dime as it is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is true is that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2012/sep/18/mitt-romney/romney-says-47-percent-americans-pay-no-income-tax/&#34; title=&#34;Politifact: Mitt Romney says 47 percent of Americans pay no income
tax&#34;&gt;about half of US citizens do not pay &lt;em&gt;income&lt;/em&gt; tax&lt;/a&gt;; but most of these individuals still pay sales taxes, property
taxes, Social Security taxes, and other non-income taxes.  Schulte&amp;rsquo;s
fake demagogue intends for readers to understand him to be referring
to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; taxes, when his statement is only anything close to true if
he is taken to be talking about only the income tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next he bemoans the supposedly uncivilized nature of immigrants,
exposing us in the process to the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nizkor.org/features/fallacies/spotlight.html&#34; title=&#34;Nizkor Project: Spotlight&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;spotlight fallacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And keep in mind there is a vast segment of these immigrants
responsible for domestic violence, gangs, drugs, drunken driving and
human smuggling. You only need to read the paper to see the result
of this everyday. This isn&amp;rsquo;t racist, it&amp;rsquo;s factual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regrettably, for the hardworking portion of immigrants this bad
element taints the entire group, but in the end we all suffer for it
and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainstream media traffics in sensationalism and race-baiting, so it is
thoroughly unsurprising that stories involving crime, especially
crimes committed by undocumented immigrants, receive a great deal of
coverage.  But it is obviously fallacious to take that unbalanced
coverage and use it to make a gross generalization about immigrants as
a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fallacy is followed by a series of bold rhetorical moves.  Our
imaginary polemicist recognizes that his characterization of
immigrants will be seen as a cheap bit of racist fear-mongering, so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;He insists that his racist claims are in fact just factual
descriptions of how the world is.  This move was performed most
audaciously by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bell_Curve&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia: The Bell Curve&#34;&gt;Herrnstein and Murray&lt;/a&gt;, and has recently come to the public
consciousness again thanks to Heroic Freethinker
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/05/08/heritage-study-co-author-opposed-letting-in-immigrants-with-low-iqs/&#34; title=&#34;Heritage study co-author opposed letting in immigrants with low
IQs&#34;&gt;Jason Richwine&lt;/a&gt;.  Of course, this is just more bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;He &lt;em&gt;actually admits&lt;/em&gt; that he&amp;rsquo;s making an unfair (and racist)
generalization about a class of individuals,
but&amp;mdash;regrettably!&amp;mdash;insists that it&amp;rsquo;s justified to do so.  It&amp;rsquo;s a
truly breathtaking maneuver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last fallacy is some twisted variation on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://lesswrong.com/lw/at/sunk_cost_fallacy/&#34; title=&#34;LessWrong: Sunk Cost Fallacy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sunk cost fallacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how is this [immigration reform] fair for all those who have
struggled through the legal process, waited years and spent
thousands of dollars to do it the right way? For one thing, it
diminishes their pride in becoming an American citizen after all
their hard efforts. They would have to ask themselves why they
bothered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly!  It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to the &lt;em&gt;other immigrants&lt;/em&gt;, who had the
time and resources to navigate the nightmarish immigration process, if
all of a sudden it was made easier for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; to cross borders.
They spent thousands of dollars and waited decades to come to the
United States, and now other people don&amp;rsquo;t have to?  Why even bother
coming after all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because in the world of Harry Schulte, you&amp;rsquo;re only doing well if
someone else is doing much, much worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Small Business Success (Take That, Obama!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/small</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/small</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life has not been easy for small business owners of the Caucasian
persuasion since Black Spy Barack Hussein Obama passed the Reparations
Act of Reverse Racism (RARR!).  Good, hardworking Americans have found
their already-shrinking incomes further taxed to pay for the data
plans of Obamaphones, which are then used by Welfare-Americans to shop
online and put local stores out of business.  Just such a fate
recently befell area White man Jan Koch (relationship to the Koch
brothers unknown), whose Travel Store is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/travel_store_closes_doors_after_29_years/&#34; title=&#34;Travel Store of Santa Barbara Packing It In After 29 Years&#34;&gt;closing its doors this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite the increasingly dystopian nature of the country as it
slides toward an inevitable race war, some hero entrepreneurs have
refused to take the easy way out (food stamps) and have valiantly
started a profitable business despite the best efforts of the Obama
regime.  Success has not come easily for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sbmag.com/2013/06/15556/&#34; title=&#34;Santa
Barbara Magazine: Jet Set&#34;&gt;David and Healey Young&lt;/a&gt;, who live a Spartan existence while their
pour all their resources into staying afloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sbmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-shot-2013-06-14-at-11.19.33-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Youngs in their sparsely-furnished home, [from Santa Barbara Magazine](http://sbmag.com/2013/06/15556/ &amp;quot;Santa
Barbara Magazine: Jet Set&amp;quot;)&#34; title=&#34;Screen-shot-2013-06-14-at-11.19.33-AM.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The severe difficulties that the Youngs have faced have given them a
humble, grounded perspective on life.  Says Healey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love classics toughened up with edgy pieces. I&amp;rsquo;ll pair a checkered
oxford with a pouf skirt and insanely high ankle-risking Lanvin
wedges.  I love L.A. designer Gladys Tamez&amp;rsquo;s hats. And vintage pool
dresses when they&amp;rsquo;re least expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David is equally modest, admitting only with embarrassment that &amp;ldquo;I
discovered the Santa Barbara-band Dishwalla, so I have a gold record
for their first album &lt;em&gt;Pet Your Friends&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  He also makes a
self-conscious reference to his signed poster of Green Day&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;American
Idiot&lt;/em&gt;.  It is rumored that the album name is in fact a reference to
David Young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vocation that the Youngs have sacrificed everything for is a
thankless one.  They run a private &amp;ldquo;jet charter service&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;a
misleading title for a business that is little more than an air taxi
operator.  David and Healey fly the planes themselves, and are
continually at the mercy of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://popdust.com/2012/11/19/rihanna-air-naked-in-the-aisles/&#34; title=&#34;Pop Dust: Air Rihanna: Nudity, Talk of Mutiny and the Smell of Hot
Processed Cheese and Fear&#34;&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s nouveau rich&lt;/a&gt;.  Often they are treated as glorified UPS
drivers; David recalls the humiliation he felt when he &amp;ldquo;flew a tuxedo
to its owner on a Citation X, the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest civilian jet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all their suffering, the two refuse to go into detail about the
debauched behavior of their passengers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens at 40,000 feet stays at 40,000 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But their reticence may only be due to the fact that their livelihood
is continually at risk&amp;mdash;one disgruntled call from an Obamaphone could
put them on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freedom to Choose (A New or Used Automobile)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shit/cars</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Alex Dunn</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shit/cars</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In contemporary philosophy it often seems as if
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/possibleviews&#34; title=&#34;@possibleviews
on Twitter&#34;&gt;all possible views&lt;/a&gt; have been formulated and defended.  It&amp;rsquo;s been argued that
only the present exists, that the past &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; future exist (and thus
that dinosaurs and future people exist too), that Sherlock Holmes
really exists, and that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t exist.  One Christian philosopher
has even suggested that when we die, God exchanges our corpse with a
perfect copy; the copy decomposes in the earth but we remain intact,
to allow for reincarnation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite this plurality of bizarre opinions, there is a reasonable
amount of consensus on certain issues related to material things and
their parts.  Everyday objects like tables, chairs, cars, and
televisions are generally agreed to be built up out of parts: I can
disassemble a car into its tires, engine, doors, etc.  In that sense,
the car exists because its parts are put together in the right way; if
they are not assembled correctly, there is no car.  The car is not
&lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noticing this unusual consensus, a certain
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QS5__yFW5EE&#34; title=&#34;CARSAREBASIC
Interview 1OF4&#34;&gt;Scott Wenz&lt;/a&gt; has boldly staked out an opposing view in pursuit of
fame and articles that might get accepted for publication in &lt;em&gt;The
Philosophical Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;.  He has recently made the exciting claim
that &lt;strong&gt;cars &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; basic&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extraordinary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps believing that his radical ideas will not be received warmly
by the philosophical establishment, Wenz has&amp;mdash;like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chronicle.com/blogs/percolator/the-strangest-conference-i-ever-attended/32805&#34; title=&#34;The Strangest Conference I Ever Attended&#34;&gt;David Birnbaum&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;sought to advance his
theory outside the confines of academia.  He has even started
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carsarebasic.org/&#34; title=&#34;Cars Are Basic&#34;&gt;his own nonprofit&lt;/a&gt; in
order to better reach a receptive audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott Wenz&amp;rsquo;s theory is complicated and highly abstract, but he has
made admirable efforts to explain the essential points in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noozhawk.com/article/letter_to_the_editor_high-speed_rail_bart_and_santa_barbara_connected/&#34; title=&#34;Letter to the Editor: High-Speed Rail, BART and Santa Barbara
Connected?&#34;&gt;clear, straightforward language&lt;/a&gt;.  He begins his précis by explaining why such things
as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bart.gov/&#34;&gt;Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART)&lt;/a&gt;,
high-speed rail, and buses are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; basic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] An Associated Press article printed Monday states that BART General
Manager Dorothy Dugger resigned under presser [sic] in May 2011, but
collected $330,000 in pay and additional benefits that included two
added months of vacation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BART is part of the heavily subsidized and expensive commuter rail
system that has failed in the San Jose area and has questionable
ridership outside of the San Francisco Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] The connection to an extravagant and unneeded high-speed rail
project is the initial billion-dollar bond recently approved to
build &amp;ldquo;stupid is as stupid does rail.&amp;rdquo;  A good portion will be spent
not on the rail but multimillion-dollar spinoffs for inefficient
BART and projects not related to the bullet train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] Santa Barbara MTD under similar type management problems in the past
decade has seen most of its board resign for lousy decisions, and
MTD&amp;rsquo;s director forced out. Remember the &amp;ldquo;all electric bus&amp;rdquo; that
failed to meet freeway specifications, fuel efficiency (batteries),
violated federal contract provisions, etc.?  What did the South
County cities do?  Appointed new board members who gave the
disgraced MTD director a golden parachute, approving more routes
that are badly used, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget the failed (and expensive)
long-distance commuter buses to Santa Ynez and Lompoc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thrust of Wenz&amp;rsquo;s theory is starting to emerge.  Trains and
buses (and bikes!) are not basic because their usability requires
government support.  The operation of trains and buses and the
infrastructure required for bicycles must be provided by the
government.  But the government is inherently corrupt, so these
non-basic forms of transportation are inherently flawed and should not
be funded.  (There was literally
&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20120715031917/http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-rail-advice-20120709,0,973921,full.story&#34; title=&#34;LA Times: High-speed rail officials rebuffed proposal from French
railway&#34;&gt;nothing California could have done&lt;/a&gt; to make high-speed rail work.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cars, on the other hand, &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; basic, according to Wenz.  My use of a
car does not depend on the government in any way.  I purchase a car
from a private dealer, I &lt;em&gt;certainly&lt;/em&gt; do not register it, I siphon gas
rather than pay the gas tax, and I drive it wherever I choose.  It is
that &lt;em&gt;freedom&lt;/em&gt; provided by cars that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carsarebasic.org/mission.html&#34; title=&#34;Mission
Statement for Cars Are Basic&#34;&gt;makes them basic&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the mode of transportation is at the core
of a free society.  Designing and maintaining &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;core routes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with
capacity to efficiently handle vehicles, allowing for safe and
flexible personal transportation decisions is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom to choose.  In a free society, everyone is able to choose how
they travel: by Ford, Honda, Toyota, or any of the many fine brands of
automobile that truly &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt; can afford.  The criterion of liberty
is having this &lt;em&gt;personal transportation decision&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;and what more
could one want?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>