<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Luna on Baruffio: a blog about Harry Potter — baruffio.com </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/t/luna/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>A Witch or Wizard</author>
    <rights>Copyright the respective author(s); all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2014-02-21 13:00:00 -0700 -0700</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can&#39;t spell &#8220;OotP&#8221; without &#8220;OTP&#8221;: an essay in Ronbledore apologetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/otp</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>[Alex Dunn]</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/otp</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, J.K. Rowling finally admitted that Ron and
Hermione should not have ended up together.  While this led us to
ponder what
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunndunndunn/status/429878749941596161&#34;&gt;alternate endings&lt;/a&gt;
Rowling might have secretly preferred, it offered powerful support for
the once-maligned
&lt;a href=&#34;http://the-toast.net/2014/02/03/regret-pairing-ron-hermione-together-ron-time-traveling-dumbledore-jk-rowling-admits/&#34;&gt;Ronbledore Theory&lt;/a&gt;,
which maintains that Ron &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Dumbledore, and at some point went back
in time to live the majority of his life as the eldest son of Percival
and Kendra Dumbledore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure illustrating the Ronbledore theory&#34; title=&#34;Figure illustrating the Ronbledore theory&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Figure 1, above: The blue line represents the &amp;ldquo;Ron&amp;rdquo; period of Ronbledore&amp;rsquo;s life, and the green represents the &amp;ldquo;Dumbledore&amp;rdquo; period.  The exact point at which Ronbledore went back in time (represented by the cyan line) is unknown, but this essay will help to narrow the possibilites.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of the Ronbledore Theory has by now been pretty well
established, but I would like to shore up its foundations with some
new evidence, evidence that will help explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; Ronbledore went
back in time, as well as&amp;mdash;roughly&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;She doesn&amp;rsquo;t get your humor like I do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step of this essay may seem to be a &lt;em&gt;non sequitur&lt;/em&gt;, but its
relevance will soon become apparent.  The first step is to show that
&lt;strong&gt;Ron and Luna Lovegood&lt;/strong&gt; are soulmates.  This is easily accomplished.
Allow me to draw your attention to two passages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, from &lt;em&gt;Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;.  Ron is here declaring his
intention to exert his prefect powers over Gregory Goyle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For heaven&amp;rdquo;s sake, Ron &amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll make Goyle do lines, it&amp;rsquo;ll kill him, he hates writing,&amp;rdquo; said
Ron happily. He lowered his voice to Goyle&amp;rdquo;s low grunt and, screwing
up his face in a look of pained concentration, mimed writing in
midair. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I … must … not … look … like … a … baboon&amp;rdquo;s … backside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone laughed, but nobody laughed harder than Luna Lovegood. She
let out a scream of mirth that caused Hedwig to wake up and flap her
wings indignantly and Crookshanks to leap up into the luggage rack,
hissing. Luna laughed so hard her magazine slipped out of her grasp,
slid down her legs and on to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was &lt;em&gt;funny!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her prominent eyes swam with tears as she gasped for breath, staring
at Ron. Utterly nonplussed, he looked around at the others, who were
now laughing at the expression on Ron&amp;rsquo;s face and at the ludicrously
prolonged laughter of Luna Lovegood, who was rocking backwards and
forwards, clutching her sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you taking the mickey?&amp;rdquo; said Ron, frowning at her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baboon&amp;rsquo;s … backside!&amp;rdquo; she choked, holding her ribs (&lt;em&gt;OotP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter
10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luna is the only person who truly appreciates Ron&amp;rsquo;s humor.  This point
is repeated in &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;He says very funny things
sometimes, doesn&amp;rdquo;t he?&amp;ldquo;), and we also learn that Ron find&amp;rsquo;s Luna&amp;rsquo;s wit
equally enchanting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could hear the match commentary from here,&amp;rdquo; said Ron, his voice
now shaking with laughter. &amp;ldquo;I hope Luna always commentates from now
on … &lt;em&gt;Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy&lt;/em&gt; … &amp;ldquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside.  Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy.  Surely, true love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True love, however, was not to be.  Ron ended up with Hermione&amp;mdash;for a
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;“It is too late, you understand me?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did Ron end up with Hermione, when our souls cried out in protest
and even Rowling knew it was wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, ultimately, is that &lt;em&gt;it had to be so&lt;/em&gt;.  The course of Time
is fixed, and Ron&amp;rsquo;s choice of Hermione over Luna was a matter of cruel
necessity.  The course of Time is fixed: it is forever true that
Ronbledore went back in time, and so nothing can occur that would
alter that fact.  &lt;strong&gt;And Ron would not have gone back in time,
had he married Luna.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had he married his soulmate, had the baboon&amp;rsquo;s backside been blessed to
suffer from Loser&amp;rsquo;s Lurgy for all of his days, then Ron would have
been happy.  He would have lived his life, content, no longer jealous
of Harry&amp;rsquo;s fame because the one person in the world who understands
him would be always by his side.  There would have been no dissatisfaction,
no reckless urges to break free of a dreary day-to-day and make a
dramatic break with the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But happiness was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron married Hermione, and suffered.  It was for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; reason that he
eventually went back in time, to escape the marriage he knew was wrong
and to &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; something of himself, somewhere where he would not
always be compared to the Boy Who Lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere?  Some&lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;How to keep soulmates apart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question remains, however, that torments all gentle hearts: how is
it &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that Ron ended up with Hermione, when true love was
staring him in the face?  What could have prevented such a man from
pursuing Luna Lovegood and winning her hand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, or who?&lt;/strong&gt;  Attend to this passage from &lt;em&gt;Half-Blood Prince&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s a Gurdyroot,&amp;rdquo; she said, stuffing the cat litter and the
toadstool back into her bag. &amp;ldquo;You can keep it if you like, I&amp;rsquo;ve got
a few of them. They&amp;rsquo;re really excellent for warding off Gulping
Plimpies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she walked away, leaving Ron chortling, still clutching the
Gurdyroot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know, she&amp;rsquo;s grown on me, Luna,&amp;rdquo; he said, as they set off again
for the Great Hall. &amp;ldquo;I know she&amp;rdquo;s insane, but it&amp;rdquo;s in a good&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped talking very suddenly. Lavender Brown was standing at the
foot of the marble staircase looking thunderous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi,&amp;rdquo; said Ron nervously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;C&amp;rsquo;mon,&amp;rdquo; Harry muttered to Hermione, and they sped past, though not
before they had heard Lavender say, &amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you tell me you were
getting out today? And why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; with you?&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;HBP,&lt;/em&gt; chapter 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you beginning to understand?  When Lavender says &amp;ldquo;why was &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;
with you&amp;rdquo;, she is not referring to Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now look!  Look at this passage from &lt;em&gt;Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I like this song,&amp;rdquo; said Luna, swaying in time to the waltz-like
tune, and a few seconds later she stood up and glided on to the
dance floor, where she revolved on the spot, quite alone, eyes
closed and waving her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s great, isn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo; said Ron admiringly. &amp;ldquo;Always good value.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the smile vanished from his face at once: Viktor Krum had
dropped into Luna&amp;rsquo;s vacant seat. Hermione looked pleasurably
flustered, but this time Krum had not come to compliment her. With a
scowl on his face he said, &amp;ldquo;Who is that man in the yellow?&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;DH,&lt;/em&gt;
chapter 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever Ron admires Luna, whenever his heart is on the verge of
telling him its truth, &lt;strong&gt;a time-traveling witch or wizard arrives to
distract him.&lt;/strong&gt;  The most heartbreaking part of this is that these
magical anti-Cupids are most likely sent by Ronbledore himself, during
his Dumbledore years.  He knows that he &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; marry Hermione in order
to fulfill his destiny, and so deliberately undermines his own
happiness for the sake of the wizarding world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me now in a moment of silence for the &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; great sacrifices
Ronbledore makes: first, his life, and then his love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>